[Music]
The Aldrich family, written by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Ezra Stone.
Henry! Henry Aldrich!
Coming, mother!
[Applause]
[Music]
Ladies and gentlemen, what is the best way to find out how really good Jello Butterscotch pudding is?
Well, now it's not to have somebody tell you about it, because words just can't give you the full idea.
Know the way to find out is to try a golden dish of jello butterscotch pudding for yourself.
And then I think you'll agree that a spoon in the hand is worth a hundred adjectives.
Jello butterscotch pudding friends is a ready prepared pudding that takes only about five brief minutes to make.
Yet it tastes every bit as delicious, every bit as homemade as if you had gone to all the trouble of making it yourself.
Of all the butterscotch puddings you ever tasted, we believe that you'll find Jello butterscotch pudding the most satisfied.
a grand pudding with a grand flavor, the rich buttery brown sugar flavor of mellow butter scotch.
So try jello butter scotch pudding for yourself.
One taste is all you need to tell you why jello butter scotch pudding is the dessert that thousands call the best of all.
[Music]
The Aldrich family who live in the comfortable house at 117 Elm Street in Centerville, USA
are friends and neighbors of yours.
All rich and his wife Alice are real parents and there never was a more typical American boy than their teenage son Henry
Well now it is evening and as we join the Aldrich's in their living room
Just see if you don't recognize Henry Aldrich as a boy from your bluff
Then yes, Alice
How steam chilly to you and ran
and ran
Yes, father. Have you put any coal on the furnace and
In just a minute, Father.
You were pleased to put it on now.
Perhaps he isn't through looking at the funny paper, Sam.
Henry never does anything until he's told three times.
But, dear, he's in school all day.
When I was a boy, I had a few responsibilities.
In fact, I had a great many responsibilities.
Yes, dear. But remember, you grew up in another generation.
Henry!
Yes, Father, I'm coming right now.
Do you realize your mother is cold?
Mother, which would you rather I do?
put some coal on or bring you your sweater.
Henry, why can't you do what your father asked you to?
I'm perfectly willing to. I just like to save all the coal I can.
Henry, I'm starting right now, Father.
Just one moment, please.
You want to speak to I, Father?
No, sir. I want to speak to you.
Yes, sir. That's what I'm referring to.
Sit down a minute.
Yes, Father.
Do you know what I used to do when I was your age?
No, sir.
Believe it or not, I used to get up at six o'clock every morning.
And after helping my father milk the cows,
I walked three miles to school, sometimes
through four feet of snow.
- How's that for?
- Now Sam.
- Well, we had four feet one morning, Alice.
And when I came home from school, Henry,
I went down to the village and did odd jobs.
- Yes, father, but didn't your folks give you any money?
- Not a cent.
And at the end of my four years in high school,
do you know how much I had in the bank?
Thirty-five dollars.
Is that all?
What do you mean is that all?
It was drawing six percent interest.
Yes, Father, but nowadays a bank doesn't pay six percent.
The great reward for saving my boys.
Alice, where are you going?
Out in the hall to get a sweater.
Yes.
And Henry, right there is a very good example of what I'm driving at.
Yes, Father, I'll go right down and fix the furnace.
And in the future will you try to do things without having to be told?
Oh, yes, Father.
This talk has done me a great deal of good already.
Well, I'm pleased to hear that.
As a matter of fact, I think I have an idea that'll please you very much.
What is the idea?
Oh, you'll see.
From now on, you're gonna find a big change in me.
What's that noise?
See, I guess that must be Mother's shoveling coal.
Wait, Mother! I'm coming right down!
[Horn]
Toby, do you know what time it is?
We've got lots of time, Henry. We're only two blocks from school.
Did I tell you about my idea, Toby?
What idea?
I'm taking care of furnaces.
Who's, Henry?
Everybody's.
I think that when a person reaches our age, they ought to begin to assume a few responsibilities.
Don't you, Toby?
How much money is there in it?
Oh boy, I hate to think of it.
I've been calling up customers all morning.
How many do you have?
Well, so far I don't actually have any.
But that's just a coincidence.
It just happened that most of the people I've called so far don't need to have anyone assume their responsibilities.
Yeah?
Well, I understand Willie Marshall makes a lot of money taking care of furnaces.
He does.
Sure.
Could I go into business with you, Henry?
Oh, no, Toby.
You assume your responsibilities, and I'll assume mine.
But, Henry, we could make twice as much.
You think so?
If we could get a few families like the Vance Givers and the Peckin Paws.
Sure.
They've got money.
The only thing is, I think Willie Marshall already takes care of them.
He does.
Sure.
And I heard that every time there's a holiday, he gets a little extra from them.
Is that right? You know, I'd like to take care of the peck and pause.
Gee, my father takes care of all of Mr. Peck and pause legal matters.
It'd be nice if I could take care of his heating.
[audience laughter]
Sure. Sure, then it would be a complete all-round service.
Henry, don't look now. But isn't that willy across the street?
Where? Hey, you've powered, wait a second. Come on over, Willy.
Am I tired? What's the matter with you?
I got up at half past five this morning to ten my furnaces.
What are you eating, Willie?
Fudge and peanuts.
Fudge and peanuts?
It's my breakfast.
That's all you're gonna eat?
Candy and peanuts are all by ever eat.
For any meal?
Sure. Fudge for breakfast, peanut for lunch, chocolate for dinner.
Gee, Toby, do you hear that?
He makes so much money, all he ever eats is candy.
Hold this bag a minute, Henry.
What for?
I won't open a piece of bubble gum.
[LAUGHTER]
Willie, you wouldn't like to get rid of one or two of your customers, would you?
Why should I?
Didn't you just say you were tired?
Not that tired.
Willie, take some of your customers.
Sooner or later they'll be putting in oil burners and then where will you be?
How about it, Willie?
Well, where will our vector scum started?
Willie, while you're starting your gum, let me suggest something.
How would you like to have me give you two dollars for a couple of your customers?
I'll buy the peck and paws and the van skivers from you.
Three dollars, Henry.
Two, Willie.
Three.
But Willie, all I've got is two dollars.
My mother gave me to buy lunches with for next month.
I don't want it.
But Willie, with two dollars, you still
wouldn't have to go back on to regular food right away.
Oh, I tell you no.
Willie, I don't like to say this,
but if you don't want to sell, I
happen to be in a very unfortunate position for you.
Oh, Henry.
Well, my father happens by chance to be Mr. Peckinpaw's lawyer.
And you know what that means.
Yeah, sure.
And Henry, isn't your father Mr. Vance Skyver's lawyer too?
Yeah, come to think of it, I think he is.
Willie, what chance have you got?
Let's see the two dollars.
Here you are.
Okay, you want to buy my shovel for 50 cents extra?
Well, we need it, you think?
Sure. You can pay me any time.
That's fair enough.
How about my overall for 25 cents?
You're overall?
Henry, you can't buy overalls for any less than that.
Okay.
And is there anything else you fellas need?
No.
I got a necktie at home, I tell you.
No, Willie. Willie, what's the necktie like?
It's red, so...
Hey fellas, wait for me!
Hello, Agnes.
Wait, where you are?
Toby and I've got a hurry on so long, Willie.
Henry, let's go over to the candy store and open a chart.
Hey, what's been going on, Willie?
I just sold them the peck and paws of the van Skyver's furnaces to take care of.
Yeah?
Yeah. I wonder if they'll be mad.
Why?
Well, the van Skyver just had an oil burner put in.
Oh.
Would that make a difference?
In a way, it would.
Yesterday, the peckenpaw left for Florida.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Toby, are you sure this is where the peckenpaws live?
Sure, Henry.
Do you suppose we're going to have to get up this early every morning?
Gee, but it's dark.
Wouldn't you think somebody would be willing to get up and let us in?
I wonder whether we really ought to wake up the peckin' paws.
You mean we've gotta wait until they get up?
Well, they certainly expect us to be quiet, don't they?
Let's go around and try the cellar door.
Okay, come on, Toby.
Can you see?
Sure.
Have a piece of candy, Toby?
I don't mind if I do.
Which bag do you want some out of?
Well, let's try the one that's in your left pocket.
Toby, isn't this the cellar door?
Can you open it?
No.
Push you little Henry.
What are you doing?
Think I'm doing.
Well, Gee, Henry, we've got to get into that furnace.
Since what I say we can't shirk our responsibility the first day we begin here, I'll push with you.
Come on.
Oh, Gee, what is it?
Imagine, Henry.
The whole lot came right off.
I guess the door was rotten.
Boy is it dark down here.
Wait a minute.
What's the matter?
I walked into a cobweb.
You've got to get used to going into cellars like this, Toby.
Oh sure.
What's the matter?
I found the boiler.
Yeah?
Where?
Right over my head.
Well at least we know where it is.
Ouch!
What's that?
Well, gee whiz Toby, I just...
(screams)
Listen, Henry, do you want to wake everyone up?
Here's the furnace.
Toby, there isn't any fire in it.
You mean they let it go out?
Imagine, boy, it's a good thing we got in here before they woke up.
Do you suppose there's any kindling?
If you find a light, turn it on.
Same to you.
Here's a box, Henry. Good, can you break it up?
I guess so. There are a lot of papers in it.
We've got everything.
You know, Toby, it won't be any time until we have it so hot upstairs, Mr. and Mrs. Peck
and Paul be hanging out the window.
Sure.
When they hear about all this extra trouble we've been to, they'll make us take something
extra.
Here we go, Toby.
I'm going to touch the match to it.
Oh boy, look at that.
Imagine, we may get as much as a dollar just for striking that one match.
Ever have an easier job Henry?
I'll say I have a...
Oh gee, there goes the candy all to the floor.
Why worry about 10 or 15 cents worth of candy?
That's what I say.
Here I'll throw it in the fire.
Boy, look at it.
I never thought I'd be in a position where I could just stand back and watch Candy burn.
Hi there!
See who's that in the doorway?
Me.
Is it Mr. Packenpaw?
No, it's the milkman.
I was just going by and I seen smoke starting out of the chimney.
Are the pecking paws back?
Back? They're upstairs in bed.
They are? I thought they went to Florida.
Oh, Gee, now we've been engaged to take care of their furnace.
Well, look, how much milk do you suppose I ought to leave?
Toby, how much would you think?
I don't know. Why not they a regular amount? That's what I would say.
Okay, I'll leave six ports of milk and one a cream.
Yes, sir.
I better tell the Fred man in the newsboy if I see him.
Henry, let's start shoveling.
You know, Toby, my father was right.
If you have a job to do when you do it, it makes you feel swell.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
And now folks, let's leave Henry and Toby for a moment and turn our attention to one
of the big topics of the day, football.
Each year you know football experts select the country's outstanding players and honor
them as the All-American football team.
Well, with this All-American idea in mind, we recently decided to do the same thing in
the field of desserts.
So we ask a number of football fans what they would give as their choice for the All-American
dessert.
And here is the way these football fans reply.
Pomerac, Pomerac, Pomerac, Pomerac, row!
Wiggle wiggle wiggle wiggle wag, a zigga zagga zow!
Pomerac, a wiggle wagga zigga zagga zow!
Jell-a-dell, put it!
R-rah, r-rah, r-rah!
Uh, the English translation, "We like Jell-o the milliputting."
And that, ladies and gentlemen, is a sentiment that's being echoed around more and more family dinner tables every day.
Yes, sir, Jell-o the milliputting is winning new friends by the thousands for its tempting appearance,
for its tender, creamy goodness, and for its rich, satisfying taste.
taste. So why not let your family enjoy it too? Serve this easy, ready prepared pudding tomorrow night
with sliced bananas or whatever fruits or nuts you may have handy. Take it from me folks,
Delo Vanilla Pudding is a treat you'll soon repeat.
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich, Henry and Toby bought a furnace route from Willie Marshall.
Without realizing that the first customer he sold them at John de Florida,
the boys managed to get him to the basement and build a fire in the furnace.
The scene opens the same morning in the Aldrich dining room.
Sam!
Yes, Alice?
Come in here and eat your breakfast.
Henry, how'd he is?
He's upstairs washing.
You know Alice, it seems to me there's already been a great change in Henry.
in Henry. There has do you. He came in so covered with ashes that I didn't even know him.
Mother. Yes, Henry. I'll sweep out the bathroom just as soon as I finish breakfast.
What's happened to the bathroom? Nothing, Father. I just changed my clothes in it.
Here's the morning mail for you. Oh, thank you. Henry, what in the world
happened to you this morning? Mother, I bought out a furnace tending business from
a guy yesterday. See, are you listening, Father? Alice, who do you suppose sent this
- A letter from Florida. - From Florida?
- Father, now may I proceed.
- Well, the pecan paws seem to be having a wonderful time.
- Well, that's nice, dear.
I envy them, poise.
- The pecan paws, I have a letter from them.
- A letter from the pecan paws?
(audience laughing)
Saying they're having a wonderful time?
- What's so strange about that?
- Why didn't they just follow and tell you?
- They're neither in Florida.
- They're in Florida?
- Yeah.
(audience laughing)
- Well, what'd they go down there for?
I suppose because it's nice and warm.
Yes, they always did find their house in Centerville hard to heat.
Well, if you'll excuse me, I don't think I'll eat anymore.
Henry?
Where are you going?
Oh, just over an attempt to something I think would be a good idea to attend to.
Sam, I hope Henry isn't going to work as hard as this every day.
Best thing in the world for him to work on Saturday.
If that can pause, let her goes on to say,
Due to our haste in getting away, we overlooked a rather important item.
At the foot of our cellar stairs, we left a box of manuscripts which we would like to
have covered and shipped by express at once.
What else does he say?
Please ask whoever does the job not to litter the basement, as Mrs. Peckinford just had it
thoroughly clean.
I'll drive around and get the box on my way to the office.
[Music]
Now let me try to shake it Toby.
Henry don't you think I can shake a furnace?
[Coughing]
No.
The whole trouble is there's a clinker stuck.
Of course Toby, but you're just filling the basement up with smoke.
Here.
Well, what do you know about that?
Henry, I still don't understand it.
Are you sure the pecking paws aren't here?
Didn't I tell you I saw Mr. pecking paws' letter?
Stand back while I show up with this long poker ring.
Imagine that.
What's the matter?
Toby, can you hold up this piece of furnace pipe right over your head?
Why, Henry?
It seemed to come apart when I just hit it.
Well, that pipe's hot, Henry.
I'll hold it up with this stick here.
Hey, look at the smoke leak out.
I'll take care of the smoke. You get to work on the clinker.
I am, Toby. I am.
Wouldn't you have thought that the pecking paws would at least put up a sign saying go on to Florida? No fires, please?
Imagine Willie selling them to you.
You wait until we get Willie.
Henry, do you realize I'm holding this pipe while you just stand there and call?
Now the poker's stuck in the grate.
Well look Henry, I don't think we're getting anyplace.
So we take that pipe down for a minute.
All the way?
Sure, let's fix one thing at a time here.
Now look at the smoke come out.
That's only until we get it fixed.
I'll pull on the poker while you shake.
When I say three, yank Henry.
One, two, three, yank.
[coughing]
Did we get it out, Toby?
I think we got the whole grade out.
Oh, is that what dropped down?
We've got to do something about these hot coals that have rolled out on the floor, Henry.
Well, at least the smoke has stopped coming out of the pipe.
And nobody can say we aren't responsible.
Listen, Toby, what's that?
What, Henry?
She was at somebody walking upstairs.
Do you suppose the peck and paws are home?
They couldn't be.
Do you know what I think, Henry?
What?
Only Mr. Peck and paws away in the rest are here.
She was. This is a nice time to find that out.
Henry, we've got to get the fire back in.
How?
How at where part of the great is still hanging?
Okay.
We'll shovel real quietly.
Quiet, Henry.
Henry.
You think he can match too loud?
Well I can hear it, but then I'm right here.
Sure, and you know what I'm doing.
What do you suppose that can be?
There must be a fire someplace.
I wonder where they're going.
Come on Toby, let's go out in front and see which way they're headed.
That's what I say.
Here hold the door open.
There's one thing I like, it's a good fire.
Toby!
Toby, look, the engines are stopping right out in front!
And they are unloading their hulls!
Toby, I think we better be leaving!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Toby, about what time do you think it is?
Must be darn near time for dinner.
Will your folks give you the juice when you get home?
I'm gonna perfectly good excuse, Toby.
If they ask where I was today,
I can say I was way out in the country.
Sure, that's because that's where we are.
Sure, that's what I mean.
Here, have a piece of candy.
No, thanks.
I'm not hungry either.
I told you when you made Willie give back your money,
you shouldn't spend the whole business on candy.
She was, you bought enough to nearly fill this barn.
Well, first few pounds tasted good, didn't they?
What's that, Henry?
That's just Willy's trying to get out again.
Hey, shut up, Willy!
Let me off here!
Go chase yourself, Willy.
We aren't gonna let you out until you promise.
Promise what?
Are you gonna tell our folks
that we were the cause of those fire engines coming out?
Are you gonna give me back my $2?
Back along to Henry, Willy.
And besides, we've eaten your $2.
(laughing)
Well, you're not gonna make me promise not to squeal.
All right, then you can stay in there.
That's what I say.
Come on, Toby.
I guess we'll go back to Centerville.
Do you mean that, Henry?
No, we'll just let him think it.
But Henry's supposing we have to keep him here all night.
Toby, don't you realize what'll happen if he tells?
They carried every piece of furniture
out of Peck and Paws House
and then had to carry it all back in again.
(audience laughing)
Do you want your father to know you were mixed up in it?
Well, let's go back and force Willie to promise.
Okay, but let me do the talking.
Oh, Willie.
Willie, we've got a little proposition to put up to you.
All right, Willie, if you don't want any of this candy.
Listen, Willie.
Willie, stop sulking.
Henry, look through the crock here.
What do you say?
Gee whiz, open the door.
Toby, Toby, he's gone.
You mean he's escaped?
He's probably on his way to my house right now.
Oh boy.
Yeah?
Maybe he's on his way to mine.
Come on, we've got to beat him back home.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Well, Sam, do you still think you were right?
About what?
You said that from now on, we'd see a big change in Henry.
Well, he didn't come home for lunch,
and here it is, time for dinner.
All in all, Alice, this has been a very pleasant day.
I still can't get over it.
And when do you suppose I will?
To make the thing doubly embarrassing, Alice.
When I saw smoke pouring out of the house,
I had to be the one who turned in the alarm.
But there wasn't any fire at all?
Only in the furnace.
But it took nearly all the rest of the day
getting the place straightened up again.
And those two tramps the firemen saw running away
from the house had been living in the basement.
Not really, Sam.
That's what they'd been doing.
That's why they built a fire in the furnace
to keep warm. Why, Alice, they were even having their milk and bread delivered there.
Oh, my goodness!
We even found today's paper there. And what was left of a bag of marshmallows?
What on earth have they been doing with marshmallows?
Probably toasting them. And the box, Alice. The box of manuscripts that Peck and Paul wanted me to express to.
Were they gone?
Probably they had been burned. Burn, mind you. And nobody knows how valuable they were.
Well, what are you going to do?
I don't know. I wired Peckinpaw. Who's that?
Is everybody all right?
Is that you, Henry?
Yes, Mother. I hope I haven't kept your dinner waiting.
And will you please come in here?
Has anything happened while I was away?
Happened?
I mean, there hasn't been anybody here at the house to see you, has there?
Oh, for instance. Well, anybody.
You know, I just wondered whether any one of the fellas I know had dropped in.
No, Henry.
- Oh, well, I'm glad I didn't miss anyone then.
- Henry, where have you been all day?
- Oh, well, tell me and I just took a walk outside town
to look at the countryside.
- Did you?
- Yeah, we explored an old barn.
Would you like to take a walk out that way sometime, Father?
- I've had all the exercise I need.
Thank you.
- Oh.
- Your father has been carrying furniture all day, Henry.
(audience laughing)
- He has?
He's been changing the house around?
been changing the house around yes but not this house I'll answer the phone
Henry yes mother if I were you I'd be very careful for the next day or so not
to do anything to upset your father you would yes dear hurry upstairs and
wash while I answer the door I just assume answer it I'll answer it but
mother I'm Mrs. Olridge is Mr. Olridge here he's on the phone will they
mother is that Willie Marshall yes dear he wants to see your father what
Mrs. Alders, I just assume tell you.
Listen, Willie, my mother's very busy.
Oh, no, she isn't, Henry.
What is it you walk, Willie?
Mother, don't I smell something burning out in the kitchen?
Bernie?
Oh, dear, it's probably the same thing.
Listen, Willie, you beat it.
Do you hear me?
You make me.
Get your foot out of the door.
I don't want to tell your fault.
He was, Willie.
Looking back of you.
Where?
Right there.
Hey, you!
Goodbye, Willie.
Mother.
What is it there?
Are you out here in the kitchen?
Yes.
That's all I wanted to know.
Do you feel a draft here?
I think I'll lock this back door.
Well, Alice, I just had an answer to my wire.
What does it say?
Box of manuscripts were only Mrs. Peck
and Paul's minutes of the woman's club.
Don't worry.
What's that, Father?
Oh, nothing to concern, you son.
He also says returning Monday.
He's coming back?
Why shouldn't he?
He also says, please engage Willie Marshall
to clean up basement and start furnace.
Could you read that again, Father?
I understand exactly what he means. Do you know where Willie Marshall is?
Yes sir, but...
He was just here.
Henry, I want you to run over and tell him to straighten that basement out and get a fire started.
But, but Father, why should Willie do it when I'm right here?
He asks to have Willie do it.
But, Mother, I won't charge.
Why not?
Well, I'd like to give Mr. Peck and Paul an introductory offer.
Henry, I'm sorry, but you're not going to do any more work tonight.
But, Mother, I feel sorry for Mr. Peck and Paul.
Why?
Well, he's a friend of fathers.
Well, all I can say, son, is that I'm certainly glad to see you shoulder some responsibility.
Now, what's that?
Oh, I guess that's just something banging against the cellar door.
Well, I better go fix it.
Father, you stay where you are. I'll fix it.
Well, thank you, son.
I'll just get my baseball bat and attend to it right away.
[audience laughter]
[music]
[applause]
Henry Orridge will be back in just a moment.
Now, tomorrow, friends, make it a special point to order several packages of those grand, ready prepared desserts,
desserts, jello puddings. You'll be delighted to find out how quick and inexpensive they
are to serve and how luscious they taste. So, asker goes up for all three flavors, jello
chocolate pudding, jello vanilla pudding, and jello butter scotch pudding. Jello puddings
are made by the makers of jello so you know they're good
hello
mister peckenpaw
or you're going to take care of your furnace yourself
Well, might I suggest Mr. Peckinport if you do take care of it, I wouldn't shake it until spring.
Listen again next Thursday evening to the Aldrich family and to the Maxwell House Coffee Time Program,
which immediately preceded on most of these stations.
A solid hour of sparkling radio entertainment every Thursday night.
The All-rich family, starring as Rustone, is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
Original music is composed and conducted by Jack Miller.
Now this is Harry Vonsell bidding you all good night.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(audience applauding)
(applause)
(gunshot)