[Music]
Memories almighty thing you would bring at best.
And the farther back you reach, the more faded you remember it.
Well, if you want to revise the memory of your youth, there's no better way
than knowing a lively teenage boy like Henry Aubrey.
It's morning and the scene opens in the Aubrey's kitchen.
Now, the itself is almost there to the E.S. Mary.
Is it not that a car?
No, no, Mary.
It had a very hard day yesterday letting it sleep.
- Great, what do you call that, how's it going?
- Good, good, good, good.
- Just go on the clockwalk.
- Oh, dear.
Mary's scrubbing it again.
- Yes.
- But he scrubbed it all day yesterday
and he didn't get any of it all.
- I know, but I think it's morning
if you can cut some time.
- The poor boy I'll go calling.
- You're gonna start the copy, mop, and please, Mary.
- Alice, where's the morning, my friend?
- The right beside your plate, Sam.
Mary, then you'll bother to use.
- Pardon me.
Breakfast is ready.
- In just a minute, mother.
I think I'm finally getting somewhere with a sidewalk.
The red paint's coming off.
Nobody's starting to turn pink now, and...
(crying)
Or is it just that the sun's finally come up?
Yeah, may I say something?
Any young lady who'd fly off the handle,
the way that it did yesterday,
just because of a little something
that somebody wrote on a sidewalk.
Well, I wouldn't exactly call this a little something.
After all, it put me in a very compromising position
with Nancy Adams.
- Side by side. - And I just figure if I can erase out that. If you're going to send another day scrubbing out here, you're going to need your energy. So let's go in.
- No, no, no, no, no. - Let me go. Let me go. Let me go. Mary, what's happening? - It's in the comfort of starting with. - I'm starting to walk outside. - Well, Mary, what are you talking about?
- I thought I wrote an error about it to the editor. Let's go there at the morning. - Well, my goodness. Let's see it. - Mary, he didn't go and mention Nancy's in my name, did he?
I don't know.
Just go on some old boy.
Come on Mary.
Well, this person or a person's vote on our side.
Oh, you didn't go and quote the exact
verbatim words did you?
Of course not.
Excuse me.
What this person or person's vote on our sidewalk
is not the concern of this letter.
Mm-hmm.
Gee, thanks Father.
But the desecration of property, both public and private,
is a matter which should arise every citizen in Santaville.
I for one feel it is high time our town council
took steps to eradicate the rising tide of vandalism.
Samuel W. Aldrich, Samuel D'Happell, you argue.
Then why you're at it?
You can just as well have added attorney at law.
- All right.
- Then right after breakfast, I want you to go down
and get a half dozen copies of the paper.
- For heaven's sake.
- I'm gonna need at least that many to send away.
- I just think you're making a big fuss over nothing.
After all, the letter to the editor isn't such a,
you really like him?
I think it's a very well written letter.
It is? Oh, yes.
And you use such a wonderful choice of words, didn't you, ma'am?
Ma'am, yes.
Well...
You got what you wanted to get to, boys?
I lost my father?
Oh, well, I...
You just wondered if half a dozen copies are going to be enough.
Alex, believe me, it's not that good.
And I'll be here?
Every time.
I've already ordered a few extra copies.
You had?
But only because I knew you were in this, on mailing them out.
Oh, good.
How many did you order?
Enough.
And just for the record, I'd like it to be known
that the only reason I bothered to write that letter was to help Henry.
Me, Father?
Yes, I think once Gladys sees my letter, she'll realize you couldn't possibly have painted that on the sidewalk.
You really think so?
Of course it's just gladness!
Yeah, the only trouble is gladness isn't too strong on logic.
Although, excuse me, when I put in a phone call.
Let's see, when my sister bailed, when do you have a gun?
M203, please.
Mother, do you think you would help my marks, any if I showed it to my English teachers?
I don't think anything could hurt them.
Hello?
Oh, hello, Mrs. Claddis. This is Henry.
Oh, yes, Henry.
I mean, I speak with Gladis.
I'm not afraid not, Henry.
He means he's not there.
And not just a moment.
Oh.
He's gone out?
No.
As a matter of fact, he hasn't gone out since yesterday.
Oh?
He's upstairs in a room.
Oh.
And he's been up there since yesterday.
Mrs. Claddis,
Do you know if by any chance,
GLATERS happen to see this morning?
- Hang in, ring.
- Hang in. - Hang in.
- Hey, look quick. - What's wrong?
- You better tell me what I just saw.
- What, you beat it?
Mrs. Prentice, there's a slight intercomotion here.
- When you're listening,
- Oh, my. - What I find another sign
about you and me.
- Well, can't you just wait to watch?
- What? - I'm gonna say,
and throw over and do three.
- Oh, boy. - Hello.
- And Mrs. Prentice, pardon me if I say goodbye,
temporarily. - Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Who did it?
Who's the wise guy?
- I don't know, but somebody has to get you.
- Not sure, yeah, well I'll show him a thing or two,
whoever the wise guy is, come on.
- He was, what this power of meat-tape
is doing on your front porch?
- Today's Center of Old Times, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Oh, they must be the copies my father ordered.
- Yeah, he's going into the business?
- No, Homer, come on.
(upbeat music)
- How much further is it, Homer?
- Right in the middle of the next slide.
If you ask me, some guys have a pretty crude sense of humor, painting the town red with my name.
Yeah, I just look glad it finds out all the trouble I'm going to for her sake.
Let's cross here.
Okay.
Well, my father was in the paper once.
He wrote a letter to the editor too.
No, it was the time he sued the railroad for Pina.
For what?
Pina, Pina.
He put a penny more than a penny, so you're nothing to me now.
He sued them for that?
No, that was just the way it started.
My father put his hand up the machine with that stuff.
The machine?
No, his hand.
And he missed his train and lost a big contact because of it.
So he sued.
Is that right?
What happened?
Be corrected.
You know?
Well, I'm telling you, Paine's opinion.
My father said, "There it is, homie.
Just look at that fence.
This is the greatest daylight boy if I ever text a guy that did this."
You know what I'll do.
Do you know what I'll do?
Why?
I'll...
Well, you're regret it as long as you live.
Maybe longer.
OK, here's a brush for you and one for me.
Come on, let's get started painting this out.
Well, before we do this, you don't
suppose the person who owns this same small pig.
Pig?
Well, you ought to be glad I don't steal them.
No matter what fact, I bet I've got a darn good pig.
I'm right there.
Helping to defamate my character.
I bet I have a darn good pig.
Come right on, father.
My father said those peanuts cost him $200 a pound.
Come on, let's start painting.
Okay.
You start on the Henry and I'll work on Nancy
and we'll meet in the middle.
Wait a second, Henry.
What's the matter?
See those two men across the street?
What about them?
Is that a camera they have there?
No, I think they're probably surveying something.
We hope it's here or not.
Come on, Homer, let's start painting
or we'll never get done.
Hi, how are you?
See, it's Mary.
Hi, Mary.
Hi, Homer.
Did you do what I asked you to?
I just came to talk to Mrs. Pettis.
Did you casually mention that the order tell Gladys to look at the letters to the editor, Karlman?
Oh, goodness, because I found out that the judges don't take the photo of those times anymore.
They don't? How come?
They go back to Venice, it's from Canada.
Well, what's that got to do with it?
Well, she said they have not a copy in their office, but they put them out against London.
Do you, Whiz Mary? If that is typical of you.
Oh, maybe it's you to do the simplest possible thing in your life. Somebody named Lamben get mixed up in it.
and we may be back to your house and get one of your father's take.
Well, I've been saying that if you're going to do that to better,
I want it because they're going fast.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
In the living room, Alice.
Here, do you know what-- what are you doing?
Well, I'm just writing something.
So I know what.
You know the rest of the papers are.
Oh, there aren't any more.
Oh, papers are gone.
Well, it's the race you've been mailing them out.
Sam, so far, I've only used two.
I saw.
Well, Henne came in a while ago and took some.
One, anyway.
In the world, few people, I thought I'd like to--
Alice, I'd like to get your opinion on something.
What is it?
Which of these sound better to you?
Main Street, ma'am, or Perot, the life and limb.
You're writing a murder, Mr. H?
No, no, a letter to the editor.
Just occurred to me that--
Alice, have you ever noticed how traffic gets snarled
around Maine and Ellen Street at five o'clock.
Or do you think a letter about the new tax assessment
would be of greater interest?
- You wanna get that fan?
- All right.
- Mother, do you want me to start right?
- Oh.
- It's a little early, late.
- Yeah.
- Larry, look at this.
- Who you think?
- Apparently, a list of things your father's thinking
of writing to the editor about.
- Is he gonna be writing to the people every day?
- I hope not.
- Or his law practice will just go to pieces.
- All right.
- Yes, fan.
- Now, that's where you might as well
put a light under the potato.
- Yes, mother.
- What was that on the phone, Sam?
- That Alice was the editor of the "Centerville Times."
- Really?
- Huh?
- Seems I've really started something down there.
He said a couple of reporters out this morning
and they just came back with a picture of two of those vandals
called "Light and the Act of Smearing Up a Fan."
- Oh, my!
- And he's gonna run it in tonight's paper
along with the second editorial he's writing.
Now that's what I call getting action.
- I should say, now over those vandals.
- Oh, just a couple of kids, he said.
(laughs)
Said they both looked as though they had been shot.
- Oh, dear.
I'll finally get what's coming to them.
Grinch it.
What do you think will happen to them?
I wouldn't be a bit surprised if they both wound up
in the foreign school.
Well, personally, I don't think it was a bit fair.
Taking those poor boys by surprise that way.
What do you want them to do?
I thought food limbs to pose.
After all, they were violating the law.
I realize that, then I realize that.
But just think of how the parents of those boys
are going to feel when they see that picture.
It seems to me that's something a parent should think
before him naturally you feel that way you're a lawyer I'm also a parent but you're not a mother
that is if you were you wouldn't let the editor print that picture how can I stop him
he started the whole thing didn't you yes but well you guys can't tell the editor that if he
insists on turning the picture you will write him any more letters well Alan
[Music]
Oh, Grottus! Grottus!
I don't think she gives you him.
What do you think you just go up and ring the bell?
Oh, but from what her mother told me this morning, I don't think that's too wild.
Well, how else are you going to get this copy of the paper to her?
If I can just get her to come to the window for a second, I'm sure she'll...
Wait a second. I think I know how I can get her attention. Stand back.
You know, throwing rocks at us, there's always no way to make up.
It's not a rock, it's just a cobble.
And I'm only going to hit the window with it.
The window...scuse me.
Where are you going?
I think I'll watch you across the street.
Why are you silly? I'm only going to hit it lightly.
Watch.
Boy, and the coach Nelson was wrong about you.
And what way?
He said you couldn't even hit the side of a house.
Where's another pebble?
Here, and then we'll try it one.
Can we actually move it?
Okay, but remember, lightly, sure, sure.
Homer went right through the window.
Yeah, but I think about it, I think he...
You think so?
See, there she is, there she is.
Oh, my God, I got it.
I hope we didn't disturb you or anything, did we?
Is that a picture of all the names you have there,
if I had it?
- Gladys, what are you doing with that?
- What are we doing with that?
- What are we getting out of it?
- Oh, oh, oh!
Gladys, I just want to ask you to give a signal to me.
- Morning!
- Oh, boy.
- Oh, okay, and we have you got any more ideas like that?
(dramatic music)
- And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Alvarez.
It's just a little later now, and the scene is still outside Gladys Senator House.
Now Homer, have you got that straight?
I...so...so?
We just stopped hopping up and down like that.
But I've still got some water in my ear.
The last one pops already, but still working on the rice.
Well, what a dry out by natural means.
Now go ahead, and remember, the important thing is to get the paper in the Gladys' house.
Okay.
and you don't have to mention my name in there unless the situation changes.
My daddest.
You know what just happened to think?
What?
Wouldn't it be easier for you to just start going to Nancy Adams?
Oh, well, hi Mrs. Prayman.
Hello, Homer.
Would you come here?
Thank you.
You suppose I could speak to Gladys, sir, I'm gonna...
No, I don't know.
You're a pretty good friend of Henry Ausridge, aren't you?
Wait.
Where a queen is?
Hmm.
Well, I ask you, but I don't know if you're come down.
Oh, by the way, Homer, you aren't by any chance
through with that newspaper, are you?
For this, now, if you're still reading it,
then never mind.
You'd like to have it?
Only if you're sure that you should.
Oh, yes, ma'am, here you are.
Thank you.
I'll call about it.
Oh, that is a necessary, you know.
It is, no, ma'am.
I'll just be running along.
Goodbye, Homer.
And thanks again to the paper.
You're entirely welcome.
And I hope you and I'm glad I've seen Joy reading it.
Oh, I didn't want it to read.
You didn't?
No.
I guess he did something to wrap my plate of healing, then.
Well, well, the guys, but Mrs. Turner,
that person was in cleanly to Father I.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Not me.
Wait a second, Miss Robert.
Let me close this door.
Yeah, that's better.
I'm glad you got that, Miss Robert.
Frankly, I didn't get what you were driving it on the phone.
Well, Miss Sanders and I think we had a bad connection.
No, we must have been.
I kept thinking what you were saying was that we should feel that picture of the two vandals.
I didn't say that exactly.
Of course it didn't.
What I said was whether we oughtn't to stop and think about it first.
About what?
Well, the ceiling of the boy's parents, the possible effects on...
Well, that sort of thing.
Just thinking is a parent, you think?
I'm as well as a time of thought that too, you know.
Yes, but you're not a mother.
Huh?
I mean, what my wife, what I was going to suggest was that perhaps we ought to have these boys in and just give them talk to the government.
Oh, Mr. Holmes, you know what your trouble is? You're too soft-hearted.
I know. You know, but that would be kind of kids before, but I have. And you can't pant for them.
Well, my wife...
Then you'll see the shop we got of them.
Why, you just have to take one look at their faces to know that their potential's criminal.
Is that right?
And those are the kind of kids you're feeling sorry for?
Well, my wife, don't you see that publishing their pictures is going to teach them a lesson they'll never forget?
Well, I wonder if you'd mind calling my wife and explaining.
No matter a fact, the more I think of it, the more I feel I ought to give that picture the widest possible script.
Yes, sir.
Excuse me.
Oh, Joe, uh, see you?
Yes, sir, sir.
Come in a minute.
Uh, Joe, I'll just decide I'd like to move that picture of the two kids in the editorial page for the front page.
To the front, but what about your editorial?
Well, let's see if we can help suit that on the front page too.
- When's the name?
- Jack, now what about that other picture I had penciled in?
- Which one was that?
- You know, that cab driver and his 13 daughters.
Oh, what was that story about again?
What was it about?
Yeah, what did this cab guy to do?
Well, he had 13 daughters, isn't that enough?
(audience laughing)
- Oh, we can run that some other time.
- Well, the only thing is this cab driver's already put
in his order for 40 copies of tonight's paper
for his immediate family.
Oh, well, I was thinking in the back somewhere then, on the source page.
On the source page.
[LAUGHTER]
Yeah, with the batting average.
[INAUDIBLE]
Because I think they story about the bandages.
Oh, excuse me, Joe.
This is Mr. Aldridge.
Follow up with that letter.
Oh, yeah, please, to meet you.
How do you do?
Yeah.
Hey, you're going to tell us.
If you have to meet in that letter, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Go get the camera quick.
Jack.
Mr. Aldridge, I think I've wheeled up a whole something.
Yes, what is it?
It's an idea that's going to--
OK, Joe?
Yeah.
I'll get this, Joe, and see if you don't think it's dynamite.
And it's over.
Just stand up against this wall here.
What?
You'll say, well, let me have your hat.
Now, just face this way, see?
And hold your arms straight out.
You're pointing, see?
Look, sir.
A little more.
More?
All right, get that, Joe.
Yeah.
Got it.
But if you want my picture for it.
I'm going to run it right next to the picture of those two
with you pointing straight up and face.
And the cuts in the cross the top will read, "Get this girl.
Dad, we must stop this. Dad."
I don't know Homer. I just don't know if that's such a hot idea.
Why? Why? Did you ever hear of anybody refusing to look at a telegram?
Sure, when they're sent collect.
But we're told.
- Hey, well, what have you got written down?
- C pays a this morning's time,
probably with potato peelings.
(audience laughing)
- And how is it signed?
- Oh, who's that?
- Just an earlier machine, and that's confusing.
- Why not just write anonymous?
- Okay.
- A-N-N-O.
You write it.
(audience laughing)
Okay. A-N-O.
I come to think of it as anonymous enough.
Yeah.
Well, do you want to send this?
I don't know.
Suppose they've already had their garbage collected.
You wish.
And they make up your mind.
Do you realize you practically ruined the whole Saturday from me?
Well, the my fault if every store in town has sold out their papers?
They didn't really look what's right in store of this paragraph office.
Well, I'll be darned.
Come on.
I didn't think of coming in here in the first place.
Sure.
They didn't have this morning's paper.
Nobody will.
Of course.
And, Homer, I promise you, as soon as I get it over to Gladys's, we'll spend the rest
of the day on whatever you want to do.
The rest of the watchday, it's almost time to suffer.
Yeah.
Well, let's ask right here.
Oh, mister, yes, any--a copy of today's "
Center for Times" place.
No, but we don't have one this, you know?
She will talk of the "Sendingville Prime" and be out of the "Sendingville Prime."
Oh, we've had quite a run of them today.
Boy.
What am I going to do Homer?
You couldn't just learn off one more copy for us could you?
Yes, I was very nuts.
But that's anyway you might do.
You see that door there?
Yeah.
And that's the composing room.
When the person there might just have an extra copy.
He's saying, at least I can do it.
What kind of a room do you say a wash hand?
A composing room.
Oh.
What are they doing there?
Well, Homer, don't you know anything?
Our composing room is--
what's the place where it's a composing room?
I guess we better knock first.
Knock? What floor?
So we don't disturb their train and fraud while they're compounding.
Homer, come on.
Here's a way of talking to this in polls with all its noise.
Do you think anybody we can ask?
How about that, sir?
Where?
When coming this way, carrying that sort of train.
Oh, yeah.
Mr. Can I ask you something?
Sorry, Sonny.
The paper goes to press in the five minutes.
Why don't you come around when they have one of those tours?
Oh, no.
You don't understand.
The man outside said I might be able to get an extra copy
this morning's paper in here. Oh, I don't know if that one or not here.
Well, you hold this one and take a look at my desk. Sure. I'll be sure and hold it
level, Bob. Yes, sir. Boy, look at this, Tom. Yeah. What is it? It looks like a
page from the paper. Isn't that right, Mr? Yeah, that's the front page. It's a nice
paper. Well, I tell my folks I was holding it. I was pretty sure I had a
paper somewhere isn't it, there. You know what, Bernie? Why? See that's just your
right in the center of the page.
Notice when the light hits it one way it's negative.
Yeah. And then it gets dripped a little like this.
And see the way it's going to look when it's finished.
That's right.
These would be a picture of a couple of kids, doesn't it?
Yeah.
What are they doing?
What's to me like they're painting a...
painting a...
...mover.
They need a painting, aren't they?
Maybe not, but it sure is.
I can't quite see who it is.
Oh boy.
Somebody in the house?
Quite like my father.
What?
Three.
Can we go get the kill fly?
Come and grab it!
Get out!
Oh boy.
Some are going loose.
What'd you do?
Mr. I'm afraid we'd go.
Oh no.
Look at my size.
Mr. Ed's kicking on what I ought to do to you, kid.
You know what I want to do to you kids.
No, he's Mr. Lettingly.
He's put the paper to bed in just a few minutes.
Now what am I going to do?
Say goodnight.
[LAUGHTER]
Oh, Mr. Will be glad to help you out.
Oh, you will.
I'm sure we send you all to be able to get back together
before the paper wakes up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I heard someone on the porch.
You do?
It must be the paper, boy.
Excuse me.
I'm like that's a cager up.
I'll take that, honey.
Not funny father. It's me.
Oh, oh, hello, Henry.
Good evening, Father.
You've been till now.
Why?
Homer and I stopped to help a man pick up.
Some things.
Then it gets you this way.
Well, there were quite a few of these things.
You don't see it.
We had some exciting news for you.
You'll follow this picture.
going to be on the front page of tonight's paper. Yeah, I know. I mean, how do you know?
Why you? Well, I haven't been having this paper office and I thought you did. Is it a good
picture of your father? Well, was he shy straight? I don't know how straight it is anymore. I
Well, I only got a quick glance, mother.
Oh, well, isn't it exciting, Henry?
Yeah.
Well, I must say you don't sound very enthusiastic.
I don't?
Well, just because I don't sound it, don't think I am.
I mean, I'm not.
I mean, Henry, is anything wrong?
Why, you know--
Wait a second.
I think I hear the paper boy now.
The father before you go out there,
I feel there's something I want to tell.
And all right, just that they get the paper.
You've got to wait it.
What I want to tell you about.
You know that picture they took of you.
Yes.
Well, I think it's only fair for you to know that.
The two boys you're pointing at.
A home friend made.
What?
Sam old.
But how?
What were you?
Good heaven.
Hi, everybody.
Something wrong.
I guess it is wrong.
Oh, I just told my father about the paper.
Oh, I've got a copy of her right here. Would anyone like to see it?
Warren, you just couldn't wait to bring the bad news, could you?
Well, Henry, that's the point. We're not on the front page.
We're not?
You mean I'm not either?
Oh, you are, you sure, Aldi?
Let me see that, please.
Sure.
Let me look too Sam.
Oh, heaven's taste.
Then what's that you're pointing at?
It's a taxi driver and it's safety and order.
[ Laughter ]
What are you supposed to be saying?
We must stop this.
You're a genuine boy.
[ Laughter ]
(static)