[Music]
And now the Jell-O family presents...
Henry! Henry Olgrich!
Coming, Mother!
[Applause]
Yes, it's the Olgrich family based on characters
originated by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Ezra Stonner's Henry with Jackie Kelk as Homer.
And yes, it's the Jell-O family.
Oh, the Big Red Letter stand for the Jell-O family.
That's Jell-O.
The Union, the Jell-O pudding.
The Union, the Union, the Jell-O pudding.
The Union, the Union, the Union, the Union, the Union, the Union, the Union.
The Jell-O tack, the Oka pudding.
Yes, Harry!
And now for the Aldrich family.
(dramatic music)
One of the most enjoyable things a man can do
is think back to the time when he was a teenage boy
like Henry Aldrich, with no cares, no worries,
no responsibilities.
But when you actually are the boy,
Things aren't always that pleasant.
The scene opens in the Aldrich living room.
It's early evening.
(sighs)
Father.
Pardon me, Father.
- What is it, Henry?
- Would you like to read something very interesting?
- I was.
- Well, I mean this book, Father.
Gee, it's wonderful.
It's all about two fellows, sing.
- That's very interesting.
- I knew you'd like it, Father.
You see, Bruce and Rodney are very close friends.
You might almost say they're practically inseparable.
One would do anything for the other.
- Very interesting.
- For instance, once Rodney's in trouble, see,
he's in a fight with five other fellows.
Only I won't tell you how he gets into it
'cause I don't wanna spoil the book for you.
- Thank you.
- Meanwhile, Bruce doesn't know anything
about Rodney's predicament.
He's home in bed, getting ready to go to sleep, see?
But all of a sudden he feels uneasy.
He tries to shake it off,
but he can't get rid of the feeling
that all is not well with Rod.
So he gets stressed.
- The phone, Henry.
- Oh, he thought about that father,
but he didn't know where to reach Rodney.
- Our phone, Henry.
- Oh, oh, I'll get it, father.
Hello?
- Hi, him.
- Look, Homer, could I call you back in a few minutes?
I'm right in the middle of a story.
I'm telling my father.
- All right, Henry, I can go.
- It's very important, Henry.
Couldn't it just went, are you in trouble, pal?
- Sort of.
- Good, I'll be right over.
- You don't have to come over and I just want to ask you
something.
- Oh, go right ahead, pal.
Anything at all.
- Thanks, him.
- I could come over, Homer.
- It isn't necessary.
I can ask you over the phone.
All you have to do is answer yes or no.
- The answer is yes.
- How do you know?
- Listen, pal.
When one pal calls another pal,
On the first palace in trouble, what else can the second palace say but yes?
No.
Not if they're real pals, Homer.
Henry, maybe you better wait till you hear what it is.
Well it doesn't matter, Homer, but go ahead if you want to.
Well, you know the school dance in a couple of weeks.
Sure, you want me to get you a date, is that it?
No, I already have a date, Agnes.
As a matter of fact, it's just the uh... Henry, did you invite anyone yet?
No, Kathleen's out of town.
I'm just sort of making up my mind.
That's good.
I mean, the fact of the matter is, Hen, that Agnes...
You see, Agnes has a...
Well, when I asked Agnes, she...
Oh, boy...
Look, Homer, we're friends, aren't we?
Sure, Hen.
Good friends.
Sure.
Practically inseparable, you might say.
Well, then just ask me, Homer, just ask me.
That's all.
Come right out and say it.
Okay, Hen.
The fact of the matter is that a cousin of Agnes
is just coming to visit her the weekend of the dance
An Agnes asked me to get someone to take her.
Okay.
You mean you will?
Sure.
Just like that?
Of course.
You need me, pal.
I'm there.
Gee, thanks, ham.
You'd do the same for me, wouldn't you?
Sure, certainly.
So there you are.
Is this L-431?
What?
Sure.
Is this Henry Aldrich?
Naturally.
The Henry older, she was a friend named Homer Brown.
Of course.
Well, I'll be done.
By him, I've got a co-agnition teller.
So long, old pal.
Remember, any time at all.
Where was I, pal?
I mean, Father.
My next spice was getting dressed.
What homo on?
Not spice, Father.
Bruce.
He wanted me to take Agnes' cousin to the dance.
Now, let's see.
Bruce was worried.
What'd you like?
father. He, Homa, wanted you to take Agnes' he cousin to the den? She was no,
she's a she. Bruce is a he. Well, thank heaven. I met Agnes' cousin,
Henry. What's she like? I don't know. Anyway, there was Bruce. You don't know.
And now she's from out of town. Oh, I thought you were through with blind date.
Well, generally speaking, I am father, but this is different. My pal needs me. I
I see.
Mine not to question why.
Mine but to do and die.
Very likely.
What?
Nothing, Henry.
Then why are you shaking your head like that?
Son, it's been my experience that a man takes quite a chance on a blind date.
More often than not, he gets stuck.
But Father Homer's a very close friend of mine, practically inseparable, you might
say.
Do you really think I'll get stuck?
Well, that shouldn't matter, Henry.
a pal need you sure but what if she's fat
what if who's fat and bangus's cousin mother do you think she might be fat or
skinny I suppose there's always that possibility she was why should that have
said you so much and read just accepted a blind date with a young lady in question
oh well I'm sure she's very nice you really think so mother do you really
father says more often than not a man gets stuck on a blind date is that what
your father says? How interesting considering the fact that he met me on a blind date.
Now Alice.
What else did your father say?
Well, he just...
Henry.
Yes, father?
Alice, when I said what I said to Henry, I had no particular personal situation in mind.
And besides, all I said was...
That a man gets stuck on a blind date.
I didn't say that, Alice. All I said was...
- That was fun.
(upbeat music)
- Gee whiz Henry, why didn't you think of that
before I told Agnes should go?
- Look home.
- A half hour ago you were such a pal,
you didn't even wanna know what I wanted.
And now look at you.
- Homer, I didn't come all the way over to your house
to say I won't go.
It's still very possible.
I may take Agnes's cousin to the day.
- When will you know?
as soon as I find out a little more about it.
- Okay, what do you wanna know?
- Is she pretty?
- I don't know.
- Is she fat?
- Is she skinny?
- I don't know.
Is there anything else you wanna ask, can we?
(audience laughing)
- Well, what do you know about it?
- Her name is Martha Adams.
She lives in Hollendale and she's Agnes' cousin.
- Well, don't you know anything else about her?
- Physically, I mean.
- No.
Except that she is Agnes's cousin.
Well, she was cousins don't always look alike, you know.
- That's the big trouble with your Homer.
All you know are the unimportant things.
Nothing about how she looked.
- Henry, after all, you're just gonna dance
with the girl for a few hours.
It isn't as though you were marrying her.
- You never can tell, Homer.
You never can tell.
Look at what happened to my father.
- What happened?
- He met my mother on a blind date.
- Oh, well, they're happy, aren't they?
- Not right at the moment.
(audience laughing)
And besides, let's not change the subject.
I've got my reputation to think about.
- Why?
- If word gets around that Henry oldridge
goes out with unattractive girls, from that moment on,
I'm finished with the attractive ones.
- Why didn't you think of that when I first asked you?
- Because I was trying to be a pal.
Didn't Agnes say anything about her cousin?
- Nope.
I wonder why.
- Because I never asked her.
- Well, why didn't you?
- Because, you know, you brought it up,
it wasn't important.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
Hi, Homer.
Oh, pal.
Hi, Agnes.
I just got into my mother told me you called.
What do you want?
Homer, one minute Agnes.
What ever you...
Ask her now.
Ask her what?
About her cousin Martha.
Is she pretty or fat or what?
You know, vital statistics.
Okay.
Hello, Agnes.
What did you want to tell me, Homer?
Well, well, how are you, Agnes?
I'm fine.
How are you?
Fine.
That's fine.
How's your mother?
She's fine.
That's Mary's.
Uh, how's your...
He's fine too.
That's good.
What's good?
Gee whiz, Homer, why don't you ask her?
Hold on, Agnes, because you've got to lead up to something like that gradually.
Um, Agnes.
Yeah?
How's...
How's your cousin Martha?
Who knows?
Oh, what's she saying?
She said, "Who knows?"
You'll have to talk louder, Homer.
I can't hear you.
I was talking to Henry.
Oh, is he there with you?
- Yeah, as a matter of fact, we were sort of talking
about our plans for the dance.
And Henry was just wondering,
what color hair Martha has?
- Why?
- So, well, so we know what color tie it aware.
- Oh.
- He doesn't want to wear a tie that would clash with her head.
- Oh!
(audience laughing)
- What color is her head?
- Gee, I don't know.
- Oh, what'd she say?
- She said she doesn't know.
- How come?
- How come Agnes?
'Cause I haven't seen her since she was nine years old.
Oh, what'd she say?
Oh, no, that's what you said.
Oh, thank you.
She said she hasn't seen her since she was nine years old.
What?
Well, ask her what she was like when she was nine.
Agnes, what was she like when she was nine?
Boy, she was a whiz.
She was a whiz, Ham.
She was?
Ask her in what way?
In what way, Agnes?
In school.
Oh.
What'd she say?
She was a whole year ahead of the other kids her age.
She was?
What did she say?
She's... she's intelligent.
That's what I was afraid of.
It's really fine, right?
Listen, Homer. When you ask somebody about a girl,
and the first thing they tell you is that she's intelligent,
you're in trouble.
Hello? Hello?
Just a minute, Agnes.
Just help me out, Homer. Just count me out.
Hello?
You can't do that. Hit me. You promised you'd take that.
That was before I knew she was intelligent.
intelligent
i thought you said you were a pal and i thought when i thought i was in trouble
and asked another pal to help me
what else could that pal do listen homie did you ever try dancing with a girl
with brains
what you're actually saying sam is that the girl doesn't count no allies with
you please i see
only you men are important
I suppose it doesn't matter at all if the poor girl gets done.
Alice, all I say was...
No wonder boys think they're kings of the earth.
They take after their fathers.
Alice!
Sam, look at it this way.
How would you like it if you were a girl?
Henry, is that you?
Yes, Father.
Please come in here.
Alice, let's not discuss this in front of Henry.
Sam, you were the one who mixed him up in the first place.
Now I want you to straighten him out.
Did you want to speak to our mother?
No, dear, your father wants to talk to you.
Alice!
Sam, I'm counting on you.
What is it, Father?
Henry, you know I never interfere in your affairs, nor do I intend to start now.
Thank you, Father.
But...
But why?
Henry, someday you too will be married and have a family of your own.
Well, thank you, Father.
Yes.
Henry, your mother is a wonderful woman.
Thank you, Father.
But sometimes...
You're welcome, Henry.
[LAUGHTER]
Son, you remember that book you were telling me about,
the one about Rollo and Spice?
Rodney and Bruce, Father.
[LAUGHTER]
Yes.
Well, sometimes it's that way between Father and Son, too.
Oh?
When one's in trouble, he knows he can count on the other.
You know how.
Father, are you trying to tell me that now you want
me to go on this blind day?
It's not that I want you to go, Son.
You just prefer it, is that it?
Well, it's not exactly that I prefer it.
But you think I ought to go, huh?
Well, not exactly think you ought to go, but...
After all, Henry, she may not be as fat as you think.
No, that's not what I meant.
I mean...
Agnes, where is it?
I'm looking for it. I'm looking for it.
It's someone's here in the album.
Why didn't you say you had a picture of Martha in the first place?
Because who knew you were gonna be so particular?
- Would have made a lot of difference
to my mother and father.
- Don't forget him very often
a picture doesn't do a person justice.
You should see some of the pictures we have of me.
They'd scare the pants off you.
(audience laughs)
- Here, here it is.
- Where?
- There, there in the lower left hand corner of the page.
- Not bad, not bad at all.
- See, hen, you were worried for nothing.
- Oh boy, not bad at all.
A little mature maybe, but I like 'em that way.
Mature, let's see.
That's her mother.
What?
Very often, him girls take after their mother.
The other one, the girl wither, that's my thing.
Let's see.
Let me see too.
What's the matter?
Listen, Agnes, I don't mind doing a person a favor.
But if your aunt allows your cousin to go out with boys,
she ought to be ashamed of herself.
What?
Very often, Henry, girls are a lot older than they look.
Sure, Homer, but even if this girl is a lot older
and she looked, she couldn't be a day over 11.
- Well, is that what's worrying you?
- Isn't it enough?
- This picture was taken five years ago.
- Oh!
- You see Henry?
- Let me see it again, Agnes.
'Cause she's still wear braces on her teeth.
- I don't know.
- Do you think she's still knock me?
- Gee, I don't know.
- Look at the beautiful hair she has, Henry.
- Where?
- Right.
(audience laughing)
- What's her mother again?
- Well, Henry.
- Well, you see, Agnes, it's very hard to tell anything
about Martha from this picture.
Is this the latest one you have?
- Yes.
- Do you have a magnifying glass in the house?
- Yeah, I think, just a minute, Henry.
Oliver, who do you think you are, cousin of you?
- Uh-huh.
- Well, you're not, see?
And that goes for you too, Homer Brown.
- Agnes, I didn't say anything.
- Never mind the excuses.
And I'll tell you one thing, Homer Brown,
If any cousin of mine isn't good enough for Henry Aldrich
than any friend of any Henry Aldrich
isn't good enough for me.
- Are you referring to me, Agnes?
- You don't see any other friends of Henry Aldrich
around, do you?
Now you can both get out.
- What Agnes?
- Agnes, what about my father?
- Ow!
(door slams)
- Now look what you did to me, pal.
(upbeat music)
The Big Red Letter Stand for the Jell-O Family
Oh, the Big Red Letter Stand for the Jell-O Family
That's Jell-O!
Yum-yum-yum!
Jell-O Putting!
Jell-O Tap!
The Oka Putting!
Yes, sorry!
Yes, that's the Jell-O Family
And right now Jell-O is making you the biggest bargain offer you've heard about in years
The offer of a full set of six beautiful individual aluminum Jell-O moles
Yes, real aluminum, sturdy, good-looking long-lasting.
They're handsome fluted moles, the type that have been so hard to get for such a long time.
These moles are a guaranteed 60 cent value, but you get the whole set of sakes for just
25 cents plus a coupon you'll find on a special banded combination of three packages of jello
puddings.
So hurry, hurry to the grocers, because this offer is limited.
With these six beautiful aluminum molds, a 60 sand value for just a quarter, plus the
jello pudding's coupon.
Don't miss this big bargain offer.
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Ulrich.
In order to help Homer, Henry has accepted a blind date.
But in trying to discover what she looks like, he has been less than a pal to his father
and a homer.
The scene opens in the Alrich Front Hall.
It is the next day.
Is this long distance?
Long distance speaking.
Well, look, can you please tell me how much it would cost to call Hollendale person to
person?
The charges are $1.25.
She was a whole dollar and $0.25.
That is correct.
Even if the person doesn't know the other person?
I'm sorry, sir, but the telephone company is not responsible for that.
Oh.
Well, look, I'd like to place a call to Hollendale person to-
Hey, Ray!
One minute, mother, the call is to Miss Martha Adams.
Henry, hang up that phone.
But mother--
Henry.
Never mind, operator.
No.
Would you mind telling me why you're calling Hollendale?
She was a hen able to find out a single solitary thing about my blind day,
just that she wore braces and was not need when she was eleven.
So--
So I decided to take the bull by the horns, so to speak, and phone her.
What for?
To ask her for a description of herself.
Henry, don't you dare.
My goodness, the very idea.
Is that what your father told you to do?
- Well, not exactly.
- Sam!
Sam Aldrich!
- What's just going on into the garden?
- Dear, what did you say to Henry about his blind aid?
- Henry, suppose you run along.
- Sure, Father, I'd be glad to.
- Sam, whatever you said to Henry was enough
to make him try to phone the girl
and get her to describe herself.
- What?
- And if I hadn't caught him in time,
our whole family would have been disgraced.
- Henry was going to phone her.
- Yes, Sam.
I hope you're satisfied with what you and your blind dates have accomplished.
But Alice, all I said was...
I don't want to hear another word!
Alice, Henry...
Henry, we're going to...
Number, please.
Give me long distance.
I want to speak to Hollendale, person to person.
Hi, Jack.
Oh, hello, Harry. Come on in.
-Gee, I'm glad you dropped over, Harry.
I was just gonna call you.
There's something I've gotta ask you about.
-Yeah? That's funny, because I wanted to ask you about something, too.
-Oh, yeah? -Yeah.
-What did you want to know, Jack?
-Well, do you know a girl here in Hollendale named Martha Adams?
-What? -You see, my father got a phone call
from a man he knows in Centerville, and Mr. Aldrich,
he wants to know something about this girl.
-No kidding. -Yeah, he wants the information
for his son, Henry.
-I got a letter from his son, Henry.
-Yup.
Do you know him? -Nope.
-Well, then how come he wrote to you?
-Henry knows my cousin, Charlie.
He lives in Centerville.
Oh.
He wants the same information.
Oh, well, do you know her, Martha Adams, I mean?
No, do you?
No.
Maybe a red nozer.
Yeah, why don't we phone him?
That's a good idea.
Number, please.
Stay 239.
Hey, this Martha Adams must be something
if they've heard about her all the way over in Centerville.
Yeah, I wonder if the father really
wants the information for the son.
Yeah.
Hello?
Oh, red, this is Jack.
Oh, hiya, Jack.
Say I was just about to call you.
Yeah, what about?
Do you know a girl in town named Martha Adams?
What?
I got a letter from a kid in the center of asking about her.
Signed Homer Brown.
No, kidding.
Yeah.
Well, who's Homer Brown?
I don't know.
Then how come he wrote to you?
Well, he didn't.
Well, not exactly anyway.
It seems his father once had some business with my father.
So he addressed his letter to Sid Benson's son around 17 if he has one.
What?
Don't you know those four ladders?
No, not yet.
[MUSIC]
What is your letter say, Henry?
I'll read it to you.
Dear Henry Aldridge, your communication received and
contents noted an answer to your request for information regarding a certain
party in my town.
I wish to state the following.
Physically speaking, I find her very satisfactory,
signed Harry Cooper.
- She, that's great, Harry.
- Oh, wait, a P.S.
As regards your request for exact dimensions,
I could think of no way to get them
without arousing the suspicions of the party in question.
- What's the difference?
He finds it very satisfactory, doesn't he?
- He seems to.
Now, what does your letter say?
- It says, "Dear Homer Brown,
Oh boy, signed Red Stevens.
(audience laughing)
What do you say, him?
- Hello, boys.
- Hi, Father.
- Hello, Mr. Aldrich, what do you say, him?
- Henry, about that blind date of yours.
- Yes, Father?
- I happened to be speaking to a business associate of mine
who happens to live in Hollendale,
and just in passing, I happened to ask him
if he knew a girl named Martha Adams.
- Did he, Father?
- His son did.
- Well, what does son have to say?
Well, according to his son, Martha Adams is beautiful, talented, charming, delightful, and breathtaking.
No kidding.
Dee, thanks, Father, but you really didn't have to go to all that trouble.
I didn't.
Of course not, Father.
After all, a fella's got to take a chance on a blind date.
Yes, Henry.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(upbeat music)
- Wait til Agnes hears the good news.
- Yeah.
- Hi Agnes.
- Oh it's you.
- Agnes guess what?
Henry's gonna take Martha to the dance.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, we'll call for you around seven thirds.
- But would you rather we came at seven?
- Wait a minute.
- I just had a great idea, Henry.
Why don't we make a whole day of it?
- It's alright with me.
- Wait a minute.
- We'll call for you three.
- I get out of school at two.
- Val has got a grip on yourself.
- It was fun.
Agnes, don't pull my tie.
Agnes, you're choking me.
- Well listen to me.
- What's the matter, Agnes?
It's just two o'clock too early.
- It certainly is.
Especially since Martha may not be coming.
- What?
- Huh?
- Why is she may not be coming?
That's what I want and a why.
- Yeah, why?
- Because right out of a clear sky,
she became very popular with a boy in Hollendale.
- Why?
(audience laughing)
Why?
- She doesn't know, but she is.
She can have three separate dates for that weekend with Red Harry and Jack.
So she's not making up her mind till she hears from a girl here in Centerville.
What girl?
The girl she wrote to asking for information about you.
About me?
She asked for information about me?
Yeah.
Well, she's got her nerve.
All right, she got to ask about me.
Is this a blind data, isn't it?
Well, I guess she doesn't want it to be too blind.
Well, well, you're a fine pal, Homer.
Me?
Yeah, and after all I was going to do for you a fine pal.
What did I do?
What did you do?
She's your girl's cousin, isn't she?
Yes.
That's the last favor I'll ever do for anybody.
And another thing, Agnes, I know my rights.
My father's a lawyer, you know, and a blind date
is practically a contract.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(upbeat music)
Isn't it nice that we danced so well together, Martha?
- It's just wonderful, Henry.
- Do you wanna know something, Martha?
- What, Henry?
- My mother and father met on a blind date.
- Really?
- Uh-huh.
- What happened?
- They got married.
- Oh.
How did it turn out?
Oh, fine.
They get along wonderfully, except for a few days last week.
Oh, that's nice.
Henry.
Yes, Martha?
Are you disappointed?
Oh, no.
Are you, Martha?
Am I what, Henry?
Disappointed.
No, Henry.
Gee.
Henry?
Yes, Martha?
Well, how did you feel about the blind date?
Before you met me, I mean, were you worried or anything?
What?
What for?
Well, I might have been not very attractive to skinny
or too fat or something like that.
Gee, what is-- no, not you.
You're sweet, Henry.
Sorry.
Thank you, Martha.
But I mean, before you met me, well,
didn't you even think about what I might look like?
Well, to be perfectly frank about it, Martha,
It did cross my mind for a moment.
But I'll tell you how I feel about it.
When a pal is in trouble, see, and asks a pal to help him out,
well, what else can a pal--
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Listen, Agnes, boy, you sure were a real pal
to write to Martha and fix things up.
Would you mind telling me what you said?
- Well, I told her you were passively good-looking.
- Not handsome.
- Are you kidding him?
Then I told her--
- Just passable?
- Yeah, I figured after she got here,
she wouldn't hold it against you that I exaggerated.
- Now listen, Agnes, I thought you were a pal.
- Well, here's a pal you can count on anyway.
Jello Puddings, yup, your best friend at dessert time.
Jello Chocolate Butterscotch and Vanilla Puddings,
Chock full of old fashioned homemade goodness.
Tomorrow, try chocolate peppermint pudding.
Just prepare one package of smooth,
velvety rich, yellow chocolate pudding as usual.
While still warm, add crushed peppermint stick candy
or peppermint extract to taste.
Top it with fluffy whipped cream and sprigs of mint.
You never taste it anything better.
All three yellow puddings are made with milk and nourishing
and they cook to luscious perfection
in just about five minutes.
No wonder more people buy jello puddings
than any other prepared puddings in the world.
(dramatic music)
Here's hoping you'll be in your living room
in hours next week at the same time.
Good night, folks.
(dramatic music)
The Old Rich Family starring Ezra Stone is Henry with Jackie Kelka's Homer is written
by Frank Tarloff with music by Jack Miller.
Mr. and Mrs. Old Rich are House Jamison and Catherine Rod.
And this is Dan Seymour in New York saying, "The Old Rich Family is brought to you by
the Jell-O family."
Oh, the Big Red Letter stand for the Jello Family.
That's Jello, yum yum.
Jello, yum yum yum.
Jello, tat.
The Oka Pudding, Jessary.
New as new as an ice storm in the tropics.
Amazing, the only one of its kind.
That's minute rice.
Minute rice for magically quick, quick meals.
You fix minute rice quicker than potatoes.
Just drop it in water and bring to a boil.
No washing, rinsing, draining, steaming.
Nothing else to do.
And minute rice is light, white, and fluffy every time.
The best rice you ever ate.
Serve it for delicious, quick, quick meals.
Remember the word minute.
Minute rice in the red, white, and blue box.
[Music]
Gracie, I want you to meet our guest tonight, Robert Montgomery. How do you do Gracie?
Oh, Robert Montgomery.
Calm down Gracie. Easy. Our program starts in just a few minutes. We're next on NBC.
[Music]
[ Silence ]