The Aldridge family based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith and
starring Ezra Stoners Henry with Jackie Kalk as Homer.
Henry! Henry Aldridge!
Come on, mother!
Now for the Aldridge family.
[Music]
Typical teenage boys are always too busy to sit down and remember way back when.
Like Henry Aldrich, they live only in the exciting here and now,
with nothing to look back on and everything to look forward to.
The scene opens in the Aldrich kitchen. It is morning.
This morning Alice
How long does it take to ask that she's got a burnt pot?
Mary these sure use the fine side of the greater for those carrots. I am father
What about the peppers in the cat? I'll get you work on those next foot Mary. They go in first
Please start on them right away before I finish the cat now Mary. Let's try to keep calm
I'm coming as fast as I can what did how do you say does she have one?
I knew I shouldn't have phoned you mean she doesn't have a burnt pot no dear
and she was very insulted that I should ask.
But Alice, Pierre always used a burnt pot.
And if he'd thought enough of me to send four genuine wild Canadian grouse,
the least we can do is cook them in a burnt pot.
Sam, they'll turn out just as well as the pot's cleave.
And just because you're cooking the dinner is no reason for upsetting my kitchen like this, just look at it.
This is a complicated recipe.
If I'm going to be at it all day, I want things where I can put my hands right on them.
Oh, they, Sam, I refuse.
Alice, you just wait. It'll be worth it.
I'm married. Please hand me the onion.
Henry and Homer are still out on the back porch feeling them.
What?
Mary, we have to start browning them right away.
Then I'm right in the middle of my peppers and cabbage.
Now, Mary, let's take one thing at a time.
Please tell the boys to hurry.
Yes, Father.
Alice, you know what we really need.
A roaring fire of time-long.
Sam, old Richard, you're not starting any fires in my kitchen.
Henry!
Homer, is that Mary?
I'm not sure, Henry.
It certainly sounds like her.
My goodness, Homer, are you crying?
Mary, how would you look after four pounds of onions?
Father wants to know if you finished peeling them.
Homer, feel around and see how many you're left.
I'll see.
There's four, six, seven.
She was, Henry, here's a funny one.
Homer, let's go with my toe.
Oh, I thought it was kind of lumpy for an onion.
I'll take in the peel one while you finish what's left.
And hurry, father's ready to start here.
Henry, who is this Pierre?
Well, you know that moosehead in my father's study here?
That's Pierre.
What?
Well, that is he was my father's guide when he bagged him.
When he was?
Bagged him Homer, bagged him.
He sends us something every year.
Last year he sent my mother Musgrat skin.
No kidding.
She's going to have it made into a coat as soon as she gets a few more.
What?
And this year he sent your father for four.
And what would you call more than one grouse?
Growses? Or is it rice?
Gee, either one sounds right.
Did I tell you my father's using Pierre's own special recipe to cook?
He is. Boy, I can hardly wait to taste them.
You? But Homer...
That's one reason I love eating at your house, Hen.
You never know what's going to show up on the table.
Well, look Homer. That's why I didn't mind getting here at 7.30 this morning to help out.
Sure, and we appreciate it Homer.
And your father sure is a card. The way he's always joking about my showing up at meal times.
Homer, I think you'd better excuse me for a minute.
What's the matter? Well there's a certain conference I'd better have with my mother.
Okay, and Henry asked if there's anything I can do after I finish her onions.
Mother?
If they haven't you finished those onions yet?
Why, not exactly Father.
Now Sam is doing the best he can.
But please hurry.
Mary, you're not chopping those peppers too fine are you?
Mother, I've got good news for you.
You had?
Yeah, Homer can make it for dinner tonight.
What?
I didn't even have to talk a member with...
Yeah, you mean you invited it?
Well, not exactly.
But don't you agree we should considering that he's been crying his eyes out for us all morning?
Henry, I like Homer.
I like him very much.
There's something about him that, well, that warms your heart.
But he's got to learn to wait until he's invited.
But what can I say to him?
Just tell him he can't come tonight under any conditions.
But be tactical.
Don't make him feel we don't want him.
Sure, mother.
I'll do my best.
My goodness, Samuel, potatoes are burning.
I know, Ellen.
They're supposed to.
[LAUGHTER]
Home, old timer.
Look, can I finish the onion?
That's swell, Homer.
Look, I just had a little talk with my mother, see.
About me?
Yeah, you happen to come up.
And Homer, you know what she said about you?
Why?
You warm her heart.
I do.
And look, Homer, would it make you feel any better if my father took us to the movies tonight?
On top of dinner?
Why?
Oh, boy.
What a swell family.
Homer, you're not gonna be here.
No, I've been a heel.
Here I've been warming your family's hearts all these years,
and what have I done in return?
Nothing.
Homer, I didn't mean that.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I've got a present at home they'd love.
Homer, wait, let me present me.
If I warm their hearts, monogram matches
are the least I can give them.
(upbeat music)
[Music]
Mother, look, monogram matches.
You see how Homer feels about us.
Henry, they're not even our monogram.
[Laughter]
Don't you agree it's the sentiment that counts?
So couldn't we forbid Homer to come the next time he's not invited?
Henry, I told you to tell him not to come this time.
Mother, you should have seen his eyes when I talked to him.
And they were sort of, sort of, all watery.
That was onions.
- Well, mother.
- I'm sorry, but we just have to put our foot down on Homer.
- What?
- Your father's already spoken to me several times
about his coming to dinner without being invited.
You mean if it's all right with father
or it's all right with you?
- Mrs. Aldrich.
- He's coming.
Yes, Homer.
Would you mind explaining how the bag
on your vacuum cleaner comes off?
- Homer, what's happened?
- Well, nothing.
I thought I'd help out and sort of give that easy chair in the corner, the one's over, see?
Yeah?
Well, you know that doily that was on the back of it?
Oh my!
That was genuine Belgian lady!
Mrs. Oldrich, I know exactly where it is.
I'll get it out.
Before you do, Homer, Henry has something to say to you.
Haven't you, Henry?
Sure, mother.
As soon as I speak to father.
Father!
Henry, it won't do you a bit of good.
Father, are you in the kitchen?
Yes, Henry.
And just look at those grouse lying there in the pot.
Have you ever seen such beauties?
Well, I'll say.
And father--
I admit, there's not much to them after you take the feathers off.
But at least there'll be enough for the four of us.
Just the four of us?
I mean, Dean, now that I really look at them, there's enough for an army.
An army?
Sure.
Henry Homer is not coming to dinner tonight.
Ha-ha!
Not under any circumstance.
But, Father, suppose we stuff them with the--
We stuff them with bread and butter first how much grouse can he eat Henry you were please tell Homer
You're sorry, but tonight is out, but you know but Mary can I have the piece please?
Father was I supposed to take care of them to you mean you haven't even started shelling them
I was busy cracking the walnut Mary you should learn to take one thing at a time now the next see where does your mother keep the
Fennel seed the one
Fennel seed Mary Fennel seed it's an herb pierce grouse wouldn't taste like anything without it my goodness father
We don't have anything like that.
We don't.
No, Fennelse?
That's not fine, say.
Wouldn't Pepper do just as well?
No, it would not.
I'll have to go out and get some.
And while I'm going, Mary, be sure and base the grouts
every three minutes.
But what about the peas and the walnuts?
Now, Mary, let's not get excited.
But my goodness!
That's the trouble with the way women cook.
No organization.
Mary, please start basing.
My father was that final about--
Mary, please, step aside.
Look, Mary.
How could you brush the hair out of my eyes?
Sure, I'd be glad to.
Mary, what can I do about Homer?
Henry, you've just got to learn to look in square in the eye and say, "See here, Homer Brown."
Mary, I can't say a thing like that to my best friend.
Why not, it's easy. Here, grab this spool.
What for?
Then start facing. I'll show you how to get rid of Homer.
Homer!
Mary, why are you rolling up your sleeves?
Homer, where are you?
You're living in a mirror.
Now, see here, Homer Brown.
Homer, what are you doing with that picture album?
Why, your mother took me off vacuum cleaning and put me on dusting books.
And Mary, who's this?
Let me see.
Oh, my goodness, that's me when I was just four.
That's what I look silly.
Silly.
Gee, I've never seen a cute little tyke.
Cute or what?
Tyke, Mary, Tyke.
Kid.
Oh.
Gee, you're the cutest four year old I've ever seen.
I am?
Gee, sure.
Oh, was there something you wanted to say to me?
to me. All right. And I'll see you here Homer. Yes Mary. Homer I know you're expecting to
come to dinner tonight and and yes well how would you feel if I were to invite you to come
over next Tuesday. Oh boy. Mary I never imagined you felt this way about me. Homer I like you
You do terribly.
Boy, if someone told me, if they told me,
gee, imagine being invited to dinner here twice in the same movie.
What?
Oh, will there be anybody here to say but just the two of us, Mary?
Now see here, Homer.
Even if there is, we could take a walk afterwards, couldn't we?
Homer, stay on your side of the table.
In Mary.
Homer, keep away.
Mary.
There!
Oh, excuse me, Miss.
Yes, sir, may I help you?
No, please. You see, I've been to several stores and none of them seem to carry it, and I thought you might have it here at the Emporium.
Have what, sir?
Fennel.
Oh, yes, sir. Full floor less iron, you're right.
Oh, fine, fine. Full floor?
Yes, sir, in hardware. Just ask anyone for a funnel.
I don't know no fennel fennel fennel seed fennel seed yes are you sure you don't mean
kennel seed I think about it you find can in the pet shop on the second floor
right next to sporting goods I don't want kennel seed I want sennel keys I mean I'm
not the fennel seed I see and mr. McIntosh oh mr. McIntosh the mackintosh is our floor walker
Perhaps he can help you good. Yes, this friend. Mr. McIntosh this gentleman would like some what is that again sir?
Fennel feed seed. Oh, yes garden appliances two-eyes over but although I must confess I've never heard of fennels
What time of the year do they come out?
Mr. McIntosh fennel seed is not a seed. Hmm. That is it's a seed, but it isn't a seed that comes up
They've come in jar jar. Yes. Oh now I understand
Do you want white mouth jars or a narrow mouth jar?
But then for storing seed I imagine the narrow ones would be more practice now just a moment. I
Don't want to buy any jar. I don't want to buy funnel and I don't want to buy kennel feed
I want kennel seed fennel seed. Do you understand?
Yes, it
Suppose I turn you over to our section manager, but over to the hiller brand with the hiller brand
If you step this way for a moment.
Mary, I must say I'm a little surprised at you.
Surprised at me, Mother. What about Homer?
I was nothing but an innocent victim.
Mother, suppose we do this tonight.
Suppose I split my grouse with Homer.
- Is it? - Sure.
I wouldn't mind doing without my drumsticks.
Now, just a moment, dear.
I don't want you to think I'm being stubborn.
But if neither of my children has the courage to get rid of Homer in a nice polite way, then I guess I'll have to.
You, other?
The time has come to be direct.
Homer!
Oh boy.
Oh my goodness.
What's wrong?
If you're here, Henry and I'm here, who's facing?
Homer?
Mrs. Aldrich, I finished testing in books.
Is there something else I can do?
No, dear.
Sit down, please.
That's something I want to say to you.
Sure, Mrs. Aldrich.
Homer?
Yes, Mrs. Aldrich.
Erm...
Homer.
I'm going to tell you a little story.
You are?
Yes, dear.
And I hope you get the point.
Oh, I will, Mrs. Orwich. I'm usually pretty good at story.
Good.
Now, this is a story about a nice boy.
And this nice boy could be anyone.
He could be you, he could be Willie Marshall or anybody.
He could.
Willie Marshall?
Yes, dear.
Now, we all like this boy. We like him very much.
and we'd like very much to have him to dinner.
It's just a question of his being invited.
You see what I mean, Homer?
- Sure. - You do?
Well, my goodness.
- Do you mind if I use the phone? - Of course not.
And I do hope this boy understands that we really like him very much.
- Yeah, I hope so. - And you sure have a big heart, Mrs. Aldrich.
- Thank you, Homer. - I'll operate it. Give me your 997.
Thank you.
Home, dear.
Yes, Mrs. Aldrich.
When you threw on the phone, why not come out here in the kitchen and have a piece of cake?
Gee, thanks.
Hello, Willie Marshall.
Willie, this is Homer.
I've got good news for you.
You're invited to dinner tonight at the Aldrich.
[Music]
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
Homer has invited himself to Mr. Aldrich
a special dinner of Canadian Grouse Alapierre.
So far the efforts of Henry and his family to get rid of him
have met with phenomenal failure.
The scene opens in the Aldrich Hallway.
It's later than afternoon.
Hello, is that you, Henry?
No, Alice, this is Sam.
Has Mary put the walnuts in the grouch yet?
I think so.
Hi.
And Sam, I'm glad you called.
I've been wanting to talk to you.
Where are you?
In the President's office.
The President?
Of the Emporium.
What are you doing there?
Having tea.
Meanwhile, Sarah is trying to get in touch with the company
that might carry fennel speed.
What seed?
Alice, I'm not going to start that with you.
What do you want to talk to me about?
It's Henry, he's disappeared.
What?
Without doing a thing about Homer.
That's a fine thing.
Why can't Mary tell him to go home?
Dear, she refused this point,
Blanks has speak to him.
Mary, well, Alice, then there's just one thing to do.
You will have to be firm with Homer yourself.
I?
Yes.
But, Sam, I've already...
Dear, have you ever noticed his eyes?
What about them?
They look at you.
No, that's... we can't have Homer for dinner, and that's fine.
There simply aren't enough grouse to go around.
I know, dear, and I thought of that.
Why don't I throw in some spaghetti?
Spaghetti? With my wild grouse?
It would be silly.
How is we couldn't? What would Pierre say?
Does he have to know?
And Mary's gone over to tell Willie Marshall not to come, so at least we won't have him on our head.
Willie Marshall, how are he gettin' included?
Why, Homer invited him.
What?
Now, do you control yourself?
Sam?
Sam, have you hung up?
No, Alice. I haven't hung up.
Are you angry?
I should I be angry.
I don't mind Homer's coming to dinner and eating my grouse.
That's something I could get over, eventually.
But why, no one in my own family can do a simple thing.
Like telling the boy he hasn't been invited is something I cannot understand.
- But, dear... - All right, Alice.
If no one else is capable, I'll just have to handle them out of myself.
- You mean you'll tell Homer? - Yes.
Good, I'll put him on.
No, I mean, Alice, right now I have to track down some fennel seeds.
Some what?
Never mind, and don't worry, I'll take care of Homer in my own way.
Goodbye.
This is all Richard, I finished chopping her wood.
Is there anything else you'd like me to do?
No, dear, and hope I can't just stand around with idle hands.
When I give the windows upstairs are going over.
Homer, I really don't feel you should do any more.
See, I don't mind.
That's the least I can do for a couple of grouse's.
(upbeat music)
- Oh my goodness, Hemi, this is a surprise, come here.
- Thanks Agnes, do you?
'Cause that dinner I smoke cooking.
- You are.
- Agnes, your mother always makes plenty, doesn't she?
I mean, that is, there's always room for one more,
isn't there?
- Sure why?
- No reason.
Did I mention I saw you in gym yesterday.
- You did, I did.
- You did.
- Hemi, I look terrible and now's off a gym blowman.
You look pretty good to me.
I did.
You sit on him, you old kid.
You're a candy chair.
I have time.
And the reason I came, you know, I always felt
if there was one person you could count on
when you had a problem was good old Agnes.
You've got a problem.
Well, you see, my father's cooking a special dinner tonight.
Your father's dinner?
Sure.
And you have to eat it?
But you have got a problem.
Yeah, so I was wondering, I was wondering--
Don't say another word, honey.
I'd be glad to.
- Glad to work. - Naturally, I'll have to ask my mother first.
- No, no, no, no, no, no! - Agnes, wait! I haven't explained about Homer!
Hello, Stair Sam! Well, I hope you don't mind my dropping in your office like this, will.
Not at all. Homer tells me he's having dinner at your house tonight.
- Yes, good. - Well, at least night came over.
Now, before you go into that, Sam, there's something I have to take care of in the outer office
that makes you self-comfortable.
Do you mind if I use your phone?
Go ahead, Sam.
Number, please.
Abbott City, 2200.
Oh, please.
Will, it's a long distance call.
That's OK, Sam.
Merry Christmas.
Right.
Thanks.
Same to you.
Hello.
Abbott City groceries, supply companies.
Oh, how do you do?
The Emporium in Santa Fe suggested that I phone you.
I'm on the trail of some fennel seed.
I beg your pardon.
A fennel seed.
Oh, look.
It's sort of an herb, you see.
Oh, yes, sir.
Hold on, please.
What's that?
Now, wait a minute.
I haven't finished.
Hello.
Who is this?
This is her.
Who?
Her?
The channel for me?
Look, I'm trying to put my hand on some fennel seed.
F-E-N-N-E-L.
Fennel.
Oh, fennel seed.
Now I get you.
You mean you have some?
Yes, sir.
Syrian or Arabian.
What's the difference?
Well, want some Syrian.
The others are Arabian.
Oh, well, you don't want to be fine.
Could you wrap some up for me?
I'll get into my car and drive right over.
Well, yes, sir.
What quantity?
Oh, about 25 cents.
Where should be enough?
I'm afraid you don't understand, Mr. This is a wholesale establishment.
Yes, I know.
Some of the orders we place from the site, $10,000.
Well, very well, Mr. I'm going to see you on order.
Never mind now. We'll decide that when I get there.
Goodbye.
Okay, Sam, what's on your mind?
Why, uh, it's...
Above Homer coming to dinner tonight.
Sam, I want you to know how grateful we are.
Grateful?
Yes. If you hadn't taken Homer off our hands,
Elizabeth and I wouldn't have been able to accept the Ferguson's invitation to their barbecue tonight.
But, but, well, that's just it.
What is?
I'm afraid we can't have Homer tonight.
I'm afraid not.
You mean you're having other companies?
No.
The Alice Shake?
What is it then, Sam?
Well, you see...
Yes, I do see!
And why don't you like Homer?
Mother, how much longer do these crowds have to cook?
I really don't know, Mary.
And must you base with two hands?
- Mother, I said we don't have the strength to do it one hand.
It's a fear it isn't lady life.
- Hey, suppose Henry isn't what are we gonna do about Homer?
- Mary, I refuse to even think about it.
This whole thing is giving me a splitting headache.
- Oh!
- Thank goodness in the kitchen, Sam.
- I'm sorry, Auntie.
I'll have the ground.
- Fine, Father.
- Sam, what's that under your arm?
- Goodbye, Fennel's seat, Alice.
It's an herb to put on the ground.
- Sam, a whole cake?
- Well, I got it wholesale, Alice.
It was dirt cheating.
- It's Santa to take us years to use it out.
Now, listen, thing like fennel seed gets used up in no time.
Now, stand back while I sprinkle some on the grouse.
Yes, sir.
There.
How do you hardly drop in free grain?
Mary, all it needs is a pinch.
But how are we ever going to use up a whole keg
if you go fooling around with pinches?
Just smell that grouse.
Yes, sir.
There's nothing that tastes better than a meal you've cooked yourself.
What?
Now, Mary?
Father, does this mean the grouse are done?
Yes, Mary.
There are more vegetables to peel,
no more walnuts to craft, no base.
No, no, it's finished.
Thank goodness. Where are you going?
Back in my room and collapsed.
But Mary, it's time to eat them.
Mother, I never want to look at another grass as long as I live.
Mrs. Aldrich.
Yes, Homer?
You're thinking of calling me into dinner.
I'm in the dining room.
I'm calling him.
Sam, what are you going to do about Homer?
I'm going to get rid of him.
If Will Brown thinks he's going to eat barbecue at the Ferguson's
while we're having his son, he's got another thing coming.
But, Alice, I have as much right to enjoy my dinner as Will has.
Mrs. Aldrich, did you know the phone's ringing?
Yes, dear.
And as soon as I answer it home and I want to have a little talk with you...
Hi.
Sam, I think I'll join Mary.
But dinner's ready.
I'm afraid this headache is ruined my appetite.
I'll take the grouse into the dining room, then I'm going upstairs and lie down.
You mean Henry and I will have to split the grouse between us?
Hello.
Hello, Father.
Henry, where are you?
Good at Agnes's.
Henry, I've got good news for you.
You and I are having two grouse apiece.
Who are you?
Yes, to come on home.
But that's the whole thing, Father.
I think I'm having dinner over here.
What? Why?
I think I talk too much.
But Henry, what about my wild grouse?
Don't remind me, Father.
We're having baked macaroni over here. Goodbye.
But-but-but...
Well...
Mr. Aldrich, I'm still in the dining room if you want to speak to me.
What? Oh, yes.
Is there something wrong, Mr. Aldrich?
Sit down, Homer.
Sit down?
Yes, sir.
About dinner tonight?
Yes.
About the...
Homer, I've got good news for you. We're having two grouse-a-peas.
- We are. - We'll have the time of our lives, just the two of us.
Gee, I never imagined you felt that way toward me, too, Mr. Aldrich.
- What way? - Do I warm your heart?
I wouldn't go that far.
Well, we're supposed to eat.
Just look at those grouse over.
Oh, gee, whizzer, those grouse.
Of course!
They look just like chickens.
What?
And Mr. Orle, which I don't like chickens.
So if you'll excuse me, I'm going home.
Now, just a minute.
Over you sit down and eat.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE]
Listen again next week, same time, same station, for another sparkling half hour with your favorite youngster, his family and his pals.
The old rich family starring Ezra Stone is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
(dramatic music)