[Music]
You don't need to tie a string around your finger in order to remember to the teenage boy you want you or want worse.
Any boy will bring back those memories, especially if he's Henry always.
The scene opens in Homer Brown's house.
The time is early afternoon.
Elizabeth, is the coast clear?
Yes, yes.
Homer that's clear as me.
Good. Give me a hand with these things.
My goodness, will all these pucks and brushes
set the place of the room, Woodward?
I'm not so loud. You want Homer to hear?
Wait, Henry, coming over.
You should be here in a minute now.
Well, I can understand why you don't want Homer around when you paint.
I'm just thinking of you, Elizabeth.
He's just got me in a pot of paint and he'll crank up your whole house.
And what makes you think so?
He's Homer, isn't he?
[Laughter]
If you couldn't make an exception, is he one?
After all, it seems Thursday, next week.
I know, and I bought him a ukulele. That's enough for any boy.
[Muffled]
Does that sound like Homer?
The little, but don't be foolish. I'd be painting.
[Muffled]
The quicker pieces, this stuff I'm so spending on time.
He is. Oh, my goodness, you're not behind the sofa.
[Muffled]
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes. I'm calling. I'm... what's that sticking out from behind the sofa? Who do you think? He thought of missing the phone, though I didn't recognize you.
(Laughter)
Did you lose something? No. Oh. You're fixing the sofa? No. Doing exercises? No. Well, I'm saying how you speak. With mother? No. Who's there?
Oh my.
Do you have a few walks to meet the captain's central?
Oh, yeah.
Did you see my chemistry, sir?
Your chemistry, sir?
Oh, all right.
Here I am, ready to start the biggest experiment of my life, and this disappears.
It's on the bottom-side of the pantry.
I bothered it to base that chocolate greek the other day.
You want to eat it with my chemistry, sir?
No wonder I felt so peculiar.
Yeah, you felt peculiar because you ate five pieces.
All right, I bothered with your sodium bicarbonate.
This is famous baking soda.
It is.
Yeah, now go get it.
Sure, father.
But you think it's very fine,
because I'd like to put anything on a chemistry set
to convey for a take with it.
Now, let's see.
I think this is the right price.
I mean, look, you won't get home a take, too.
I think you could've used the way to eat
the heat out of the house before you start.
I'm not starting, but it can't hurt to test the color.
And I'll stand back.
Come on.
Mother!
You're so smuggly!
I'll never make it back to the cold cold cold cold.
I'll give you a little.
Stand in front of me.
Is it all right if I borrow a few things from a kitchen?
- And then what more? - An experiment.
If you can use chemistry to take one advice first,
then very well, if you promise to return everything,
then you can borrow what to need.
- I already have.
And mother, yes, she is.
- You're looking for father.
He's under the piano.
(audience laughs)
- Oh, I'm going to a piano room.
- Stay under there, father, I'm going.
- Wheel of browns just look.
You've got green paint all over everything.
- Elizabeth, it isn't all over everything.
Just a few spots on the wall and a little on the ceiling.
Henry, come in here.
Hi, Mr. Brown.
You started painting yet?
Henry, quiet.
Homage right upstairs in his room.
Oh, was I raising my voice?
I'm a crazy wordy.
Henry, are you sure you have everything straight?
Sure.
I'm to get Homer out of the house and not bring him back until you're through fooling
around with the woodwork.
Henry, I'm not fooling around.
Oh.
Do you think you'll have any trouble getting Homer out of the house?
Sometimes he's as stubborn as a mule.
You're brown.
It's tough as when you get something in his mind.
I'm trying to find it hard getting it out.
You don't have to worry, Mr. Brown.
All I have to do is smile at Homer and he was,
I can get him to do anything I want.
Excuse me.
Homer, what are you going to do about those green spots?
Oh, God, just hand me the seven-five.
Homer?
Homer, are you having your room?
I have a little room.
Say, say, Homer, what are you saying with me?
He was, what are you making with that chemistry fest, money?
Homer, that's against the law.
- Well, I don't mean I'm making a money tournament.
You're inventing a hair grower.
- What for?
- To grow hair.
- I'm what?
- Hey, he is.
(laughing)
- But a homer, you've already got more hair than you need.
- I know.
- He looks like a head of lettuce now.
- And I'm not making it for myself.
- No?
- No, it's just as human beings in general.
There's an article in this magazine that says,
"The guy who finds something like that will make a fortune."
- No kidding.
I'm going to stand back while I put in some leaves.
Yeesh!
It would make cakes rise and make you the same things as the hair.
A whole year old-timer, going full around with things like hair restore.
When we could be outside, doing really important things.
Like what?
Well, I...
Well...
Did you know they're starting to rip up Main Street today?
They are, sure, from Burch to Ticamor.
You see the kind of important things that are going on in the outside world?
Well, growing hair is important.
It's true.
Homer, did I mention I was planning on our going to a movie too?
On May.
No saying.
Plus a soda afterwards.
I'm not interested.
Well, how about now?
But Homer, look, I'm smiling.
Homer, something stubborn is a mule.
the mule.
(music)
Can I, will you please stop driving when Homer the fresh air is good for again.
That is so good for me. Why are you forcing me to go to the movie?
I'm not forcing you.
Then let go of my arms.
Look, Homer, old timer.
Just give me one good reason why you don't want to go to the movie.
I've seen the picture.
I know, but give me one other good reason.
Why should I go to the movie when I could be making a million dollars?
And helping myself a man to go home.
I'm going home.
Homer, you can't go home, and that's that.
Why now?
Homer, please don't ask me. Why not? You just can't.
Oh.
What do you mean by a remark like that?
Can we answer me one question?
Did my parents tell you to keep me away?
Your parents?
Homer, you have no right to ask that.
Oh!
Look, Homer, I'm gonna get y'all whole bag of sour bowls.
Who over yourself?
Sour bowls.
I'm the only two happy to go in the candy kitchen
here and buy you some on me.
Now don't you move, Homer.
Say right, then.
Your hand, old timer.
Anything we say.
Oh, that new one, huh?
Oh, hi, Lily.
Why are you standing around with them like that?
Like why?
Like you're looking, but your mouth hanging open and everything.
Oh, are you willing?
Have I been a school?
I know, but why do it in public?
[LAUGHTER]
Know what, Lily?
I'm doing a surprise party tonight.
You're all sure my parents even have family
trying to keep me away from their house
while they're getting everything ready?
Oh.
You don't want to know?
Why do you suppose they're throwing you today?
My birthday isn't so next week.
I don't know.
Oh, now that I've seen something,
My father did mention something about going out of town next week.
Sure.
Sure, well, have a good time, Homer.
What do you want to know?
Nothing.
Happy returns of the day and all that sort of stuff.
Well, what's the matter?
Oh, nothing, Homer.
I guess your mother's just inviting your closest friend.
You know, we weren't invited.
Oh, well, that's OK.
Homer, don't give it another thought.
Well, I don't mind.
Well, I'm not hurt.
Well, I love it, old work.
Well, you never see a messaged somewhere.
It was my social noise.
Is anybody I wanted my party is you.
You mean that homeless?
You are.
I'm not personal.
I'm not.
Here comes Henry.
I don't want him to know I've caught on.
Oh, sure.
Here, no.
We're a whole bag of sour balls.
Different colors.
Oh, hi, Willie.
Hi, Henry.
Well, it's the long home.
We're all the--
You know when.
You know where.
We'll be talking about.
Oh, nothing.
Hand all the time.
Well, come on.
Let's go.
Go where?
To the movies.
Even though it's a terrible picture, I certainly wouldn't surprise you.
Well, do you?
And I'll tell you what else, him.
This time, it's on me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
And where did you say you were, Henry?
At the movies, Mrs. Brown, I'm fine with you there.
You got home where to go?
Oh, I got him to go, all right.
Oh, that's fine.
And Mr. Brown still has half of it.
But it's in your world, and it's stealing to do.
I thought he was just doing the woodwork.
- Well, his best dad had once it twice more,
so he decided to do a complete job,
so keep her away as long as possible.
- Well, about that,
if you haven't heard from Homer
in the past 15 minutes, have you?
- Tell me, you haven't lost him, have you?
- No, no, I haven't lost him.
He's just a little misplace, that's all.
- Oh, I've missed him.
- Got up to go for drink of water, see him?
He whiz, and you know how terrible he is on direct.
We probably just went back to the wrong street.
Elizabeth.
Oh, here we are.
Henry, Mr. Bonnaby, Betty, I've said it.
Homer, 10's up here now.
Mr. Sure, Mrs. Brown.
I'll go over to the theater with a fine-tilt comb.
Goodbye.
Elizabeth, are you still with the phone?
Oh, no.
I've got to call the hardware store. We'll need some more paint.
But will you have plenty of that for the living room?
Yes. But I was thinking, if we do the living room,
think how shabby the hall will look by contrast.
Will Brown, you mean you've started again?
(music)
Hi Mr. Trissel.
Oh, my...
Are they really as soon as I get these jelly rolls in the window?
Take your time.
Boy, if there's one thing I like to stand around and smell, it's a bakery.
Eh...
Ah, what can I do here?
What?
I'm just sort of picking up on...
What? Oh boy.
What's wrong?
I think that looking at grass case here.
Oh, those are my special orders.
That's taken back. The one with pink icing.
What does that letter in say?
Happy anniversary to Virgy and Fred.
It does.
You know, upside down, Virgy looks something like Homer.
What is it you're after, Oliver?
I look like I'm after something.
Yep.
Mr. Sky, so I don't want you to give away any secrets.
Did my mother place an order today?
Yes, it is. Oh boy. I've got it written down here.
"Rive brave, half a dozen rolls and some donuts."
That's all? Yep.
You couldn't be in a safe home, could you?
He suppose my mother could avoid a case that said Happy Birthday, Homer.
And he thought he said Happy anniversary, hurry, he and Fred.
Oh, she ordered with donuts.
Oh. Well, when I think of it, I am pretty fond of donuts.
I guess they are more practical for a party who don't have to fly some parties.
Now that I think of a donut here perfect.
Oh, but these donuts can't be for a party.
Why not?
Not right, it's a pretty small party.
You mother just ordered six.
Six.
You want one, two, three, four, five, six?
Yeah.
Mr. Fiverr, you must be wrong.
Wrong.
You must have had six dozen.
Six dozen?
Sure.
He was how far would six donuts go with a mob that's coming to my house tonight?
- How can I?
(dramatic music)
- As the fleet seems proudly out
under the Golden Gate Bridge for their spring maneuvers.
- Homer, Homer, are you in this row?
Homer?
- Young man, would you mind moving?
- Yes, sir.
- You're blocking the United States fleet.
- Oh, excuse me.
Homer!
the battle line seems like great people to the imaginary enemy
young man with you please be quiet but lady could you please tap that fellow
sitting next to your mask him if he's home or brown that's not home a brown
it looks just like him that's my copy bag
I was sure I recognize his hair that's not hair that's ahead of neck it
I'm moving off yes ma'am besides I think I see him down front anyway now the
Please let's go to the Burnt Soundwell at the enemy.
- Come on, Burnt.
Oh, I'm going to run along to run along the street.
Let's go now on. - No, I'm going to park him home.
I'm going to let go of you, sexy.
- And what I thought. - I'm going to.
- I'm going to run along. - I'm going to run along.
- I'm going to run along the street. - I'm going to run along the street.
- Donnie, would you please stay behind that street?
- I guess you want to see how you were coming along
with my pants. I'm after first point in just a few minutes. Yeah. I'm supposed to
stay away from home until supplicing in a way. Yeah. I'm being surprised you know.
That's fine. That's how I happen to get caught with my pants on press. You don't
happen to have a door open do you? No why? No reason I just thought I told a
draft. I thought I used your phone. All you need is a nickel son. It's a
pay for them. Hey what's it there. I'm showing again.
Suppose I wrap this over code around my way. OK but be careful with
facing on a public street you know sure.
I'm nine one one.
Yes ma'am.
I'm a sir. What is this now?
Did you press those hands so I was a little taller.
How could I do a thing like that?
Well I know I'm no tailor.
a miracle man. Is this Adney? Yeah. I just called ask if your cousin Eloise is still visiting you.
You're a what? No reason. But if you want to bring her along tonight, it's perfectly alright.
Say your what? You know Adney. You know.
Sir, do anything weird you should have had around in Paul's house.
Oh sure you were.
Listen on the what's up.
Adi, don't tell my mother, but I know.
No what?
About my surprise party tonight.
You're having a party?
You were invited, either?
No.
She was my mother showing all the pieces on this thing.
Look, Adi, if you're definitely to come.
Adi, Adi.
Sure, and Eloise too.
How are you, doll? How are you?
I'm going to have a shot in the way.
Where are you wearing?
All right, Mel.
No, no, no.
Wait, what are you doing here?
where only I'll be correct.
Why is he gone? I haven't been following him.
He's calling past me.
Hey, homo.
Come on.
What's up, Lily?
Oh, I kept running.
Homo, do you know you have that over-cold on roll?
It's a never mind, Lily.
Oh.
Well, the reason I've been looking for you,
Charlie Clark and Toby Smith are pretty upset
about nothing uninvited.
And two, listen, Lily, would you give them up
and tell them it's a mistake and they're definitely the term?
Okay.
Maybe you better stop by the bakery on your way
in order to ignore dozens of what donuts
with all these extra people coming, we're gonna need them.
Okay, and you happen to have five nickels for a quarter.
I better pick up and see who else my mother forgot to invite.
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Olgre.
When Henry reveals to let him go home,
Homer jumps at the conclusion that his parents were throwing him at the prize party.
And while he's been checking on all the preparations, Henry has been trying desperately to locate him.
The scene opens in a phone booth at the movie house.
Mother, are you still there?
Yes, dear. Your father's coming to the phone now. Are you in some kind of trouble?
Trouble, Mother? Huh? She was what my giving him in trouble?
What is he, your father?
Hello.
Boy, father, am I in trouble?
What's happened now?
Why, it's sort of hard to explain, but could you come right down to the colonial theater and testify to your son's character?
Go, "Parachts"?
Yes, sir. And explain to the manager that I'm usually very well behaved in that I've never molester the lady in my life.
He had to be able to be kicking walls out as he was sexy-canded.
I thought Will was just doing the living room woodwork.
That's the way it started.
And thank goodness he's about to,
all the assu-cinnages are that poor.
Come on, goodness, what happened?
He overlapped.
He walked?
From one room to the other.
Oh, Alice, don't you know what that's to do?
Why not?
He overlapped with that too.
I found the bottom.
In the kitchen, I mentioned from I was actually a terrible figure
perfectly powerful saying here what happened well my cousin
always didn't make me have a strength to do it alone
say you do what
hold half you don't see a body two-boy cap and then falling off a bike over the
house and have a play guy go now don't you think if you rule that tell him to stay
home tonight
I suppose it would
a good
a
fine
bring them where
yeah don't worry it's a fine party that you're growing far
but I'm
that I am
- This is a new thing to tell me.
- Maybe I shouldn't tell you this.
This is bound by Homer, no.
But he might have caught on when Henry tried
to keep more of him than a house all day.
- Oh my goodness.
- And Elizabeth, you suck down on that soon.
- How about tell, how long we just okay?
- But I should go to the party.
- I didn't have any answer to come in.
- Oh yes.
- What the hell is what I'm gonna do?
What's the surprise party?
If you mean you didn't know,
I've never been so surprised in my life.
- Oh, there.
- I'll never be able to get to these Eddie and Ty.
You're gonna have the party anyway.
- The moment it's second or last, you would be great.
You thought if I didn't, well, look, Elizabeth.
It probably won't be many, young students.
Why not get a few bottles of ginger ale and some cookies,
and they'll have a love later.
- It's all right.
I need a phone, Alice.
- Who are you gonna call?
- It's Isaac, basically, and double my order of donut.
(upbeat music)
- All right, Homer, now how do you want your haircut?
Well Mr. Latham, you notice when you look in my hair in a certain way, it reminds you of a head of leather?
Well now that you mention it.
Could you just sort of look more like a head of a fabric?
Uh, no, dry. I hope so.
Yes, sir.
So, you're having a surprise, buddy.
Don't move.
Mr. Latham, should I mention I'm inventing a hair restore?
Yes, what for?
We saw hair. When I get it perfected, would you be interested in trying it out on some of your customers?
When you get it perfected, I'd be interested in trying it out of myself.
Oh sure.
Yes, uh, Barbara with a bald head, great poor recommendation.
Who's that tapping on the window?
Oh, hi, Henry.
Hey, who is the home owner of you, Ben?
What are you mad about?
What am I mad about? What am I mad about? Where did you go for that drink of water?
- For tonight, I have a fool.
(audience gasps)
- Oh, the bakery.
- What?
- Homer, it's still, isn't it, a tick-free shop.
- It might interest you to know, Homer,
that you owe me for a box of cocklets.
My father had a bar for that lady in the theater.
- What lady?
- Never mind.
- How do you want me to cut the sides, Homer?
Close the floor.
- Which of a faster than me?
- A card to sell.
- Well, make one side close and one side close.
We'll take out the style, it looks bad.
- Okay.
- 10, look what I picked up.
- It's bad to party snappers.
- Party snappers?
- Sure, you know, you're pulling two strings
inside of the palm.
- So what, home?
- Look into the palm that was in this one.
- Two four dares, two four dares.
- One top of the chair.
(laughing)
- Home, are you crazy?
- That's a good one.
- But what do you buy those for?
- They're just a thing to brighten up the party.
- Party, what party?
- And you don't have to pretend, I know.
- You know what?
- It's a prize party, my folks are throwing for me tonight.
What?
You didn't think I'd be smart enough to figure out why you were taking me away from home, did you?
Oh boy.
Then you had home.
You're crazy, Homer. There's no party.
You're a Henry. That's why I have to take him to the corner, coming.
Homer, you've got to listen to rings.
But go over him.
Boys, what's up with those scissors?
Come on, we'll phone your parents and prove it.
Henry.
Oh my God.
[Music]
It's a lovely party, Elizabeth. What are you supposed to keep in handling and homework?
Fair be here soon, and I hope so.
I'll keep it again, T.A.L.I.T.
Reminds me to give you a dozen or so doughnuts to take home with you.
How many is Mr. Saggle said already?
I'll say 15 dozen and more arise every half hour.
What are you so got into?
I don't know. He doesn't even answer his phone.
Well, the children seem to be enjoying the donut.
As a matter of fact, I think they're playing a little game with them in the kitchen.
What sort of game?
The one I never heard of. I think Willy called it "Winger" or something like that.
The lady of both hands was after the cabin died.
You get the tinged-off, Agnes?
Most of it. Where's Will?
Out in the backyard. He wanted a fitting cigar door before he soaked his brushes.
The garage door?
I'll never know how he overwrapped that phone.
[Laughter]
Do you happen to have any donuts that are more perfect?
More perfect.
Yeah, the last couple of dozen Mr. Sribles
that over have all sent her home and the throwing our game.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Stop running.
I think home is coming up to speed.
Couldn't have the lights well enough.
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
Everybody's going to be there.
We're going to have a good night.
We'll just come in.
There's a little door now.
Anyone wrong?
[SCREAMING]
(screaming)
- Hey, why did you come from?
- He was Mrs. Brown, what's going on?
- Oh, it's a time party.
- What?
You mean there really was one?
- Doesn't do no.
- But he was, no.
Boy, Mrs. Brown, you certainly could've saved me
a lot of trouble if you'd let me know
that that's what you were up to.
- Hey, Ray, what happened to your hair?
My hair?
I just got in the way of Mr. Latham's scissors.
My goodness, some boy, if you think I'm bad,
You should see Homer.
He looks like an eggplant.
Look, there he is.
Well, I finally convinced him that there
wasn't any surprise party, and he went off-store.
I'll get it to have a donut in some ginger ale.
Henry, you look all worn out.
Hello, who's so-on, Mother?
I just called to tell you I made you a little late,
getting home.
Homer, where are you?
I'm driving on vacation.
I got a jar for the evening.
What kind of a jar?
I'm making a downer.
- No!
- I need a come on home.
- I can mother.
We have two dozen to go,
and I'm just beginning to get the hold and the sand in.
(upbeat music)
- I got the sand!
- Oh, I'm in.
I'm in.
I'm in the down of your head, kid.
- No, listen, I'm in.
- I'm in.
- It's cut on the by.
It's just cut on the by.
- Okay, I guess okay.
But where do you take a look at your own hair?
- What?
What's the matter with you?
- He was.
It's turning green.
- What?
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
(buzzing)