The All-Great Family written by Clifford Goldsmith
And me Henry Olvey
Coming, Father!
[Music]
An out for the Aldrich family with Dick Jones as Henry and Jackie Kalka Palmer.
Every once in a while for the fun there is in it, grown-ups like to recall the far away
pleasures of their own teenage days.
And always right in the middle of those memories, they're romped the boy like Henry Ulterich.
The scene opens on Henry's front lawn.
Listen, Henry, I'm not arguing with you, but why don't you plan to go to the movies with
me to marry?
Homer, can I help but if Agnes did invite you to her party?
Why didn't he dance with her at the dance last Saturday night?
and we if Agnes gave me an invitation or an bended niece on a silver platter I wouldn't go.
You know what the Lawson's give it to eat at their party.
What? Marshmallow.
Why, why, why, marshmallow?
Just one marshmallow without anything on it.
Homer, for the last time, I'm going to Agnes's party.
Alright, alright, you wait 'til I get an invitation to go someplace some time and you weren't invited.
I thought you didn't want to go.
I don't, I don't.
Can't you have as much pride as I do?
Look Homer, why don't you call up somebody?
Why don't you call up Marie Saunders National for a day?
Who? Marie Saunders?
Why not?
You're crazy about her, you know you are.
Marie Saunders, she was, and we have never even spoken to her, and she's never spoken to me.
So, you're always following her around in school?
I am not.
She was the my fault she's always walking in front of me.
And besides, and we're just trying to change the subject.
Homer, for the last time, I'm going.
Okay, then, okay.
I always thought you were a social climber, and now I know it.
Why did you call me Homer?
You're gonna live the event, bap.
(upbeat music)
(laughing)
- Hey, Gary, what's up?
- He is, this is a swell party.
Is this a swell part?
- Do you really like it, Colin?
Did you get some marks now?
- Sure.
- All right, everybody, quiet.
Quiet, let's get out of here.
- That's what I say.
- It's Henry's turn came before, but it's a certain body.
- It's my turn, old boy.
- How's it on, Henry?
I'm holding somebody's forces.
Every heavy hangs over the head.
What's the Leona Due to a demon's forces?
- Well, there's a blonde little male or a female.
- A female, I think.
- Yeah, of course.
- What does he have to do, Henry?
Well, make it good, Henry. Make it good.
Here's what the owner has to do.
You want to go to the telephone, see?
Yeah.
She has to go to the telephone.
Boy, am I bored.
Boy, do I wish I had something to do.
Well, you can be scared about the floor, can't you?
But mother, what is there to do sitting up?
Is there any reason why you can't preach something?
See everybody else.
See why don't we move out of this town?
Is it my boat you want more popular?
I'm popular, I'm popular.
And what are you lying on the floor, Paul?
[LAUGHTER]
Glenspethone.
Well, yes, he is going through here with you.
OK.
If it's the father, what do I say?
What do you mean, what do you say?
Are you in or are you out?
Hello.
Is it on the ground?
Yes, who is this?
Kathleen?
Oh no!
It's whatever it is you think it was Kathleen?
It is what Kathleen?
You want to guess who it is?
No.
It's Marie!
Who?
Marie Stonders!
Well, I'll be done!
Am I my darling?
No!
Well, Homer!
What?
Would you think I would care if I asked you something?
No.
You would have liked to see me and my wife in room with you.
Who you?
Oh gee whiz.
Come on, what's happening?
Nothing, I just knocked over the telephone table.
Sure, I'd like to see you tomorrow.
Do you want me to come up to your house?
Oh my goodness.
Oh wait, there's a minute.
Sure, I don't mind waiting.
Hello?
Hello, did you change your mind?
Hello.
Hi, Mom.
Yes, Marie.
Listen, Homer, they just--
How about your haven't done so?
Okay.
It's not hard to see.
Okay, sure.
Hi.
Is this really Marie Saunders?
The one with the yellow hair.
So he wins.
Goodbye.
So, boy.
Hold her.
What's her thought?
I dropped the phone right out of my hand.
[Music]
[Laughter]
I was never going back in my life.
I nearly died.
I get home and believe you Kathleen.
I can't believe you.
But as soon as I thought I'd die,
I knew I could buy you a Kylie Posh tournament
and a Foshman.
It's my turn, old boy.
Sit down, darling.
I'm sitting.
Go ahead.
See, when I think of home awaiting some warning saunters
and they haven't struck to all tomorrow afternoon.
And you can't just see him, Henry.
But if my brief son has ever found out
that Kathleen wouldn't that call?
All right, not quiet, everybody quiet.
Kathleen's going to start.
Heavy heavy hangs over the forehead.
What's the Leona Duda, a dangerous fortune?
Well, does it belong to a male or a female?
A female?
Oh, boy, a primary chicken.
Oh, my.
Well, the owner of the article over my head has to go to the telephone and call Homer's mother.
Oh, my God.
Good.
Sorry, that's good.
And when he answers, he has to say he's Marie Saunders' mother.
Oh, my goodness.
And she has to tell Mrs. Brown that Homer has been bothering her daughter, and will she please
see to it that he stops.
Oh, my God.
Who asked to do it?
Egg your castle.
Oh no, you're not going to shove me out on any limb and cook my goose.
But, Magnas, you have to. You won't get your bracelet back.
It's a lace chowing, maybe Homer's mother's on a bed.
Okay, then phone her in the morning.
On the morning?
You smile at breakfast?
All you have to do is raise the deuce with her, I guess.
Tell her that Marie is practically having a breakdown because Homer bothers her so much.
[Music]
Hi, Simone.
Hello, thank you, Mother.
Hello, Henry. Did you have a good time at the party last night?
Oh, boy. Didn't we?
Oh, boy, Mother. You know what we did?
I had some time to listen now, then.
Sam, your breakfast is getting cold.
Well, boy, every time I think of it,
think of it. It's the best darn thing you ever heard of. You certainly must have
had a good job. Let me tell you about it. Leave it to Will Brown. It starts today
all right. What is Will Brown's enough? I've never seen Will go upset. Who is Mr.
Brown? Homer's father? Yes, Henry, and I happen to be talking to your mother. That's
all right. Excuse me. Apparently about five of the brown had a phone call for
Mrs. Saunders. From whom? Marie Saunders mother. Henry, what I don't say about
interrupting me. I'm sorry, father. Then what did Mrs. Saunders own her about? He
He didn't say, but apparently she took Elizabeth over the coast about something regarding Homer.
What do you think Will wants to do?
What?
He wants to know whether he can sue Mrs. Saunders for "Clander."
Is that good or bad, Father?
I mean, well, was it "Clander"?
I don't know. I asked Will Brown what he said, and he said he wouldn't tell me, and I first told him it was "Clander."
Henry, I want to eat your cereal. This doesn't concern you in the slightest.
Is that clear, dear? The only thing is that...
Hey Henry!
Who is that you?
Yeah, I want you to finish your breakfast yet.
Hello, Mr. and Mrs. Haldry.
Good morning, Homer.
Why, but you certainly seem to be feeling good.
I am.
Boy, Henry, am I glad I decided not to go to that party last night.
You are, Homer?
What happens?
Don't you wish you knew?
And listen, if you haven't finished your breakfast, I'm going on.
I want to get to school early and have a chance to see.
To see?
I want to get there.
Homer, about how long ago did you leave home?
About a half an hour ago.
I've been over telling Charlie Clark something.
And Henry, I'll tell you about it when I see you at school.
No one has any rights to feel that good at this hour of the morning.
It's just temporary, Father.
He isn't going to be feeling that good by this afternoon.
Henry?
Now tell us all about what you did that you're so funny, last night.
Oh, uh, why?
Probably.
It wasn't anything, Mother.
Wait, just...
In Mary Out in the Kitchen, I believe she is.
Well, excuse me for a second.
I want to see whether I can help her cook my eggs.
Mary!
What did you want, Henry?
Listen, you're...
Could you do something for me?
If you are borrowing money, I have it a thing.
It's much more simple than money.
And would you be willing to phone Mrs. Brown?
Why?
Well, all you have to do is say you're Marie Saunders' mother
and apologize for borrowing her.
Oh, no, Henry.
You won't.
Neither would you be willing to call over.
What's wrong?
Well, he's expecting to meet--
I mean, you know how crazy he is about Jamari.
He is?
Sure.
He practically worships you.
I'm just asking you to have a date with your behavior
in structural work for 15 this afternoon.
Well, all you have to do is time somebody asked you to come over to her plate.
Well, I had a year old to try and do anything with the car.
But, Mary, let me tell you what happened last night.
Hey, Henry. Henry.
What do you want, Homer?
I want you to do something for me.
I haven't got time. I gotta go to class.
But Henry, usually you have to do.
Well, first, Homer.
I've been thinking things over and I want to tell you something.
Not till I guess who's telling you about this.
What do you really think of Marie Saunders?
Why?
Well, gee, I think she's a prettiest girl in the school.
But have you ever noticed that she's sort of peculiar?
I mean, I'm the telephone, for instance.
She can be just as nice to you as though she was crazy about you.
And then you're me to hear it's school and boy, she's so bashful she won't even look at you.
Well, look, let me tell you.
Let me tell you, Carol, will you stop interrupting?
All you have to do is find the first chance to have and give her this nose.
What does it say?
What gives you this ad-make?
Just find her and give it to her.
She'll understand.
But homo!
Oh, hi, Kathleen.
You want me to have you caught on your...
No.
What type of train you have?
Nothing.
Just sort of a no.
Oh my goodness, I was just talking with Agnes and she said his mother's followed the whole thing,
looked like a stinker.
Kathleen, I hope you don't think there's anything funny about this.
What?
Frankly, I don't think you should have started this whole darn thing.
Frank, can we ask if it was our your idea?
You're the one that told me to find him and say I was Maureen.
Sure, but I never dreamed it's...
You're...
Listen, Popley, would you be willing to have a date with Homer this afternoon?
I...
You know how crazy Homer's always been about you.
What about me?
But sure, he practically worships you.
Who is that?
Homer!
And don't you think the least you can do is be at the Haven when it gets her this afternoon?
Oh, no, Emi.
And what's mine? You think you can put all the blame for this on the moon?
You're very, very much mistaken.
Goodbye.
But, Cass, me, you're just taking it in the wrong way!
Homer, you're too like yourself.
I'm in a hurry, mother.
Are you three going to hold good about this awful thing, dear?
Sure, mother. I wouldn't make a thing like that up.
We had a new year, that.
Homer, are you sure you're getting homeless, sir?
What's the truth for you?
Sure, Father. Don't you remember last night when I was going on the floor?
Well, I've got to go. Goodbye.
Hey, but you can't leave that even your cup cut.
I'm gonna eat it, Mother. I'm gonna take it right along with you.
You're not gonna take a good-cussed cup out of the tree.
I know what I'm dumping it into my hand.
Goodbye.
Over!
Over?
I won't do it on anything. I won't be back in the afternoon till making pictures of the trees.
Well, I can't but the life of the other Samoyu won't get eaten.
Well, it isn't that I doubt you a little bit.
And simply thinking things over and I don't believe Homer.
And this morning Marie found his mother phone.
Your first impulse was a sewer.
Yes, that was my first impulse.
But since then I've had a second impulse.
And may I ask why our own son would make up a story
that Marie begged him for a date if she didn't?
Well, in the first place you stay home and from a mother's point of view.
And only a mother... I mean, I know Homer better than you do.
A boy isn't as popular as he liked to be.
He's close.
But he got too much pride with me.
Well, yeah, I'm sorry, but I believe...
Now wait a little bit. Tell me honestly. Why would any girl want a pomer?
And that really shows how little you know your path. Well I know girls.
Hello. Hello. It's Homer Brown, man.
Oh.
Homer, is there bell children too? Yes, but Homer isn't here.
So this is Mary Allry. When you come to Institute,
I'll be busy discussing when I suspect Kingdom Downey can they be just so old?
Today? Homer? Yes, I just thought it'd be nice if you cut a shower together.
What are you doing with your telling?
I will.
Well thank you. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Elizabeth.
Yes, please.
Our number is L-2-3-2.
I guess that was the mistake then.
What are you doing?
Why, just a girl for hula.
Apparently she changed her mind.
Oh, Homer's name.
Just tell him I'd like to see him again.
He hates him.
Who is this?
He's traveling on his own.
I just thought maybe he'd like to sit down and have me have my scream with it.
Yes?
Were you telling Mr. Brown?
No, just a minute.
Yes, Mr. Brown?
Are you sure it's Homer?
You want to sit down and have ice cream with me?
Oh, yeah!
Very well, I'll put you down.
Goodbye.
And there's a bag!
Yes, we do.
Apparently, I've been misjudging Homer.
I don't know what it is, but the boy's got something.
No!
(cheering)
- Come down, baby.
- Get on me, mom!
- What are you running, little boy?
- I've been looking for you all lunch hour.
Would you be willing to put in a phone call for me?
- No!
- Well, you know how crazy Homer Brown is about him?
- About me?
- Yeah.
She practically worships you.
- Me?
Really?
Homer?
- Sure.
Would you be wearing the medium at the Haven's at 4.15 this afternoon?
No Henry.
Why not?
He's really a very slow guy once you get to knowing.
Heeee!
You mean he is a slave?
Oh no!
And boy, if you only knew how crazy he is about him.
Oh hi Homer!
So aren't you going home for months?
Oh I've got to go in this father shop here.
Hello Homer!
Homer?
Wow!
My goodness it's so easy to see those always crazy to see me.
But that's how that's for you.
As soon as he's got you, he won't hide.
He just the same.
It's not you wouldn't be very much fun to go out with some of my friends.
Hey, Henry, what do you want, Charlie?
You don't seem only going to barber shop there?
Yeah.
What do you think he ordered?
A shave and a lilac water massage.
a side. Hello. Hello. Is it Alice O'Rourke? Is it Elizabeth? Oh, yes, Elizabeth. Alice,
I want to ask you something and I want to serve it in front. Oh, of course. Tell me, what
did you think of Mrs. Taunter? Mrs. Taunter? Oh, I think she's perfectly lovely. You do?
Yes, and she has a darling daughter.
You think so?
Yes, why?
For no reason, Alice. Only her name happens to be coming up with membership and they quill it's next week and um...
And um...
Yes?
And I don't want to be pregnant, it's just because we're finally decided that you threatened our husband with a tooth.
But frankly, if she called me this morning and accused her we're bothering her daughter.
And so it's my fault of all the girls, how and how they date for them.
They do all the phone rings calling inside.
It does.
And now it's...
When I call Mr. Saltis, that's the best.
He talked after those he'd never heard of me before.
Well, my goodness.
Elizabeth, you're the best he's been overdoing.
I don't know, but the point is, who do you want anyone like that in the club?
Hello?
Hello, William Brown speaking?
So anyone Mr. Brown is Mrs. Brown by any chance there?
No sir, this is my office.
You have to call our house.
Well I did and there's no answer.
And can I leave a very important message?
Who is this?
Wyatt, this is a very close friend of Mr. and Mrs. Sonders.
Mr. and Mrs. Sonders?
Yes sir.
And Mr. Sonders wanted me to phone and say his wife
and very sorry she bothered Mrs. Brown this morning
and she didn't mean any word of it.
I see.
Yes sir.
And this is a friend of Mrs. Sonders.
Just a second.
Mr. Saunders is right here in my office, I'll let him talk to you.
He's where?
Henry Aldrich will be back in just a few minutes.
But now let's listen to "Allowie Soul" from "Porgi and Beth."
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(music)
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(music)
[Applause]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Alder.
Homer Brown, because of a practical joke played on him at a party last night,
is under the impression that he has a date that's afternoon with Marie Zombie.
Missus Brown is under the impression Marie's mother objects to Homer's attention.
And Henry, which is very much that he had had no part in the joke.
The scene opens in the old-rich living room.
Henry, was that you that just came in the front door?
Yes, Mother. Has anyone told me?
No, dear.
Who are you expecting a call from?
Oh, Homer.
Are you passing Anderson or Geraldine Long?
No, dear.
May I ask what the trouble is?
The trouble?
Nothing's the trouble, Mother.
Well, I know you didn't eat any lunch.
And here you are at 4am afternoon with a face of my lawn.
Mother, you think girls have the right attitude?
Well, it's what?
Poor anything.
Yeah, I don't know.
You ask the girl to do something, and they all say no.
Boy, I only think about it themselves.
Well, why don't you go out to the ice box and get something to eat and see whether you don't feel better?
Mother, if I ate everything in the kitchen, I still wouldn't feel any better.
And besides, boy, I've got to go out.
May I ask where you're going?
I'm just out.
I'm going to try one more girl.
Then the truth will evolve.
Hello?
Hello, Alice, this is Sam.
What was it you wanted?
I wanted?
I have a message here saying I'm the phone you.
Oh yes, I almost forgot.
It's about Henry.
Here, I'm finally convinced we ought to do something.
What's the trouble?
Sam, I think he's getting a complex.
A complex?
What about?
Well, dear, I'm not sure, but I think it's about Homer.
You know how terribly popular Homer is these days?
Homer is?
I didn't know anything about it.
Well, neither did I until a little while ago.
And Sam apparently handed me a message.
I'm not sure.
But I think it's about Homer.
You know how terribly popular Homer is these days?
Homer is?
Sam apparently Henning must know about it too.
Well, what do you want me to do?
Call him up and try to make a date?
Yeah, this is nothing to laugh about.
My first impulse was to suggest that we send him to some other school
where you get a brand new set of girls.
But I don't think that would do it.
No.
No, because frankly, I think the cause of the whole trouble is his look.
It's look.
Well, that's something we can't help.
You'll grow too.
Well, what?
That gray suit of yours, Sam, that we had picked over for Henning to wear.
He fought it from the start and I think his instinct was right.
Now Alice, we went into that battle and just before school started.
And it was to get 25 cents a week extra provided he was willing to wear that suit.
Alright here, but we didn't know how the girls would react.
And I think the thing to do is to get him a new suit even if it means reducing his allowance.
Alright, tell him beginning next week his allowance will be frozen at the old level.
[Music]
Mother, I give you my word, I don't understand this.
I don't understand any part of it.
Now, Marty, if you did call home around us, why don't you tell me that he has lost your money?
Mother, he's never even said a lot to me, and I never said even that much to him.
Well, there's certainly something about this, I don't understand.
Exactly what does Mother say when she follows you?
Frankly, she began dusting those she's got her head.
And I told her, now here, now here!
You know who you're talking to?
And what did she say?
There's no thing!
I'll see you at his mother.
Hello?
Who?
Homer?
Oh, is this Homer Brown?
Is that Homer?
Mary, let me talk to that young man!
Oh, then Mary Orvis,
is there anything I can do for you?
And when I get sodas all I want right now, Mr. Goodhaven, I've already had two.
I think I'll wait a little.
And what can I do here, Kathleen?
I haven't got all of anything more right now either.
But I may want another one.
When a person I'm waiting for is yes, here.
Kathleen?
I'll have another one.
After all, I've got here a little late.
Who are you waiting for, Kathleen?
I think I'm one of the boys.
I was promised to meet you here.
When were you waiting for?
Yes.
One of the boys.
It's a surprise, we all have to get to go home.
Yes, isn't it?
Listen to heaven, you want to see any boy waiting here, have you?
Honey?
No, I didn't see anyone except Homer Brown.
Oh, get going?
Just a little?
You can see me, but I'm playing with you.
Is that right?
Honey?
My goodness, how did we go with coming in now again?
Let's see where--
Hey, we all, we can't catch you?
Yes, no, yes, no, we're here.
No, we are both, hey, isn't it?
It's not wrong.
Honey, may I take you over just a second?
Me, Kathleen?
You mind my asking what you three girls are waiting here for?
Well, you certainly don't know how many girls you...
Why?
[Inaudible]
Like, I tell you, Adnis, would you like to have a soda?
I'm looking at you to see Homer?
[Inaudible]
If you hot cross, it will be real.
This one's got queen.
See, where's the phone?
Hey, you don't mind my asking if you're crazy.
Mary, there's anything you worry about.
[Inaudible]
Go?
No, I'm two.
Three, two.
Oh, you're right.
You're coming to a practical jail time, Mary.
Why, if you don't have to raise your voice like that.
Oh, you're talking like that, I just...
Hello.
What are those, who's Mary?
Who is this, Mary?
No, it's Henry.
Is this Homer?
Yes, you are.
I got a message to Mary for.
Mary?
My sister?
Then when you see your teller, I'm sorry, but you'll have to make it some other time.
Listen, Homer, why are you doing?
For me.
I'm watching.
You're walking in a time like this? Don't you ever teach your engagement?
I'm going out to dinner.
Where?
Have Marie Saunders, what do you think I'm laughing for?
Is that wrong?
And you know what my father just decided?
Why?
He said any boy that is as popular as I am would have an allowance increase.
And for you?
Boy, and we are my grit.
And you know what Marie's family and my family just decided?
Wow.
Somebody's been doing some furnaces.
And boy, if we find out who it was, do we hit him then?
Is that right?
But hold on, I'm glad you're happy though.
I'll say I am, and I hope you are.
Goodbye.
This is probably one sit-through of the section, I showed him.
Oh, yes, Mr. Behaven. I'll sit-through it.
Do you mind if I sit down for a minute?
The Aldrich family was rebroadcast for the American Armed Forces and the Reliance.
[BLANK_AUDIO]