[Music]
And now the Jell-O family presents...
Henry! Henry Oldridge!
Coming, Mother!
[Applause]
Yes, it's the Oldridge family, based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith,
and starring Ezra Stone as Henry with Jackie Kelk as Homer.
And yes, it's the Jello family with its three famous desserts.
Jello and those six delicious flavors,
Jello Puddings with that old-fashioned homemade flavor,
and Jello Tathioca Puddings,
a miracle of goodness, a marvel of speed.
[
They are made by famous J-E-L-L-O.
And now for the Aldrich family.
To a typical teenage boy like Henry Aldrich, every holiday is naturally a red letter day.
And whatever the celebration, Henry is always certain to be right in the center of it.
Adding a little color of his all.
The scene opens at the Aldrich breakfast table. It's the week before Christmas.
Sam, I'm just as pleased as I can be.
Yes, what about?
Henry, he's been so helpful this past week.
And dear, do you know what I think?
What?
He's really growing up.
You know what I think?
What?
Christmas is just around the corner.
Sam Aldrich, you're just being cynical.
No, Alice, I'm just experienced.
Anytime now he'll start in dropping hints.
What hints?
Is that what he'd like us to give in for Christmas?
Sam, if he does, it's just because he's trying to be helpful.
Father, are you in the dining room?
Yes, Hadra.
Hi, you father old-timer.
There we go.
I thought you might like your pipe here.
Thank you, Ed.
Can I fill it for you?
No, thank you.
Or strike a match and light it?
No, thanks.
She was, isn't there anything I can do?
Would you care to smoke it for me?
Sam!
Henry, is there something special on your mind?
Something you want to say?
Why, no sir, I'm just passing the time of day.
I see.
Only, now that I think of it, did I mention that swell football game I saw?
Wendy, Thanksgiving day.
Boy, it was some game.
It was?
Yeah, too bad I didn't enjoy it.
Still didn't?
Why not?
I don't know.
You take a football game and you sit way back in the stands, see?
And if you're not equipped, where are you?
You're right. It sure makes you angry.
(audience laughs)
Hey, Henry!
Oh, gee, I'll be right with you, Homer. Excuse me.
Hi, Henry. Wouldn't you like to be a little more explicit?
Sure, Father. The game I missed the best part of was the one we came closest to winning all season.
Hi, Homer.
Listen, Henry, when are you going to casually show that advertisement to my father?
What? I'll tell you.
Oh, gee, you wish. Don't you want him to make me happy for Christmas?
Christmas?
Oh, my intent is show it to him.
Just as soon as I find it.
You lost it?
Not permanently.
I was eating some cookies the other night, see?
And the next thing I knew, your ad had disappeared.
Temporarily.
You mean you ate it?
Aiden?
Now that I think about that last cookie was kind of chewy.
And you'll never get that piccolo if you go around eating up my head.
Besides, Homer, if you ask me, you ought to be more subtle about that piccolo.
Who's not subtle? I'm not subtle.
Look, for Christmas, I want those binoculars down into Havens, right?
Right.
So I just subtly drop a few hints and mention that I wasn't able to see the Thanksgiving
football game from way back where I sat.
And right away, they know what's binoculars I want.
They do, sure.
Only, they just try to worry me by pretending they don't understand.
She, Henry, are right. You have to be subtle.
You know what I'm going to do?
Just a few days before Christmas, I'm gonna give my father a box of good cigars.
Cigars?
Sure, and right inside I'll put a copy of that piccolo ad.
How's that for being subtle?
Henry!
Yes, Mary?
Maybe one of you could help me.
With what, Mary?
Well, look, Homer.
Suppose you were a man, see?
Mary, are you insulting me?
Of course not, Homer.
I just said "suppose you were."
Oh.
So if you were this certain party, would you prefer a pen and pencil set or a three-speed
You're buying me a blanket that travels at three speeds.
I should have known better than to ask you a simple question, mother!
Wait a minute, Mary. Ask me again.
Mother, are you in the kitchen?
Mary, dear, I'll be right back. Sam!
Mother, I just want to ask you what I should buy, Kermit for Christmas.
Sam, look what I just found in the cookie jar, an advertisement.
Someone's advertising in our cookie jar.
Here, don't you get it. Henry put it there for us to find.
Oh, let me see him.
Are you never the life of the party?
Buy one of our piccolo's and start playing second fiddle.
675 delivered.
Alice a piccolo?
San, that's what he wants for Christmas.
In grade with bluebirds, one dollar extra.
That would be lovely.
But Alice, where does a football game enter into a piccolo?
Here it's obvious.
Of course Henry wants to play in the school band.
What?
so he can sit right on the sidelines and get a perfect view.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, Mr. Dehaven.
I'll be right with you, boy.
Look, Homer, there are my binoculars.
Where?
Right there in the store window next to that sign that
says, make mother happy for Christmas
with a personalized darning egg.
Now, what can I do for you, boy?
Mr. Dehaven, I like a box of your best cigars.
Yes, sir. We have an excellent brand here that comes all wrapped for Christmas.
Oh, that's swell. I'll take it.
Good. That'll be $11.50.
How much?
$11.50.
That 11 you're speaking of. Is that dollars?
Here it is.
Cheers, all I have is a dollar and a quarter.
Mr. Dehaven, could I please try these binoculars in the window?
Very well, Henry, but be careful.
Gee, thanks.
Mr. Dehaven, don't you have cigars without quite so much tobacco
that come for about a dollar and a quarter.
- No, I'm afraid not.
Why don't I get your father something else?
- Not cigars.
- We have some nice simulated plastic picture frames.
- Picture frames?
- Yes, you could slip your picture
and one of them and give that to your father.
- My picture.
And watch my piccolo go right out the window.
(audience laughing)
- Apparently I'm afraid there's nothing I can do Homer.
Now be careful with those binoculars, Henry.
- Yes, Mr. Dave, and all I'm doing
is looking through them.
Boy, imagine 11.50 for cigars.
People sure do burn up money.
Boy, Homer, boy, are these binoculars in these.
Let me look to them, Henry, let me look.
Okay, but take it easy, Homer.
Hey, you see, Agnes lost him down by the soda fountain?
Yeah.
You know how much her check is?
Only five cents.
Gee, are those binoculars as powerful as that?
Excuse me, Homer.
Who are you, phone?
My father to drop another hen.
Number three.
Al 992.
Yeah, 992.
I think I'll join Ag.
What for?
I wrote her a treat for a long while.
And boy, this looks like a good time to pick up her check.
Hello?
Hello, Father.
Henry, I've got to meet your mother.
What is it?
Why, nothing in particular.
I just happen to be down here in de Haven's drug store.
And I saw--
I saw--
Saw what?
Nothing, Father.
But don't you think it's pretty interesting to be able to see a check from as far off as 20 feet?
See a what?
A check, a check!
Henry, what are you driving at?
Driving at Father, I?
Well, Gee, I just called to pass the time of day!
Yes, but...
Well, now that I've passed it, so long, Father!
Henry, where's Homer?
Over there with Agnes and Mr. de Haven.
If things go right, my parents ought to be in for these binoculars sometime today.
Good. Did I mention there's no extra charge for the leather case?
They come in a case?
Oh yes, with a strap that goes around your neck.
Boy, that's a fine thing.
Say Homer, I found a sample box of 15 cigars that I can let you have for a dollar and a quarter.
But Mr. Dehaven, I have narrows a dollar.
What?
Agnes' check was 25 cents.
I thought it was only five.
So did I.
Only she was deliberately holding her thumb over the two.
[Music]
May I help you, sir?
Yes, do you sell a checkers at this counter?
Oh, we do indeed.
Would you like to see them in wood, plastic, or reinforced cardboard?
Well, or if you want to go whole hog, we have a dandy set and hand-carved ivory.
Well, it really doesn't matter what the checkers are made of, just so that they're big enough to be seen from 20 feet off.
Twenty-three? Yes. Oh, wouldn't it be rather inconvenient to play from that distance?
Oh, it sounded ridiculous to me too, but as near as I can figure out, that's what my son wants for Christmas.
Well, if you'll, uh, just wait a minute, I'll see if we have any large checkers and stuff.
Thank you! Mother! Oh!
Father, what are you doing down here at the Apario?
I was supposed to meet your mother at the information counter ten minutes ago.
Oh. Well, she still has time.
By the way, Father, does a letter case with a strap that goes around your neck mean anything to you?
No, I...
I ran into Henry and he said if I saw you to casually mention that what he wants for Christmas comes in one.
You don't say.
And Father, I have a problem.
Yes.
Well, if you knew a certain party that was...
well, close to you.
Uh... close to you?
Yes.
And suppose you wanted to get him something very special for Christmas to show him how you feel about him.
What would you get?
Well, I really don't feel I should say.
Father, you must tell me.
Well, naturally, Mary, I'm sure whatever you get him, he'll be crazy about.
But if I were that man, you know what I'd really like.
What?
Well, a new hunting rifle?
My goodness.
You're right, Mary. It's too expensive.
Oh, I'm not worried about the money.
No.
No, it's coming out of my special campaign fund.
Well, Mary, I hardly know what...
Well, that is. I'm certainly... Mary.
Father, my goodness, you kissed me right in the middle of the Emporium.
[LAUGHTER]
I don't mean to interrupt, huh? Oh, that's quite alright.
And could you please tell me which way to guns?
I beg your pardon?
Oh, I know, and sporting goods.
Now, don't you go spending too much, Mary?
Nice girl, Mary.
Lovely.
Friend, daughter.
Oh.
Oh, I'll say, isn't your jewelry department nearby?
Two miles over, but as long as she's going as far as a hunting rifle,
I wonder how she'd like a pearl necklace.
But, sir, about those checkers, I've measured all of them in the largest as an inch and a quarter in diameter.
Oh, well, I'll tell you, uh...
Does the set come in a leather case?
- Why no? - And it doesn't have a strap that goes around your neck.
- No. - Well, thanks.
The more I think of it, the more I'm sure we're on the wrong track with checkers.
Well, we have this chest-set in leather case,
- Chests. - And it's been reduced, and we could have a strap put on it.
No, no, I'm afraid not.
If I don't like Chests, why should Henry?
- Sir! - Oh, that's my wife. Excuse me.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I've laid but I've finished every last bit of our Christmas shop.
No, you haven't, Alice. We still need a gift for Henry.
Henry? Didn't you send away for that piccolo?
Yes, but he wasn't heading for a piccolo.
He wasn't?
Not unless a piccolo has something to do with checks.
You can see 20 feet off when it goes around your neck.
What?
Incidentally, Alice, what do you think of pearls?
Pearls?
What?
Why, dear, they're very lovely.
They'd make a nice present for a young lady, wouldn't they?
Oh, my goodness.
Yes, but aren't they rather expensive?
Alice, in this case, nothing's too good.
Well, well, naturally, Sam, it's up to you
And dear, while you're doing your shopping, there's something I ought to take care of too.
Very well, dear, and try to think why it is Henry's been handing out.
I will.
Excuse me, madam, could you let me buy, please?
Young man.
Well, back again, madam.
Yes, these ties I bought a little while ago, I'd like to return them.
So soon?
Well...
Our ties don't usually start coming back until after new years.
Well, you see, I think I'm getting a pearl necklace from my husband,
and I couldn't very well give him just ties in return.
I see. Very well. I'll make out a refund slip.
Thank you.
Incidentally, you've had quite a bit of experience with gifts, haven't you?
I certainly have.
Well, what would you say it was that handy at football games
comes in loud checks and goes around your neck?
Why, madam, that's obvious.
It is?
Yes, you will find our mufflers right over there at the next count.
[LAUGHTER]
But that's incredible. Henry would never...
Why, it's incredible.
What matter, what else could it be?
Mary, you bought Kermit, what, for Christmas?
A gun, mother, a gun.
Do you really think you should be giving a man
you might eventually marry a thing like that?
What about it, though, that's just what Kermit would like?
And, mother, my problem is, what should I have engraved on it?
and grave?
And on the barrel, I was thinking of something like, "To Kermit, peace on Earth, goodwill
toward men."
Here I wouldn't have it engraved until after Christmas.
Why not?
Well, suppose it's the wrong size and has to be returned.
And Mary, wait till you hear what I'm getting from your father.
Hey, Henry!
Mrs. Alvich, have you seen Henry?
Well, I believe he's up in his room home or I call it.
Before you tell me what you're getting?
Mary, maybe you can help me out.
With what?
I've never had any experience rolling cigars.
Rolling, what?
Cigars.
I thought if I bought the raw materials
and eliminated the middleman, I might get by for a dollar.
I've never rolled a cigar in my life.
Hi, Homer.
And I don't think it's a bit nice of you
to infer that I have.
My goodness.
Homer, Mary didn't mention anything about my family
buying those binoculars, did she?
No.
She, I went through every hiding place in the house.
And the only Christmas present I found was a muffler.
For you?
Gee whiz, no.
My parents wouldn't palm a thing like that off on me.
You should see it, Homer.
Chex is big as that, although--
[LAUGHTER]
No, kid.
Boy, it looked like it was on fire.
[LAUGHTER]
Henry.
Yes, Homer?
I hate to mention this, but--
Well, maybe your parents didn't get your hints straight
and watch you something else instead of binoculars.
Henry, will you please answer the phone?
Yes, mother.
Homer, what else could they have thought I was heading for?
Hello? Hello, is this Aldrich? Yes.
L-303? That's right. Well, this is the Emporium calling.
Have you decided on what sort of engraving you want on that hunting rifle?
Hunting rifle? Yes. Hunting rifle?
But you bought this afternoon for the young man.
Are you sure you're calling Aldrich? Yes.
L-303? Yes.
And somebody here bought a hunting rifle? Yes.
Hello? Oh, boy.
Only maybe you shouldn't have told me that.
Oh, it's for you?
You better call back later and speak to either my mother or father.
Goodbye.
Homer, did you hear that?
I'm getting a hunting rifle for Christmas.
Oh, anything fall I asked for was a piccolo.
Boy, that just goes to prove what a few subtle hints can do.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[Music]
[Applause]
Now we'll hear something holiday hints from Meredith Wilson and this fucking piece.
You know Meredith?
What?
That wonderful, colorful, jello family sure had a lot to holiday cheer.
Oh, there's no doubt about it. Those big red letters are just as friendly and cheerful as...
Santa's red suit? Yeah. Hey Prancer. Come on boy, come on boy up,
that's a whooow now. Take it either on that chin. Okay. And after the holidays too, the
same big red letters stand for the same good cheer, the year round.
J. E. L. L. O. Also means satiny smooth, jello pudding.
Every day of the year. J. E. L. O. Also means jello, tappy ochopunny.
And J. E. L. O. Also means jello, the world's most famous shimmering dessert, and nothing
could taste better or sparkle prettier on your table through the holidays, or any day
than any or all of the six delicious fruit-like locked-in flavors of shining, shimmering jello.
Listen to that man go I'll take strawberry, we we we we we we.
Cherry, we we we.
Lemon, we we we we.
Lemon, you're not.
Mmm.
Jake, eat, help, help.
Oh, and back to the Aldrich family.
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrichs.
Henry wanted a pair of binoculars for Christmas, but the subtle hints he's been dropping have led his parents to the first place.
have led his parents to buy him a muffler and a piccolo. Only now Henry
believes they've bought him a hunting rifle, which is really Mary's present to
her boyfriend. The scene opens in the Aldrich living room and it's Christmas Eve.
A snow shovel? Mother, you're giving father a snow shovel for Christmas? Mary,
let me finish. First, your father will give me my pearl necklace. Then I'll give him
his snow shovel. And Mary, you're going to see the longest face you've ever seen.
Well, I should think so.
And then I'll give him his real present, a lovely chess set and a leather cage.
A chess set?
Yes, I saw him admiring it in the Emporium the other day.
Oh, Mother, you're so sweet.
Oh, and Mary, I feel so warm.
So do I.
The house has been so different since Father insulated it.
I didn't mean that.
I mean, everything's so perfect.
Hello, Mother.
Hello, dear.
Hello, Mary.
Hello, Henry.
Would anybody like me to make them a glass of eggnog?
Eggnog, Henry?
Sure.
That's just the thing I'm in the mood to make.
Thank you just the same, dear.
Mary, please phone Mrs. Dixon, and make sure she
launders our good tablecloth in time for Christmas dinner.
Henry, I got that box of cigars from my father.
I did for a dog?
Sure, from Willie Moore.
I don't know Willie smoked cigars.
He does, and this is a box his uncle send his father.
No kidding.
Sure.
Mr. Marshall said the way he feels about his wife's family,
He wouldn't smoke them with a 10 foot pole.
(phone ringing)
- I don't mind answering it, ma'am.
- I'm practically there.
Hello?
- Hello, Mary.
This is Kermit.
- Oh, hello, Kermit.
- Hello.
How have you been?
- Fine, Kermit.
- You had the sniffles when I left last night
and I've been worried.
- You have?
Isn't that sweet?
- How are they?
- Who?
- The sniffles.
- Oh, why?
(audience laughing)
I just finished my Christmas shopping.
You have?
Kermit, I certainly hope you didn't get anything from me.
Well, I...
Oh, Kermit, you shouldn't have.
It's something you wear on your hand.
Really?
Kermit, you're teasing.
No, I'm not.
And they're made of pigskin.
Oh!
That's only if I'm going to give you.
Oh.
Well, I certainly hope you won't ask me to give you any hints about what I got you.
I won't.
You won't?
I'll give you a tiny hint. Just keep your eye on the bull's eye.
On the bull's eye?
And I'm not going to say another word.
Gee, that's a puzzle.
It is.
Well, I can't think of what it could be unless it's a gun.
A gun?
But I know you wouldn't be foolish enough to buy a thing like that.
What?
Not for a guy who served four years in the infantry.
[LAUGHTER]
Well, naturally, I didn't.
Oh my goodness.
Is anything wrong, Mayor?
No, no, but I have to hang up.
Are your snipples coming back?
Kermit, I haven't time to explain goodbye.
Oh my goodness.
What is Mary?
What's her?
Can we out of my way?
Don't you realize all the stores closed at seven tonight?
Are you looking for something in that closet, Mary?
My goodness, I hope it isn't too late.
Mary, Mary, what are you doing?
Mary, let go.
I've got to return this right away.
Return to listen, Mary.
What's that down?
Mary, out of my way.
Mother--
Mary, don't you move another step.
Mary, I warn you.
What's all the shouting about?
Mother, Mary's going to return my Christmas present.
That mufflers for Henry.
Mufflers!
I'm returning comets gone.
Kermit's gone.
Kermit.
Now please let me go, Henry.
I'll never be able to return it in time.
But Henry, Henry, you didn't think that gun was for you instead of Kermit, did you?
Why?
For Henry Alice.
For Henry.
If that gun was for anyone, it was for...
For whom?
Kermit.
Excuse me.
Where are you going?
Up to my room.
And I hope Mary's very happy with her pearl.
Mary?
The pearls of...
High stoodness.
Boy, that's a fine thing.
Henry, where are you going?
How, mother?
Just out.
Dear, you haven't got your coat on.
Gee, who cares?
Well, at least take your new muffler.
Mother, I...
I'd rather not even mention that muffler.
(classical music)
- Hey Henry.
Henry, what are you doing on the curb?
- He's sitting at Homer, Gee Whiz, what does it look like?
- I've been looking for you for nearly two hours.
Merry Christmas.
- Sure, Merry Christmas.
- Right.
I heard about the gun being for Kermit.
Tough luck.
That's okay, Homer.
That's okay.
Maybe the better man won.
Henry, don't say that.
Why not?
Why not face facts?
Gee.
And to think I've been looking forward to this Christmas since last Christmas.
I know how you feel.
I'm not getting my piccolo either.
No?
I'll be lucky to get anything.
Didn't you give your father those cigars?
Sure.
He lit one.
You know what happened?
up in his face. It did? And Willy won't even give me my money back. He says, "Is it his
fault? His uncle doesn't like his father." What's that? A bunch of kids singing
carols on the library steps. Boy, you'd think they'd know better than to disturb the
piece. I'll say. Oh, are you humming? Me? She was, I was just checking to see if they're
- Are they? - No.
- Hi, fellas. - Who's that?
- She was at Staches Johnny Dixon again.
- Merry Christmas to you all.
I just delivered your mother's table clock, Henry.
Aren't we lucky? - Lucky?
- Sure. Look, snow on Christmas Eve.
Isn't it neat?
- What's so neat about snow? All it does is get under your collar.
- And when do you mind leaving us alone?
- Whoa, sure, fellas.
And I hope your mother's cold gets better, Henry.
- Cold? She's got a cold?
- Whoa. That's the way she looked to me.
to me. Say that I show you the swell present I got for my mother. Look, a real
aviator's helmet. Yeah, fur line. That swell. With real fur. Well, I better get home and help
her trim the tree. Merry Christmas to you all. Chee. Yeah, gee. Imagine getting all excited about a hat.
Henry, what? I'm going home.
Oh, you're going to leave me alone? On Christmas Eve?
I'm sorry, Henry. That's where I'd rather be.
She was. Good night.
And Henry.
Yeah? Merry Christmas.
(SINGING)
Henry! Henry, all great!
She was. Mother, what are you doing out in the street?
Here's your coat.
Gee.
Thanks, Mother.
Don't think I'm forgiving you, Henry.
But if you get sick, I'm the one who'll have to suffer for it.
Now put it on.
Yes, Mother, and look.
Hey, Ray, is that you?
Sam!
Alice, what are you doing out here?
Sam, I know we agreed not to speak to Henry, but...
Father, what's that under your arm?
Why, uh...
Gee, whiz, it's my lumberjackin'.
Henry, I'm still the one who has to pay the doctor.
Gee, thanks.
Well, Alice, can we go home?
You're going before I wish I marry Christmas to you all?
What?
Merry Christmas, Henry.
Yes.
Merry Christmas, son.
Gee, Gee, listen to what they're saying.
Love and joy come to you and to your also too.
And God bless you as a whole, Father.
Father, could I apologize for thinking that gun was for me?
Well, that's all right, son.
We all make mistakes.
Sam, I'm so happy.
Hey, I'm just curious.
What was it you were heading for, always?
G-Father, it was silly.
Forget it.
I'm curious.
Well, a pair of binoculars, I saw in the haven.
Binoculars?
But, G, they don't compare to a muffler.
Yeah.
Well, shall we all go home now and trim the tree?
Right.
I'll tell you, Alissa, suppose you go home and start without me.
I just remembered I, I ran out of cigar.
Don't buy them from Willy Father, they blow up in your face.
Well, Leah, shall we start for home?
What, before we do, could I go into this store here and put in one phone call?
To whom?
To Haven's drugstore, and tell Mr. de Haven not to sell my binoculars before Father gets there.
[Music]
Now, very Christmas to all of your families from the Jell-O family.
Jell-O, Jell-O puddings and Jell-O tapioca puddings.
Now for all you youngsters listening in, here's a little Christmas poem.
If you ever get the feeling that you'd like to squeeze the cat,
or tie a tin can to the dog or sit on father's hat,
is hat, or pull the lamp from off the desk or overturn the ink, better stop before you
do, better stop and think.
Because you know what's coming and it's not so far away.
Just two days from now it'll be Christmas day.
You can squeeze the cat in April, you can tease the dog in June.
In August you can dig the yard with Mother's Silver Spoon.
Fathers had a squash in March and next month they'll still be ink.
Better wait a little while, better wait and think.
As you know what's coming, and it's not so far away.
Just two days from now it'll be Christmas Day.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
And here's wishing all of you, from all of us,
a very Merry Christmas.
Good night, folks.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
The Aldrich family starring Ezra Stone as Henry
Jackie Kalk is Homer is written by an almond-toe car and ed jurist with music by Jack Miller.
Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich are House Jamison and Katherine Roth.
And this is Hugh James of New York saying "The Aldrich family is brought to you by the
Jell-O family."
"For desserts that are delicious, boy, believe me, you should know.
They are made by famous J-E-L-L-O."
[Music]
This began next Thursday, same time, same station for another sparkling half hour with the Old Ridge family.
[Applause]
This is NBC, the National Broadcasting Company.
(Bell)