[ Silence ]
[ Music ]
Ten minutes!
Ten miles!
Coming, mother!
[applause]
[music]
The Aldrich family, written by Clifford Goldsmith,
and starring Ezra Stone as Henry Aldrich,
brought to you by the puddings that are tops in taste,
Yellow pudding.
[Music]
Do you remember when you were in your teens?
Well, when you listened to Henry Aldrich and his pals,
We think you sort of be able to detect a little of yourself.
For Henry Aldrich is a typical American boy from a typical American family.
Just listen and see if I am not right.
It's noon in Centerville, and as the scene opens,
Henry and his pal, Dizzy Stevens, are just coming down the stone steps of Central High School on their way to lunch.
Well, Dizzy, what I want to know is where it could have gone.
Listen, a lunch box isn't something a person just overlooks.
Well, you certainly overlooked yours.
Oh, no, I didn't.
Somebody took mine.
Boy, I didn't need any breakfast this morning.
Can't you buy anything?
How am I going to buy anything?
The only thing I've got in my pockets is this knife.
Gee, where's Henry?
You wouldn't like to sell that knife, would you?
Oh, no.
It's got two blades, a quark screw,
and a combined can opener and nail file.
I'll give you 20 cents for it.
No.
I'll give you 30 cents.
dizzy. I think I know who took my lunch. Yeah who? Erwin Cooper and he's right over
there. Hey Erwin. I'll wait here. What do you have Henry my boy? I don't want I don't
like to insinuate anything but you haven't by any chance seen my lunch have you. What are
you trying to do? Kid me? Don't you have the locker next to mine? What if I have?
Well I remember distinctly when I put my lunchbox in my locker this morning you
were standing right by it go on now wait her when don't try to walk away I went
I know when hey Henry what do you think just happened to me what do you remember
violent Hawkins who say the girl I always wanted a date with and never did
dreams she'd even look at me I don't know sure you know she's the one that
Slapping in the face of time I tied it to the desk.
(audience laughing)
Did she just slap you again?
No, wait till I tell ya.
She just asked me to be a partner at the class picnic.
She did?
Sure.
Who are you going with?
Oh, I haven't asked anyone yet.
You're not supposed to.
You have to wait until a girl asks you.
I do?
Sure, hasn't anyone asked you yet?
Well, I've been too busy for anyone to ask me.
How could they even find me when I've been here, there, and everywhere looking for something?
I found you.
Do you happen to know the name of that girl in our class with blonde hair?
With blonde hair?
Yeah.
That's the way half of them are.
No, she's the one that when she speaks, it's in sort of a low voice.
Oh!
You know who I mean?
No.
Well, I'll tell you, Dizzy.
She wears high-heeled shoes, and everyone Cooper is crazy about her.
Oh, I think I know the one you mean.
That's on, girl, Henry.
What's the matter with her?
Boy, I wish she'd asked me to go to the picnic.
Henry, do you realize what you're doing with that knife?
Well, you just cut your tie in, too.
She whizzed, and that was one of my best.
Henry, you ought to sell that knife before you
do some real serious damage.
No. I'll give you a 50 centrere.
Yeah?
Yeah, with 50 centre you can buy out the school cafeteria.
(audience laughter)
I'm hungry, but I'm not going to sell this knife.
And besides, look, what is it? I just found 10 cents in my pocket.
Are you sure that is in mind?
How would your dime get in my pants pocket?
Well, I had a dime and changed this morning.
- It's coming off it!
- She was busy staying in front of me quick.
What's the matter? Come on, let's go across the street to the Havens drugstore.
Howdy, yup, Tiffany.
- Hey, wait for me, Henry!
- Hey Henry! - Somebody's calling Magnus Lawson.
She ruins every one shower I have.
You know, I'm gonna leave you before she ruins mine.
-
You'd like to take me to the picnic.
You mean you haven't got any of those things, will you?
Of course I haven't!
Would you like to be my partner, Henry?
Well, the only thing is...
Oh, has somebody else asked you?
Well, somebody asked me not to accept any offers until I see about something else.
I love to put up a lunch, Henry.
I just get the biggest kick out of it!
Don't talk anymore about food, Agnes.
I'm starved.
The last class I had was in nutrition.
Oh, hey, that's too bad, Henry.
She was, I'm hungry enough to eat a well-balanced lunch.
Say Agnes, you know who that was
that just went into the Havens drug store there?
Just now?
Yep, that girl with blonde hair and high-heeled shoes.
Oh, come on, let's go in and see.
Oh, I don't think you better go into 'em.
Going into me to couple of the fellas in here.
Oh, you are.
Well, would you let me know about the picnic, Henry?
Give me three days, Agnes.
But if you'd rather not wait that long, I'll understand.
Goodbye, Henry.
Hey, Henry.
Hiya, Homer.
Henry, come over by this table in a minute.
What do you have?
Do you know who that girl is sitting at the counter?
Which one?
The blind with the blue eyes.
Yeah, isn't she a beauty girl?
You couldn't know me a dime, could you?
That's all I got myself, Homer.
I'll pay you 25% interest.
No, I've got to go over to the counter and get my lunch.
I saw a first though Henry.
Yeah.
What do you have?
Oh yeah.
I guess this young lady was here first.
Oh well I haven't decided yet.
Oh.
Mr. Is that big ham there?
Yes sir.
What's that next to it?
Those big.
Oh.
What's this?
It's fried chicken.
Well I'll take apple pie.
Apple pie.
A small piece.
That's a nickel isn't it?
- Yes, sir. - Put a scoop of ice cream on it.
Could I trouble you for a paper nap, can you?
Oh, oh, sure. How many would you like?
Just one.
Here, she was. Take the whole container.
Uh, do you want whipped cream on that pie?
Well, no extra charge. Shoot the works.
Hey, um...
Not bad.
That'll be 15 cents.
15 cents?
Nickel for the pie, dime for the large ice cream.
Yeah, well, that's fair enough.
Only, uh, can I have the water ice cream in the first place?
You don't want this?
Well, would it be an awful lot of trouble if I didn't take it?
You mean I got a dismantle, is it?
[laughter]
Well, I'm afraid so.
Listen, what do you want?
Well...
Could I have the menu, please?
Oh, sure.
You wouldn't like a piece of apple pie on me, would you?
I don't think I should.
Well, why not?
Gee whiz, Mr. One apple pie and I think I'll take the same.
Just plain?
Yes, sir, plain.
Well, it certainly seems good to have spring here.
I like spring.
I like to go on picnics, too.
You do?
Yeah.
Are you going to the craft picnic?
I'm not saying yet.
Well, what's the idea of shaking pepper all around?
Gee whiz, Mr.
I know I had it in my hand.
Would anyone mind if I could take ice cream on my pie?
You want ice cream too?
Vod you're small.
Well I think I'll take the small.
Not large?
How about you buddy?
What was the matter of fact I don't think I'll eat anything at all?
I must be hungrier than you.
Yeah.
Frankly I was just going to eat to kill time anyhow.
Oh could I have a chocolate mold or two?
A chocolate mold?
One cup!
(audience laughing)
Yes, one chocolate maul.
- What is your name?
- My name is Henry Albridge.
- My name's Geraldine Love.
- It is?
- Mm.
- She was Geraldine Love.
(audience laughing)
- Who takes the check?
- Oh, I'll pay for it.
I wonder, I wonder if--
- Who are you looking for?
I just thought there might be someone in here I know.
Who?
Why, you're...
Wonder whether there could be anyone outside looking for me.
Would you mind excusing me for just a second while I step out?
How about this test?
I'll be right back!
Busy?
Hey, Busy, why don't you have?
Come here, I'm in a terrible position.
What happened?
Hurry up.
Here's my knife.
Give me that 50 cents.
I haven't got 50 cents anymore.
No?
No, I've been getting something to eat.
Haven't you anything?
Just 30 cents.
Well, she was, I don't make 40 cents, give it to me.
Here's the knife.
Oh, I didn't give the side to eat after all.
Only in a way I did.
Oh, he had teeth, thanks.
So long.
Yeah, I've got to go back in.
- Was anyone out in front?
- Was there?
And was it a good thing I saw him?
- That'll be 20, 30, 40 cents.
Huh?
That'll all.
- Aren't you gonna eat anything?
- See, if you could have seen the lunch I brought from home.
- Oh, you've already eaten?
- I stuffed myself.
Hey Henry, what do you have, Disney?
Your mother's out here.
My mother?
Henry, I've been looking all over for you.
Is somebody sick for you?
No, dear.
You let your lunchbox at home in the living room.
Mother?
Well, dear, you can't go all day without anything to eat.
For mother, I've had more than enough.
I left that box home on purpose.
Hi, Geraldine.
Is that you in there?
Oh, hello, where are we?
And where did you come from, Erwin?
I see you find your box, Henry.
Now maybe you can eat something.
Henry, mother, do you mind if I change the subject
for just a minute. I want you to meet Geraldine Love.
Hello. Come on, Henry. Let's go over to school.
Okay. It was nice when I saw Henry.
She wish she's gone.
Who is that young woman, Henry?
She's the best looking girl in school, mother.
She's hardly the best man, Ed.
But you don't really know her.
And while I appreciate your bringing this lunchbox,
I do think it could have handed it to me more cautiously.
Henry, Agnes Lawson's mother phoned this morning.
Well, she said, "I wanted to know whether you wouldn't like
to go to the class picnic with Agnes. I hope you didn't tell her I would.
Why wouldn't you dare? I couldn't possibly. Why not? Because.
Henry, there isn't any girl you know quite as nice as Agnes.
But mother, she can't begin to compare with Geraldine.
I'm sure he isn't as rude as that young woman. You're just jumping at the conclusion.
Henry Agnes' mother has always been so nice to you. And so is Agnes.
But she's still not my idea of a girl I might go on a picnic with. Then I don't
think you should accept any more of her hospitality.
Henry! Say! Henry! Aren't you going to be late to class?
Oh, hello Agnes!
Oh, hello Mrs. Olgritte!
The light film may ring any minute, Henry!
Well, there's still lots of time, Agnes.
Henry, don't you think this would be a good time to tell Agnes what we were just discussing?
For Mother, look at the clock. I didn't know it was so late.
It won't take one minute.
What is it about?
Well, Agnes...
Would you like to have me go to the picnic with you?
Oh, Henry, of course!
Well, I'd like to go with you.
See that, there it didn't take one second.
Oh, I'm so glad you can go Henry.
I think I'd better hurry.
Oh, do you mind if I walk with you?
No.
Goodbye, dear.
Goodbye, mother.
Goodbye, little girl, Bitt.
When are you going to eat your lunch?
During music.
Dilly.
Look, hurry across the street.
Oh, Henry, all of it.
Oh, she was Geraldine.
Could I see you alone, Henry?
Oh, wait for you.
Right at the entrance, Henry.
You better go right on in, Agnes.
Henry.
Well.
Henry, everyone Cooper can't go to the picnic.
Would you like to be my partner?
I...
be your partner.
Of course.
Well, gee, where is...
Would you?
The only thing is...
Has someone else asked you?
I can fix it, all right.
I can fix it, I'm sure I can.
Really?
Of course.
Oh, Henry.
Henry, I'm so thrilled you can go.
She was. Think how I feel.
I'm going with you.
Boy, I'm going with you.
Can you bring the long Henry?
I bring you.
Oh, I just hate to put up an old lunch.
Sure, I'd be very glad to.
Oh, my goodness. We better hurry.
Henry, hey, Henry, I've got a message for you.
Come here.
What is it, Dizzy?
Could you excuse me, Geraldine?
You won't forget Henry.
Forget?
How could I?
Listen, Henry, let me tell you, boy, you're gonna pass right out.
Why?
I fixed it up for you.
You fixed what up for me.
To go to the picnic.
With whom?
The girl you said you wanted a meat.
But I just met her.
Oh, no, Henry, that isn't the girl you wanted a meat.
I just talked to the one you want.
She's crazy to have you go.
But, Dizzy, I've already got a date with this one.
It's too late to tell the one I have talked to you.
You can't go, Henry.
She busted a date purposely.
Boy, on eye your pal?
I'll say you're my pal.
That makes three girls and one picnic.
You know, ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls of Henry's age often say
and do a lot of things that puzzle parents.
But among the most surprising things
about all boys and girls is their strange powers of hearing.
Your own son, for instance, may be just upstairs
in his room when you call him from the kitchen.
- Tommy?
Oh, Tommy, come down here a minute.
Tommy!
- But no answer, so you call again.
And this goes on for several minutes
until you finally say to yourself.
- Well, I did think he might want this extra dish
of jello chocolate pudding if he doesn't, I'll eat it myself.
Wait a minute, Mother, here I am.
Where is it?
Uh-huh.
You see, it just goes to prove that all you have to do is mention just barely whispered
jello chocolate pudding, and folks young and old will come running.
Because seriously, ladies and gentlemen, jello chocolate pudding is a mighty delicious treat.
It's a grand satisfying dessert, delightfully smooth and creamy,
me, and every tempting spoonful is rich with swell, chocolaty flavor. You'll be glad to
know, too, that jello chocolate pudding is easy to make, and that it costs only a few pennies.
So try some real soon. For keen, luscious enjoyment, jello chocolate pudding is in a
class by itself.
[Music]
Now getting back to Henry Alvich, when we left him Henry through no fault of his own,
was dated with three girls for the class picnic.
Now the scene opens on the morning of the picnic.
Henry wearing an apron is working in the Alvich kitchen.
Mother, is this all the wax paper we have?
Well, Henry, you've already used two rolls.
But I'm making the sandwiches big.
May I ask how big Geraldine's mouth is?
Look, Mother, look at this well bottle of stuffed olives.
Where did you get enough money to buy those?
I sold a picture that was up on my wall.
Mother, I wonder why Geraldine doesn't like to put up a lunch.
What did Agnes say when you told her you couldn't go with her?
Very little.
Well, Henry, I still don't like it.
But don't you think it was alright for me to tell a girl,
dizzy, fixed up for me that I couldn't go?
That was entirely different, huh?
Henry, what's the trouble of the portable phone of grass that was up in my room?
Mary, I meant to speak to you about that.
Do you need it today?
What's more, I'd like to know what became of that pillow that was up in my room?
Well, which one?
The Princeton one.
Couldn't I borrow that if I take very good care of it?
I'm going to rent a canoe, Mary.
Why can't you take my Harvard pillow, Henry?
She was, though I could ask any girl to sit on Harvard.
Why not, Henry?
Well, in the first place, it's coming out at the seams.
No, Agnes will notice that.
Agnes, I'm not going with Agnes.
I thought you were.
Mary, didn't you tell Agnes?
How are you?
Mary.
Mary, the message I gave you.
When you were going over to her house yesterday, I cooled downstairs to you.
I didn't hear you.
But you must have.
I said Mary, will you please tell Agnes I can't take her to the picnic because I have a very urgent engagement
Well, I certainly didn't understand you had a G whiz if that doesn't leave Agnes in an embarrassing position
Why Agnes why Agnes she'll have to eat her lunch alone. Oh, no, she won't dare mother
I couldn't take her you certainly will the level Geraldine thing you've known Agnes a great deal longer than you had Geraldine
My mother haven't you caught on?
I'm not fond of Agnes.
If I take her I'll be embarrassed the whole afternoon.
Mary, could you let me speak to Henry alone, please?
Yes, mother.
But I fully disapprove of the whole thing.
That's because neither one of you is a boy.
And what's more you've never had to take out Agnes?
Henry, I realize Geraldine must be a very pretty girl.
She's beautiful, Mother.
Well, that's Grant. She's the most beautiful girl that ever lived.
But don't you see how Agnes is going to feel?
And her mother's always been so nice to you.
Oh, don't misunderstand me, mother.
I'm very fond of Agnes's mother.
In fact, if it were a choice, I'd rather take her.
I'm sorry, dear. I'm not going to say anything more, I see.
Does that mean yes or no, mother?
I've said, "All I'm going to."
Henry, get me, sister, front door!
Hey, Henry! I'm calling, Des.
Henry, I'm in an emergency.
(audience laughs)
What's the matter?
Do you wanna buy this knife?
I'll let you have it for 50 cents.
It isn't worth 50.
You try to sell it to me for 50.
(audience laughs)
And if you don't buy it,
I won't have any lunch at the picnic.
Why not?
My girl can't go.
She can't, doesn't she?
No.
It would be your...
Listen, busy.
If I'll fix you up with one of the slullest girls
you ever met in your life,
will you give me that knife?
Are you kidding me?
Do you like fried chicken?
And peanut butter sandwich and devil leg. Oh sure I do. Give me the night
This here. Who is it? Come here while I tell up on boy. Are you one luck?
Hello operator
She was what she liked. She's a dream
Yeah, and she's got the swallest mother
Operator I want one at three seven three one. Let's freeze now wait a minute Henry
Isn't that Agnes's number
Dizzy, her mother can cook. I know, Henry, but I'm not interested. She's got a lunch basket
that's really a laundry hamper. She has? Mm-hmm. A operator? The line's busy? Well, will
you let me know when it isn't? Boy, am I going to have a swell time with Geraldine. You know
What I'm going to do, Dizzy?
Why?
Well, I'm going to rent a canoe.
Where'd you get the money?
I sold a set of books I never read.
And hey, look at this phonograph.
Gee whiz, what did you sell?
I get that.
Oh nothing.
Want to listen to something swell?
Ever hear anything like it, Dizzy?
I got a pillow from Princeton, too.
Yeah, I'm gonna let Geraldine sit on it.
Right in the middle of a canoe.
And then you know what...
And then what?
Well, you know that capicle...
...weild on the far side of the lake?
Yeah...
Boy, is that a swell place to eat lunch?
She would.
Hello?
Hand me what happened to the racquet?
Hello, Agnes?
Agnes, how would you like to have me arrange a very pleasant surprise?
How would you enjoy going today with Dizzy Stevens?
What does she say, Henry?
Oh, no, Agnes, I think you've got the wrong idea of him.
What's that?
Oh, no, Agnes, he isn't like that.
Hang up, Henry.
Maybe who are you talking?
Agnes, Mrs. Orrich.
Henry, you are not to tell her you can't take her.
- Can't take her. - Yep, but mother--
- Did you hear me?
- Yes.
Hello Agnes.
I'd like to go with you.
No, I'd be very glad to.
I'll pick you up in about an hour.
Goodbye.
Henry, could I have my knife?
She was.
Am I gonna have a swell time?
Agnes and Geraldine both at once.
(dramatic music)
(crying)
(crickets chirping)
Do you see anyone coming, Agnes?
Maybe she changed her mind, Henry.
I'm sure Geraldine is coming. She told me she was.
Aww, couldn't we get into the canoe here?
You know, I've always wanted to go in a canoe.
Haven't you ever been in one?
No.
Can you swim?
No, I can't.
Is that right?
Oh, gee, look who's coming down the path.
Who is it?
Geraldine.
I'll be back in the second magnet.
Oh, gosh, Henry, why don't you wait here on the top?
I've got to help her carry your sweater.
Hello, Henry.
Oh, I saw you came.
Let me carry your sweater for you.
I think you have it so much.
Henry, who's that down on the dock?
Well, it seems Geraldine there was a misunderstanding.
Henry that girl isn't going with us, is she?
Geraldine, she's just a friend of a family.
But I asked you to go.
Well, I'm here to go with you.
She's really going just for my mother.
Hi Geraldine.
Now look over here.
Oh, Erwin Cooper. I thought you couldn't come.
I'm here though. Hi, Henry.
Glad to see you, my boy.
I'm glad to see you.
Oh, I'm glad to see you.
Henry!
Who's that calling you Henry?
It's just a girl.
Tell me!
Yes Agnes!
What's the matter?
You Henry look!
He's got one foot on the dock and one foot on the canoe and he's holding your lunch bag
get right over the water!
Agnes!
Pull your legs together!
I'm going to fall in!
Oh, put that lunch bag down Agnes!
I'm going to... (screams)
No!
(crowd laughs)
I'm going to be lucky, so I am!
I'm going! I'll pull her out.
It's only three feet deep.
Grab a canoe, Agnes!
Stand up!
Get your head out of the water!
(crowd laughs)
Agnes, don't be childish.
Just get off your knees.
- What's that lot?
Then wait in.
I'm coming Henry.
Open your eyes. You're waiting the wrong way.
Oh, James, wait a minute.
You're giving me your hand, Agnes.
All right. Here.
Come on out.
Oh.
There.
Don't drip in the lunch basket.
Oh, I won't, Henry. I'll just squeeze my dress out a little here and there.
[audience laughter]
I'll be alright!
Now look Agnes, don't you think you want to go right straight home?
Oh no, this sounds awfully warm.
We can get in the canoe and I'll be jive by the time we get to the other side of the lake.
Where's Geraldine?
Oh, there she is! Look!
And I'm the lake with Erwin!
She was...
...the Renekindo.
And they took my lunch basket.
Come on, come on, Henry.
Get in this canoe with me, huh?
Sure.
I'll get in.
Isn't this lucky you had this crimson pillow for me to sit on?
Yeah.
Say, did you know your hair has all come down?
I let it down on purpose!
And me, you mind if I played its phonograph while I lean back in the sun?
Well, if you have to
As we lucky everything is ended up beautifully
[Music]
You know, ladies and gentlemen, when folks get to talking about favorite desserts,
there's one they never fail to mention, and that's "Butterscotch pry."
Yes, the butter scotch pie is a mighty swell treat, and it's marvellously easy and inexpensive
to make too when you make it with jello butter scotch pudding.
Because when you use jello butter scotch pudding for the filling, you do away with all guessing.
You save time and effort, and you make certain that every single pie will be a grand success.
Furthermore, this rich, taffy-colored pudding gives you a pie filling that's as creamy and
satin smooth as can be.
You'll be delighted with its golden butterscotch flavor, its zestful, satisfying goodness.
So furlough the lead of so many smart modern housewives.
Tomorrow night, treat the family to a luscious butterscotch pie made the easy way with jello butterscotch pudding.
Ask your grocer for several packages of this tasty dessert, but be sure to say jello butterscotch pudding.
Because only jello butterscotch pudding can give you such rich mellow enjoyment.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(upbeat music)
[Music]
I'm sorry mother, but I'm through with them forever.
Really, Henry?
I've never seen a girl yet that didn't turn out to be a disappointment.
Why?
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just hard to please.
Oh, could you put some more sunburned lotion on me?
I'll ask Mary to.
Don't let Mary get near me.
She'll put it right where my poison ivy is.
[Music]
The Aldrich family starring as the stone is written by Clifford Goldsmith, original music composed and conducted by Jack Miller.
Mrs. Harry Bonsell speaking and wishing you good night for the puddings that are tops in taste, jello puddings.
(audience applauding)
[Music]
(laughing)