[Music]
And now the Jell-O family presents...
Henry... Henry O'GRAE!
Coming, Mother!
[Applause]
Yes, it's the O'GRAE family based on characters
originated by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Ezra Stone as Henry with Jackie
Pelka's home. And yes it's the Jell-O family with its three famous desserts.
Jell-O in those six delicious flavors regular Jell-O puddings with that old
fashioned homemade flavor and Jell-O tapioca puddings. A miracle of goodness, a
A Marvel of Speed
Everyone's a Jello Goodfellow
A very good Jello Goodfellow
So rich, so tempting and mellow
J-E-L-L-O
And now for the Aldridge Family
[Music]
117 Elm Street Centerville is your own house or the house on the next block
or that house right around the corner in your memories.
And the important person in and out of it is always a typical teenage boy like Henry Aldrich.
The scene opens at the Aldrich breakfast table.
It is Saturday morning.
- How long has we have to? - Now, Sam.
- Started out to be such a nice day.
The air is brisk, the sun is shining.
Why ruin it by discussing Henry's report card.
- But do you have you seen it?
- I signed it.
- But have you seen it?
- You don't think I signed Henry's report card
with my eyes closed, do you?
- Yes.
- How old?
- If you looked at it,
you'd certainly be more upset.
And I'm sure we ought to have his basal metabolism taken.
- That's why.
- His basal metabolism, Sam,
it's at the bottom of a lot of things these days.
(audience laughs)
- Not report cards.
Alice, there's nothing wrong with Henry
that some hard work won't cure.
You just got to learn to stop procrastinating
and buckle down.
- That's right, dear,
and I think you should speak to him about it.
- Yes, Alice, I will.
Tomorrow.
- Why can't you do it today?
- Alice, the sun is shining, the air is brisk,
and it's Saturday, Henry's day of rest.
- Sam Aldrich, if you ask me you could do
with a little buckling down yourself.
Henry yes mother come in here please and dear if he has any homework I think you should do it right now
You were calling on my mother yes dear father has something to say to you he has oh boy
I'll answer the phone yes father Henry Henry what I want to say is yes
what I want to say father if it's going out of your head I don't mind dropping the whole thing
until it comes back.
I haven't forgotten Henry. Sit down.
Sit down? But father, yes, father. I'm sad.
I mean, sit. They're the seated.
Henry, your mother and I have just been discussing your report card.
You have? On a nice day like this?
I had the same reaction.
Henry, don't you think it's about time you buckle down and started to worry about your schoolwork?
Gee, I do worry about it, Father.
You do? I give you my word. There's nothing I worry about more.
I'm glad to hear that.
But I'd be glad to do a little extra worrying if it would ease your mind.
That's very cooperative of you, Henry, but there's one method we ought to try first.
There is what?
Work.
Work?
Yes.
Father, when you say work, how do you mean that?
Just the way it sounds.
Good, hard, industrious effort.
I want you to buckle down and really put your mind to your study.
Yes, sir.
Now, what homework do you have this weekend?
This weekend?
Well, gee, that's a wonderful part, Father. I practically don't have any at all.
Not at all?
Well, just a few simple geometry problems.
And gee whiz, I cannot close off in five minutes.
Good! Suppose you take five minutes right now and start knocking.
Yeah, what?
But Father, when I said five minutes, I was thinking of five minutes Monday morning
when my brain will have a whole weekend's rest.
Henry, your mother and I have taken all the procrastinating we're going to.
You're not to leave the house until your geometry is done.
But Father, is that clear?
Yes, sir.
Sam, could I speak to you out here in the hall?
Yes, Alice.
I'll get to work, Henry.
Yes, Father.
But I'm really much better at homework on Monday morning.
Sam, you didn't tell him to do his homework now, did you?
Yes, why?
That was Homer on the phone,
and I'm afraid we'd made a terrible mistake.
In what way?
He's on his way over here.
Alice, I'm afraid that's a mistake we can no longer avoid.
Here you don't understand.
We didn't realize that the boys have a date
to go ice skating with Kathleen and Agnes.
So wouldn't it be just as well
if he did his homework Sunday evening?
- Alice, after I ordered him to do it now.
- But Sam, this is Saturday, his day of rest.
- Suppose I do this, Alice.
Suppose I help him.
- You will?
Well, that might help.
But nevertheless, dear,
I'm certainly going to write a note to Mr. Bradley.
- Henry's principal, why?
- Sam, they have no right to ruin
a boy's entire weekend this way,
especially on the last good ice skating day of the year.
Oh, Alice.
So will you answer that, dear?
I'm on the stove.
Hello.
Hello, Sam.
This is Will Brown.
Yes, Will.
Sam, I just looked outdoors, and it's a wonderful day.
Yes, isn't it?
The sun is shining.
There's a don't snap in the air.
And I thought, why stay cooped up in the house?
Why not call good old Sam and spend the afternoon bowling?
Bowling?
Why not?
You mean, why be cooped up in the house
when you can be cooped up in the bowling alley?
But Sam, I have to get out of the house.
Elizabeth's trying to get me to shellac the dining room
Shall I get sure that's her favorite indoor sport trying to get me to shellac
So what do you say aren't you in the mood to bowl Sam? Oh, I'm in the mood all right good
Then suppose you pick me up right away. Well, I'll tell you there's a little matter. I have to clean up first
You mean Alice has stuck you with some job. No, no, no, it's just just well. It's nothing. I can't finish in five minutes
Okay, I'll be waiting for you so long Sam. Goodbye, Will
- Hey, Ray.
- I'm in the dining room, Father, buckling down on my homework.
- Good.
- Gee, Father, mother told me about your helping me,
and boy, I certainly appreciate it.
- That's quite all right.
Now let's get started.
- Hey, Henry.
(audience laughing)
- Gee.
- Sounds like Homer.
- Doesn't sound like anyone else.
- Hi, him, hi, Mr. Old, which boy, what a day, what a day.
(audience laughing)
- Homer.
- Is that an apple in that food bowl?
- Homer, don't bite it.
It's wax.
It is.
Boy, what a day.
Come on, Henry, let's go.
Let's go?
Sure, are we meeting the girls at 12?
Well, first, Homer, there's a little matter, my father,
and I have to get out of the way.
What a little matter.
My geometry homework.
You're gonna do that now?
What'll you do Monday during lunch?
(audience laughing)
Homer, the fewer interruptions we have,
the quicker we'll finish.
So would you please sit quietly in the corner?
Yes, sir.
Now, Henry.
Henry, did I tell you about that trick,
Agnes and I worked out?
Homer, if--
We're skating along gracefully, see?
And then all of a sudden, she grabs me by the wrist
and throws me over a shoulder.
Homer, I--
And when I come down there, she is to grab me again.
Homer?
Yes, Mr. Olridge.
I'll shut up.
Good.
Now--
Is that banana wax, too?
It is.
Oh, the pear, too?
Homer, I'm sure Mrs. Olridge must have something edible
in the kitchen.
Yes, sir.
You don't mind my leaving?
Not a bit.
You won't be long, will you, hand?
No, Gee, if we buckle down, we'll be through in no time.
Henry, how many problems have you done so far?
How many?
Well, there's one in particular I'm sort of stuck on.
Which one?
The first.
I see.
Well, let's get to work on it.
Yes, sir.
Just as soon as I get this lampshade fixed.
What's wrong with it?
Well, Gee, was-- did you ever notice how it tilts?
Boy, you can hardly concentrate.
Excuse me.
Where are you going?
get a pair of pliers so we can work with a free mind.
- And reset down.
- Yes.
- You'll never get anywhere if you keep on procrastinated.
- Now, what's the problem you're stuck on?
- A farmer gray has a field that is 900 feet on one side,
800 feet on the parallel side,
and the remaining sides are 100 feet each.
If the field is in the shape of a trapezoid,
what is the area?
- Henry, that can't be right.
But I copied it right off the blackboard, Phon.
The field is in the shape of a what?
Trapezoid.
Oh.
Oh, trapezoid.
Well, that shouldn't be hard.
Do you have your pencil, Henry?
Yes, sir.
And your ruler and your paper?
All right, can Henry now first tell me what is a trapezoid?
What is it?
Well, Henry, you can't expect to find the area
unless you know what it is.
But, Father, that's the whole thing.
I don't even remember Ms. Bennett ever even mentioning trapezoids.
I can't. Do we have a nutcracker on you?
A nutcracker?
All your mother had to eat that wasn't in a can with these walnuts.
Homer, you'll find my hammer in the basement.
Yes, sir.
Henry, do you think you'll be through by the time I'm all cracked?
Homer, just run along.
Yes, Mr. All, which I'll leave you alone.
Let's hurry, Henry. Suppose you look up trapezoids.
Where's your math book?
Why, in my lunchbox.
- You're having it for lunch?
- No, sorry, I put it in there so I'd be sure not
to forget to bring the book home from school.
- Well, please get it.
- Well, that's just it, I forgot my lunchbox.
(audience laughs)
- You don't have a book at all?
- No, sir.
So couldn't you just tell me what a trapezoid is?
- A trapezoid, of course.
Now, as I remember it, a trapezoid is a sort of...
- Yes, Father?
- Henry, you'll never learn by my telling you.
The thing for you to do is look it up.
But we're fathers.
Doesn't Homer have a geometry book?
Sure, but it's probably in his house.
Well, ask him to get it.
But fine.
And please hurry, Henry.
A certain gentleman is waiting for me on a very urgent matter.
Hello.
Elizabeth, this is Alice.
Oh, hello, Alice.
Elizabeth, I'm writing a letter to Mr. Bradley.
And I wondered if you'd be interested in signing it too.
What sort of a letter, Alice?
About the amount of homework they give the boys.
I say, "Dear Mr. Bradley, as one of your mothers,
I am deeply concerned about my son's weekend."
Henry has homework over the weekend?
Yes.
Well, isn't Homer lucky?
He never has any.
But are he and Henry in the same class?
That's true.
They are.
He must have homework.
I should think so.
You know what Homer's trouble is he takes after will.
Always putting things off.
- He does?
- Alice, I'd hate to tell you how long I've been after Will
to shellac my dining room floor.
I asked him this morning and he said
he's going bowling with Sam.
- Sam?
Sam's going bowling?
- Isn't he?
- Well, right now he's working on a trapezoid with Henry.
- You don't say?
Well...
- Elizabeth.
- Oh my goodness, it's Will.
I better hang up before he gets away.
- All right, goodbye Elizabeth.
- Goodbye.
Will, I'd like to speak to you.
- Elizabeth, I've never seen my bowling shoes.
You're bowling shoes, they're in my broom closet.
What are they doing there?
They're so comfortable to do housework in.
Elizabeth.
And anyway, Will Brown, you won't need them.
Why not?
If Sam Aldrich can fix Alice's trapezoid,
you can survive your life.
Thanks, her wife.
Oh, don't stand around asking questions.
Suppose you stop.
But Elizabeth, it's too humid to show up.
You used the same excuse in July.
But Elizabeth--
Will Brown.
How would you like to have sweet breads for dinner?
Every day from now on.
Sweet breads.
Elizabeth.
Glad you're going to get them if that floor isn't done today.
But Sam will be here any minute.
Hi, man.
Elizabeth.
Father, have you seen my geometry book anywhere?
Where did you put it?
I don't remember.
I always put things like that right out of my mind
as soon as I get home on Friday.
Well, I haven't seen it.
And Homer--
Well, there it is on the hall table.
Excuse me.
Oh, wait a minute, Homer.
Didn't you promise to help me shellac the dining room floor?
Sure. When the time came, then she couldn't get out of it.
Well, the time has come.
Look at the brushes and let's start.
What fun?
Homer starts shellacking and shut up.
Henry, go back and look through that encyclopedia again.
Gee, was father. I did four times, and I give him my word trapezoids, nowhere in there.
Henry, it must be everything's in the encyclopedia.
But it isn't. It goes from Tripani to trap shooting.
Oh, I know. Remember when little cousin Bertram visited us last summer?
What about him?
Boy, if there was one thing he liked to do, it was cut pictures out of books.
You suppose he took trapezoids with him?
That's a fine thing. Let me at that full.
Father, who are you calling?
Mr. Cleary, my accountant.
And find out once and for all what a trapezoid is.
Number two.
Elma, 494.
Do you think Mr. Cleary can help us?
He can't know one can. I've never seen anyone who could do the things with figures that he can.
Hello?
Oh, hello, Mr. Cleary. This is our all-rich.
Why, hello, Mr. All-rich. I've been trying to get you all week.
Every time I call your office, you're in conference.
Oh, yes. We don't have too much time left to get your books in order.
Yes, I know, and I'm very anxious to have them out of the way, naturally.
You are good, I'll have you right over.
What?
All I have to do is get your books together and sharpen my pants.
But, Mr. Cleary...
I don't usually work on Saturdays, but if we buckle down, we should be through in two or three hours.
Two or three?
Goodbye.
Mr. Cleary, come back. Mr. Cleary, I don't have time to. Mr. Cleary, I'm in conference.
And now it's time to listen to someone who actually is in conference. Meredith Wilson and his talking people.
on-track on-track
the sirs at best names
on-track on just a moment here
on-track
that's french for intermission
on time no it is but what has all your glamorous french got to do with henry
all rich and his trapezoid
we're the intervention on the all rich family program
no yes
sponsored by the jello family
world's most glamorous desserts
all i see
there's glamour in the shimmer of jello six delicious flavors starting with
Strawberry Eewee, cherry Eewee, orange! Love it to you!
Ah, those shimmering flavors are rich with locked-in flavor!
J-E-L-L-O-O!
And Jell-O's locked-in flavor can't get out until your first tempting spoonful.
Now that's why it tastes so good.
It makes you think of the real ripe fruit itself.
And don't forget those big red letters that spell Jell-O,
also stand for the entire Jell-O family of desserts!
[Music]
And now back to the Aldrich family.
Yes, getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
After Mr. Aldrich had made a date to go bowling with Will Brown,
Mrs. Aldrich and vaguely meant to helping Henry with his geometry homework.
This inspired Mrs. Brown to insist that her husband get to work shellacking the floor.
The scene opens in the Brown's dining room.
It is later the same day.
Homer, that's the oldest mistake in the world.
But Father, I thought you were leaving him down at your inn for us to get out.
You thought I was leaving you.
Now we're stuck in the middle of the dining room floor, surrounded by wet shellac.
What are we gonna do?
Keep quiet, I'm thinking.
Yes, sir.
And do you have to keep staring me in the face?
Father, where else can I stare?
Elizabeth!
Why are you calling Mother?
Homer, I have a very important appointment with a certain gentleman.
Elizabeth!
Well, do you have to shout all of...
Well...
Well, what?
Well, wouldn't you know it?
Elizabeth, let's be constructive. Get us out of here.
Here, I'm afraid you'll have to stay there until the chill act drives.
What?
And why are you there, Homer?
Mother, what are you getting out there in the hall?
Your geometry book.
What?
Here, catch.
Oops.
If Henry can do his homework, you can do yours.
But Elizabeth, what about me?
You can help Homer.
Help Homer.
Father?
Gee whiz mother have a heart.
Do you see it Henry?
Could you boost me higher Father?
There is it all that top shelf?
No Father.
Well...
That's a fine thing.
I was positive I saw it out here in the garage.
Gee whiz father what good is a mechanics handbook at a time like this?
It might cover trapezoid.
But Father, do you realize it's past 12?
I realize it, Henry.
I realize it very well.
And we're not going to waste any more time.
What's the name of your math teacher?
Mespenant, why?
We're going straight over to her house
and ask for help.
Mespenant?
Do you think that's why?
Why?
I mean, asking her to see me on a weekend,
considering what she goes through all week.
Henry, come along.
Hey!
Back on the garage, Henry.
Quick!
Mr. Albright!
Father, what's wrong?
Sam, are you out, Mary Beth?
It gets his hands on me, I'll be trapped for the rest of the day.
And they get behind the car.
Sam!
Mr. Olgrich!
Okay, keep down.
Sam!
I'm afraid he isn't out here, Mr. Cleary.
That's strange. He told me he was very anxious to get those books audited.
Mr. Cleary, you don't submit Posey meant for you to meet him at his office, do you?
You think so?
Perhaps you ought to drive down there.
Perhaps I'd better.
Let me close those garage doors for you.
Mr. Cleary, you didn't snap the padlock, did you?
Yes, why?
Well, it's just that the locks got terribly rusty and Mr. Aldridge keeps putting off oiling it.
One of these days we're not going to be able to get it open at all.
No, Gus, I don't have a bitter junk for you today.
"Junk? Oh, didn't you hear Miss Brown? I'm out of the junk business."
"Oh, you are?"
"Yeah, Sheila Mahash, she gave up the ghost."
"She died?"
"No, no, retired. Moved out to the country with some relative."
"Yeah, I got a card from her just the other day."
"She'd gained eight pounds."
"A card?"
"Well, written by a friend, actually."
"Yeah, they say she's starting to eat like a horse again."
"You need any exterminating Miss Brown?"
"Do I need what?"
exterminating. That's my new line. Need any?
Well, none that I think you could handle.
Gus, do you know anything about carpentry?
Carpentry. Yes, sir, above.
I made a nice living at it back in '19, '07.
You did?
Or was it '08?
Gus, could you?
No, no, it was '07, all right.
I remember because William Jennings, or was it 'At Five'?
Gus, the point is,
Do you know anything about trapezoids?
Yeah. Trapezoids.
I just found home a geometry teacher and she's gone skating.
Well, what size trapezoids?
Hmm. Right.
Oh, any size?
Any size?
Miss Brown, you can't build a thing like a trapezoid any size.
We're not going to build it.
No.
And what do you want the carbon to form?
Oh, excuse me, Gus. That's my phone.
Oh, I see an ant here in the corner of the porch.
Of course I just give him a squirt, that's...
Don't bother.
It'll be on the house, Michael.
[DING]
Hello.
And listen, but this is Alice.
Is Will there?
Why, yes, Alice.
Only could you send him over to our house right away.
But he's still in the middle of his shellac.
What?
Alice, what's wrong?
Our car seems to have a short circuit in the horn.
It just keeps blowing and blowing.
Oh, my.
And it's locked in the garage, and Sam's disappeared.
Alice, Gus is here.
Now I'll send him over.
Would you thank you, Elizabeth.
Goodbye.
Gus.
Oh, God.
I got him, Miss Brown, clean his whistle.
Gus, could you?
And about that trapezoid.
Wouldn't you say they was too dangerous to have around anyway?
I saw a man fall off one in the circus one time.
[LAUGHTER]
I'm gonna--
I'm off for peculiar.
Gus, never mind that.
Could you go over to the Aldridge's?
Their car horn is stuck in the garage door's lock.
Oh, sure thing.
Door's locked, huh?
Do you happen to have a rat tail file around?
No, I don't.
A settling torch?
No.
Well, I'll find something to open it with.
Alright, goodbye, Ms. Brown.
Goodbye, guys.
Mother!
Homer, how did you get out of the dining room?
Mother, never mind me, it's Father.
What happened?
We were standing here in the middle of the room, seein'
Father said he couldn't stand being cooped up with me in trapezoids, both, so he did it.
Did what?
He tried to jump from the middle of the dining room to the living room doorway.
Oh, dear.
Can you know what happened?
Of course, he didn't make it.
Mother, that isn't the point.
He was carrying his pot of shellac when he drew it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Henry, do you see Miss Bennett anywhere on the eyes?
Not yet, Father, but I'm keeping my eyes open.
Are you still upset?
Henry, I'd rather not discuss it.
Yes, sir.
But you'd think Gus could have gotten us out of the garage
without breaking down the door with an axe.
Henry, what does Miss Bennett look like?
- Gee, you can't miss her.
She's sort of, well, gee, she's very healthy.
- Healthy, how?
- White in a big way.
- I see.
- Henry, oh, boy, Kathleen.
- So you finally showed up.
Do you realize it's nearly three o'clock?
- And Kathleen, let me explain.
- That's not necessary.
Henry, my interest you to know
that Agnes and I had a wonderful time skating with Charlie
Claus.
- Charlie?
- Yes.
Now if you'll excuse me, I'm going over to see
If Charlie's resting comfortably.
Something happened to him?
Agnes threw him over his shoulder.
And she wasn't there when he came down.
Kathleen listened.
Goodbye, Henry.
But Kathleen?
Never mind, Kathleen Henry.
Look over there.
Is that Miss Bennett?
Where?
Well, gee whiz.
Father, do you think a math teacher should go around
in public doing figure-8s?
Is that what she's doing?
She's trying to.
Miss Bennett?
Oh, Miss Bennett?
Oh, Dad.
I'm Miss Bennett.
Henry, you oldridge, could I please speak to you?
Oh, stop me, Henry, stop me.
Father Quay, I've got you.
Oh, my--
[LAUGHTER]
Thank you very much.
Isn't this fun?
[LAUGHTER]
Miss Bennett.
Henry, I'm like, oh, my own boy, I'm not too steady.
Oh, Miss Bennett, I'm Henry's father.
Oh, how do you do, Mr. Alden?
Would you believe it?
I haven't been on skates in 10 years.
You haven't?
- Thomas Bennett, we have a problem.
- Yes.
- That is Henry has a problem.
That is, well I know it isn't ethical,
but we're sort of stuck on that trapezoid.
- Trapezoid, what trapezoid?
- The one that's our homework for Monday.
- Henry did I give a problem about trapezoid?
- Gee, wait, sure, you wrote it on the blackboard.
- I did.
I haven't taken up trapezoids with the class yet.
(laughing)
- What?
- She hasn't taken it up.
- Oh boy.
- I meant to get into them this past week,
But somehow I just put it up and put it off.
Miss Bennett, do you mean to say?
Do you mean to say--
Mr. Otheletch, you're letting go of my arms.
Father!
Miss Bennett!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Sam.
Yes, Alice?
Are you all right on the couch?
I'm fine.
Is that easy chair comfortable, Henry?
Yes, mother.
Would either of you like another blanket?
No, thank you.
No, thanks, mother.
Well, I just want you both to know
I think it was a very brave thing to do.
Brave?
Yes, pulling Miss Bennet out of the water like that.
We didn't do it to be brave.
Miss Bennet was holding on to us for dear life.
We rescued her in self-defense.
Dear, I know better.
Father, are you really going to take me out of school if Miss Bennet stays at Central High?
I haven't decided.
Sam, don't you think you ought to cool off first?
Alice, I'm as cooled off as I'll ever be.
Incidentally, Sam, did you find out what a trapezoid is?
Yes, Alice. A trapezoid is a...
A trapezoid...
Well, Alice, do you see that lampshade over the dining room table?
The one that sort of tilts?
Yes, that's a perfect example of a trapezoid.
You know father it just occurred to me it's been hanging over our heads all day.
Hey Henry!
Hey Homer!
I've got the fall.
I'm here all the time and here's my geometry book.
Boy Homer, you sure took your time.
I couldn't help but my father and I just got through cleaning off the walls.
The wall?
Boy you should have seen the way his cans flashed when it landed.
[laughter]
Gee Homer.
Homer what's this all over your book?
over your book shall I what you think that's a bad shape you
ought to see my father.
It says it's the first time in his life he got his hair to stay
down.
Mr. Cleary on the phone.
Cleary.
Yes he called to say you weren't at the office either.
Alice what did you tell him?
I told him you were flat on your back.
Good.
So he said not to let you up he'd be right over with the book.
What?
Alice.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Homer.
Homer, stop pushing.
He's pushing him.
You all right?
Choose pushing.
Boy, Homer, are you girl crazy?
She wants somebody new comes to town.
What's wrong with taking a look at it?
Then move over so I can see her, too.
Well, gee, wait.
Okay Henry, who's girl crazy now?
Girl crazy eh?
Well when kids of the age of Henry and Homer, they're all so dessert crazy.
Especially when it's jello coming up.
A treat to look at and a treat to eat in those sex delicious flavors.
Strawberry, raspberry, cherry, orange, lemon and lime.
All sex with that locked in goodness that makes them taste so rich and fruit like.
Cut your jello into shimmering little cubes and pile it into sharpet glasses.
Lake it lightly with a fork and combine with sliced oranges or grapefruit.
Jell-O is America's favorite gelatin dessert.
And you know that name Jell-O is a trademark, the property of general foods,
and tells you you're getting a genuine Jell-O product.
Look for those big red letters on the box.
Those big red letters stand for the Jell-O family.
[MUSIC]
Here's hoping you'll be in your living room and hours next week at the same time.
Good night folks.
The Oldridge family starring Ezra Stone is Henry with Jackie Kelka's Homer.
It's written by Norman Tocar and Ed Juris with music by Jack Miller.
Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich are house Jamison and Catherine Roth.
And this is Dan Seymour in New York saying,
"The Oldridge family is brought to you by the Jell-O family."
Everyone's a jello good fellow
A very good jello good fellow
So rich, so tempting and mellow
J-E-L-L-O
(
This is NBC, the National Broadcasting Company.
(bells ringing)
(piano music)
(bell chimes)
[buzzing]