[Music]
And now the Jell-O family presents Henry, Henry Oldridge. Come here, mother.
[Applause]
Yes, it's the Oldridge family based on characters originated by Flippigold Smith,
and starring Ezra Stone as Henry with Jackie Kelt as Homer. And yes, it's the Jell-O family.
[Music]
Oh, the Big Red Ladder stand for the Jell-O family. Oh, the Big Red Ladder stand for the Jell-O family.
Back Jell-O Union, yeah. Jell-O Pudding, yum, yum, yum. Jell-O Taffy, Oka Pudding, yes, sir.
And now for the Aldrich family.
Right in the middle of everyone's memories, there is always a teenage boy.
And if he's like Henry Aldrich, he is right in the middle of plenty of other things too.
The scene is the Aldrich living room. The time is evening.
Alice! In his sand!
There's the ex-relief for the dining room table.
Why, dear?
I thought I'd have the committee work in there.
And we're going to need lots of room.
Let me see.
The last time I saw that Lee Henry was using it on his bed for a desk.
A desk?
Yes, he was doing his homework.
In bed?
Yeah, that's the place he seems to concentrate this.
I'll ask him what he did with it.
You mean he's still here?
Yes.
I've been trying to get the financial committee together for weeks.
And we'll need all the peace and quiet we can get.
Sam, I give you my word.
Henry will be at the school play where he can't possibly bother you.
Meanwhile, why not sit down?
Of course.
You were all flush.
I'm all right.
I've been married to you long enough to know when you're flush.
Now I remember it's in the whole closet.
What is?
You see how over here did you are?
The leaf for the dining room table.
Mother!
They're waiting!
In here, dear!
Good night, Mother.
Good night, Father.
Good night, Henry.
Turn around.
Let me see how you look.
Mother!
Dear, why are you wearing that old blue tie?
Why didn't you wear that nice one?
Aunt Harriet gave you for Christmas.
The red one.
The red one, mother?
To the theater?
She was, do you want Gladys to think I have no breeding?
No, I suppose it's all right.
Now, do you have your ticket?
She was sure right here.
A hanky?
I've got two of them.
One up here, one down here.
(audience laughing)
Did you tie your money up in it?
Gee, mother, how juvenile do you think I am?
Henry, you've got to learn not to ask leading questions.
What about the pins in your new shirt?
Did you get them all out?
Of course!
Well, check the tails again.
I wouldn't want you to sit on a pin and do it your time.
I give you my word, Mother. There isn't a pin on me.
And boy, I better get going. This is my first date with Gladys.
And I don't want to keep her waiting. Good night, you all.
Drive carefully, dear.
Be sure you've got enough gas.
There's plenty, Father. I checked the car from head to toe this afternoon.
I even washed it.
Alice, was that our son?
My goodness, he certainly seemed to have everything in hand, didn't he?
Doesn't that please you?
I'm not sure.
What?
I mean, Sam, he doesn't seem to need us anymore.
You'll always need his allowance.
Yes, I'm serious. He's growing up.
It was inevitable, Alice. It's nothing to cry about.
I'm not crying. It's just...
Am I? Feel like I've suddenly lost my little boy.
Mother!
Look at this.
Henry, what's wrong?
I choose one of where are my shoes?
No, what?
I choose! I ran out of the house in my bedroom.
They must be up in your room.
Oh, boy.
Don't run, dear. You're losing your trousers.
She was, did I forget my belt, too?
You better check everything again.
Yes, mother and while I'm doing that would you please look up Gladys's address in the phone book?
I never asked for work. You were
Alice it looks like your little boy had come back
Is this the well-being and sure Gladys and I certainly want to apologize boy
I never realized roe X was way back here
You don't know as a matter of fact. I understand this is a play you want to see from the spa back is possible
So we go to what's sure?
Seventh and eight seats in
Would you excuse us, please?
Excuse us. Oh, oh, hi Cynthia. Excuse us. Oh my goodness. Can we look what's right in front of me?
Oh boy, where did that pole come from?
I'm glad you take my seat.
I can really see fine if I just tell you a little.
Gee, what is glad I said?
I couldn't have you tilted on our first day.
We wouldn't be polite.
Let's change.
Alright.
May I have my program now, please?
Your program?
Oh boy, how did I forget that?
Excuse me, I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
Oh, oh hi Cynthia.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Safe, Charlie, did I have two programs please?
Sure, I'm here, thanks.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Oh, excuse me, Emily.
Oh, she was Cynthia, did I get you again?
Excuse me, excuse me.
Hair gliders.
Thank you Emily.
- Hey, hey, hey.
(laughing)
- Well, anyway.
- Who's that?
- Homer Brown.
Boy, some people never grow up.
- What do you mean?
- Imagine yelling all over a public place like that.
Boy, I certainly want to apologize for her.
- I don't mind that, I think it's cute.
- Cute?
Homer Brown, cute?
- Isn't that a nice nice guy you're wearing?
- That red one, yes.
Did you know that red's my favorite color?
Well, do you, where?
I mean, I didn't see all this for getting ready to stop the overture.
Could I have my purse, please?
Your purse?
You mean I have?
Didn't I give it to you just before we left my house?
Well, do you, where's no?
Oh, my goodness.
I must have left it on the whole table.
What am I going to do?
I don't think anyone will steal it, Gladys.
Oh, would you be a beer and hop into your car and run home for us?
Now?
And my purse.
I don't have my hat, did you?
And I understand this is a very sad place.
Well, I wouldn't mind letting you want to mind.
Yeah.
I've got one up here and one down here.
[LAUGHTER]
Yeah, I'll get you to help.
Oh, you missed it.
What's that?
That's my first time.
But glad as you won't need more lipstick
until I take you home.
[LAUGHTER]
That's why, if you must know my glasses are in the purse.
Glasses?
[LAUGHTER]
Thank you, Dr. Shout.
Well, as you, Gladys, I didn't know you needed glasses.
I don't.
I just wear them to keep my mother happy.
suppose we don't tell your mother
you don't have to be miserable all evening
look glad it's very well
but i'm thinking about how you feel about me early in our friendship
but glad it's not even
well that is naturally
well if it's that important i'd be
glad to get to your purse
tell me i knew you were a gentleman
and you'll have a back phone
sure because i'll be awfully lonely without you
oh boy
i'll be back before you know it
Excuse me.
The present on the whole table.
You sure?
Excuse me?
Excuse me.
Ouch!
Hi, Henry.
Boy, Willie, boy, a fine parking attendant you are.
What the hell are you stop blaming it on me?
Who else can I blame it on?
She was looking at all the cars parked in front of mine.
I parked everybody's car as they came in.
What'd you come to early for?
To avoid trouble.
Get me out, will we?
Get me out.
I will.
Just as soon as I study the situation.
Listen, I have to go all the way back for Gladys' glasses
and the play's going to start any minute.
And we must have known Elton hired me
to take charge of a parking lot,
and I'm not going off half-cost.
Now, the way I figure it, all I have to do
is move this mask back and that's cheap out,
and then you can slip your car through the space.
I can?
I'll move it. Keep an eye on my rear.
Willy, if you ask me.
I know what I'm doing.
Out of my back bumper.
Fine.
I'm clearing back.
Sure.
Here I come.
He was coming.
Keep on coming.
Oh boy.
Everybody had a puppy that was clearing back.
You are?
Was your front bumper that had...
Pull up.
Holy moly, all this!
What's wrong now?
The bumper's a lot.
They are?
Well, what do you know?
We'll just don't stand there, will we do some?
Let's not move our heads, Ken.
All I have to do is move that today and up front and we'll have a whole thing with it.
And, Willie, that's crazy.
If you're going to move anything, it should be this red convertible.
Henry, you're the one who's crazy.
It's a sedan.
The convertible!
Listen, Henry, are you insinuating I don't know the parking business?
[Music]
Now, where were we, gentlemen?
Right in the middle of fiscal expenses, Mr. Audrey.
Oh, yes.
Shouldn't we wait until Ferguson gets back?
Mr. Harris, this statement has to be ready for the meeting tomorrow.
Why did Ferguson have to go to the school anyway?
It seems, Mr. Kilmer, he left his car to his son,
and now his bumpers are locked with another car.
Well, that couldn't take very long.
Yes, but before they can straighten that out, they have to get the rest of the parking lot untangled.
I think we better go on without it.
Yes, I suppose so.
Now, I think the best way to start is to figure out our asset.
Asset?
Mr. R.W.E.S. we don't have any assets.
The club is 250 in the red and everyone knows it.
I know, Mr. Head.
I make a motion.
We just make up a report chain.
We owe $250 and not worry the club about how it happened.
Oh, Mr. Head.
I second the motion.
How about some bridge?
Now Mr. Kilburn!
Listen, Henry, what's the idea of calling me out of the auditorium in a time like this?
I had to, Homer.
But screaming, kitten, just playing the old aunt, and I think she's just about to get murdered.
But Homer...
I've been looking forward to that since the curtain went up.
But Homer, I can't get my car out of the parking lot. I'll have to take a street car.
This is the first date I've had with her.
What?
Homer, don't you understand?
The only part I got was you have a date with a streetcar.
[Laughter]
Now, Homer, with Gladys Prentice,
so won't you please do me a favor and sit with her?
Me?
So she won't be lonesome.
Nothing doing him.
What a home, brother.
I saw that pole right in front of your seat.
Pole?
There's a pole there?
You know, dying well.
Come on, hardly even noticed it.
That's how infotecimal it is.
- It's been tassel, it's been tassel, huh?
- Oh!
- And she was, if you lean a little,
you hardly know it's there.
- Oh no, when I get off balance, I get a headache.
- Look, is it worth a quarter to your mouth?
- 50 cents.
- 50?
- Well, she was, you should be willing to have
a little headache for that kind of money.
- Okay, I'll do it.
- Gee, thanks Homer.
- 75.
- Now listen!
- Can we eat a headache in the polar worth at least 75 cents?
- But that hardly leaves me enough for sodas.
Okay, Henry, step aside.
Where are you going?
Back to my seat and watch thing be.
Get there, Lynn.
Okay, okay, okay.
Here's your 75 cent.
Hey.
So glad us I'll be back before she knows.
Okay.
Yes, Mr. and Dr. Isaki.
Yes, Ms. Hotchkiss.
She's been learning.
Well, she was already.
I better inspect the body.
Excuse me, can I get in this row?
Thanks.
Excuse me.
Oh, so high Cynthia.
Sam, I feel terribly guilty about having to leave.
Yes, yes, of course.
But I'm sure you and Mr. Kilmer can appreciate my position.
After all, you have children of your own.
Yes, but couldn't Mrs. Harris take the saddle shoes down to your daughter, Cynthia?
I have the car, Mr. Ahrich.
Oh, oh yes.
Yes, but I'm certainly going to speak very sharply to Cynthia about interrupting our meeting like this.
I was against her wearing open toe shoes from the start.
Well, if you must go, you must.
Well, and if I don't come my bet, I may not.
No, no, we won't.
Good night.
Mr. Aldrich, I've just finished heading up those figures.
Yes.
And according to my addition, we have $194 in the bank.
What?
That's impossible. We have a deficit.
I know. I must have gone all somewhere.
Let me see those figures.
a year. Mr. Kilmer you've added our membership to our assets. I have my mind.
Oh boy. Excuse me. Hey fellow what do you think you're going into the auditorium?
Have I missed much? Only the first act. Let me see you take it. Take it you already
took it. Me? Well maybe not you but somebody took it. Look fella try and know
When you're the third guy who's tried that excuse tonight.
Well, but it isn't any excuse my girls inside waiting for me.
Yeah, and Rolex.
Now I know you're a gay crush.
You've arisen an empty seat in that row.
Well, she were naturally homers in it.
Look, I have strict orders not to let anyone in without a ticket
and that's that, so stand back.
But she was, I sold more tickets for this drunk lady
than anyone in school, ask Mercedes.
She knows I had a ticket.
Mercedes isn't here.
What? At a time--
Look, fellow, why not stop trying to be a welter
and give me a dollar and I'll sell you a ticket?
But she was only half left as 50 cents.
Well, can't you borrow the rest?
Barmer?
Sure.
Well, that's an idea.
Could you loan me 50 cents?
No, wait a minute.
Well, I just purchased that.
Oh, that's just it, my girl.
Since she can't see a thing without her.
Well, why not see if she's got as much as a dollar in there?
Open Gladys's purse?
Sure, girls always carry get mad money.
Oh, I couldn't.
Why not?
She might get mad.
Besides, what would she think of my character?
Listen, it'll just be a loan, will it?
It is as though you won't pay a back loan.
- No. - Well, okay.
Stand back while I open it.
You see any money?
- Not yet.
- Could you hold a few of these things?
- No. - Okay.
Here's your comb, notebook, glasses,
library card, key chain, compact.
A map!
Left glove, hanky, another glove, left the right.
A laugh!
How about money?
I think I hear something rattling near the bottom.
Here's her mirror mending tape needle and
thrift lifesavers.
What flavor?
He's gone.
That's glottishes all over everything.
Flipping.
Oh boy.
Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
So let's think.
Just roll under the auditorium door.
I told you,
fella.
You don't go in there without a ticket.
Now listen, fella.
Listen yourself, fella.
[Music]
Oh! The Big Red Letter stands for Evigello Family.
That's Jello. Yum, yum, yum.
Jello Pudding's, yum, yum, yum.
Jello Tack, Bianca Pudding's Yes or Weeee!
Yes, and there are dozens and dozens of swell treats you can make with the Jello family of yum-yum desserts.
And here's a grand new combination to surprise the folks with tomorrow.
Maple Nut Tapioca, made with Luscious Light and Mellow Jello Vanilla Tapioca pudding.
Just prepare a package of Jello Vanilla Tapioca as usual.
Then chill and serve with log cabin syrup, topped with chopped nut meat, sauteed in a little butter.
It's a wonderful dessert. Delicious Jello Vanilla Tapioca, with tangy maple syrup and crunchy nut meats.
Try all three jello tapioca puddings.
Jello chocolate, vanilla, and orange coconut tapioca.
They're ready prepared.
All you do is add milk and they take about five minutes to cook.
Look for 'em on your grocery's dessert shelf.
Jello tapioca pudding.
(dramatic music)
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Oldridge.
Henry left the performance of the school play
in order to get Gladys's purse. But when he returned he couldn't get back in without
his ticket. Meanwhile he is hired Homer to sit with Gladys and keep her company. The
scene opens in the auditorium just as the second act is ending.
Hello? What's this?
Inspector, is it a clue?
Yes, Miss Hotchkiss. A very... a very vital clue.
vital crew and if this doesn't lead us to the killer my name isn't Inspector
Hornblow of Scotland Yard.
[applause]
Oh my goodness, that would be the most knowing that in the first time.
Did you really enjoy it, Gla?
No, I did. I guess I grabbed your arm a couple of times, didn't I, Homer?
Gee, I didn't mind.
Would you like to go out to the hall for another glass of water?
No, I don't think so.
That's good.
Boy, did that Cynthia Harris step on my toe the last turn?
I wonder where Henry is.
Henry?
Henry Aldrich.
Aren't you worried about him?
Well, it wouldn't be very polite to be worried, you think?
It wouldn't.
No, it wouldn't mean I wasn't having a good time with you.
Oh.
You know who I are?
What's that I seem to be?
Gee.
Gee, it's suddenly gotten warm in here.
Oh, I was thinking it was getting a little chewy.
Yeah?
Would you like my jacket?
Oh, I couldn't deprive you.
Gee, I don't mind.
Well, suppose I just follow a part of it.
A par?
They just agreed.
Oh, I'll tell you. I don't think my folks will be too happy if I tore it off.
Oh, goodness, you're cute.
I am.
Hey, you just let us put you on around my shoulders. I wouldn't be so dressed.
Oh. Oh.
How's that?
Much better.
Oh, my goodness, whoa!
Where?
I got window and back there. See those two hands on the ledge?
She was a must be some guy trying to sneak in that way.
What's that in her hand?
Well, I'll be doing it.
Grattice it isn't a fellow, it's a girl.
It is.
Sure, that's a personal left hand.
Well, my goodness, isn't that disgraceful?
There goes a janitor after her.
What's he doing with that window, Paul?
Oh boy, he's gonna let her have it right on the knuckle.
I swear to the ouch!
[laughter]
Oh, I give it to him.
She's doing hands disappear so fast.
Oh, right.
Yes, Grattice.
Did you know you took your arm away?
I did.
Yes, and it's getting very chilling again.
Graddish, don't you think it would be a good idea if I went back to my own seat?
Why Homer?
I mean, she was Henry's my best friend and he did pay for your ticket.
Well, you're doing him a favor.
I am.
Certainly. He wants me to have a good time, doesn't he?
Yes, but...
Well, I've been miserable sitting alone.
Sure, but...
Homer, please put your arm back where it was. I'm freezing.
But...
Homer...
How's that?
Mmm, that's better.
Oh boy, am I a heel?
Willie, where are you? Right in front of you, Henry.
Boy, this basement is dark.
Are you sure we can get into the orchestra pit this way?
Sure.
When I played the tube in the school orchestra, I used to sneak out this way all the time.
Boy, my suit must be a wreck. I fell right off that window sill into a thorn hedge.
Hold it.
But we turn here.
Willie, are you sure?
Positive. I memorize the space-ment like a book.
You do?
You throw when you're carrying a tube, but you can't be too careful.
[laughter]
Come on.
Gee, Willie, I certainly want to thank you for helping me out like this.
Well, that's okay, Henry. After all, I was responsible for tying up your car.
What did Mr. Nelson say when he fired you?
I wasn't exactly fired. I retired by mutual agreement.
Did he at least get paid?
Well, I'll tell you the truth, Henry. I didn't think I ought to press that point.
Especially since the fire department had to come over and help untangle those cars.
A hold it, Henry. What's the matter? We should be almost to the door of the orchestra pit.
Where? Well, feel along the wall on your side for a pipe.
What for? It was right to the door. Oh.
Feel around. Okay. Did you find it?
Well, he was at a steam pipe. Yeah, I found it.
Well, keep following it and go forward. Sure.
When you get to the orchestra pit, sneak in behind Agnes' lost in space.
Okay. Well, let's be quiet, huh?
Henry, you're not something over?
No shovels.
- Kelly, half a dozen of them. - That's funny.
I don't remember those being there last winter.
- Willie, you mean we're lost? - Well, not exactly.
I just don't know where we are. - No.
- What is it my fault, Henry?
This is the first time I've come through here without my tuba.
- [music playing]
- You said you. Can't you tell me who murdered my ass?
- Miss Hotchkiss, I think you'll be walking through that door.
That door in a moment. All right, men, scatter.
Oh, my goodness, I'm dying. I'm just dying.
Have you ever seen the mark?
I'm dying.
She also am so excited, my tozer curl.
Yes, doctor. I hear someone.
Quickly turn out the lights and careful men,
he may be armed.
Oh, man, you terrified of my hair.
Hold this. How's that?
My goodness, coat hands warm up.
She was a pretty cold yourself.
- Well, but you better keep out the door.
(sighing)
- I'm your toes man.
- Oh my God, look, the door's out there.
- It's your murder.
- What are you doing?
Who is this?
- I don't know.
- Will you are you sure this is the door to the orchestra?
(crowd laughing)
- Well, instead of murder it sounds familiar.
- All right, men, glad it.
(crowd laughing)
- Hey!
- No way!
- You've come to the end of your road.
- Now listen, you guys, I pay for my ticket,
and I'm coming in.
(audience laughing)
- Now, Sam, calm down.
- I am calm, Alice.
It's just that after all these years it hurts
to find out I've missed Judge Ralph Kilmer, so complete.
- Now, dear baby, you had a good reason for leaving.
- Good reason?
His excuse was he had to go to the school auditorium
and take his daughter home.
- Yeah, that doesn't sound unreal.
- Because you've got another attack of our hiccups
from laughing at the school play?
- Laughing, I thought it was a serious drama.
Exactly, certainly could have thought of a better excuse.
Fine meeting, Ferguson runs out, then Harry, now a cure-mer.
Well, there's one thing to be said, you certainly can't blame Henry.
Well, that's something.
Why, good is that, couldn't be Henry, it's only 10.30.
Henry, is that you?
Yes, Mother, it's sigh.
Here, come in here, please.
Mother, if you don't mind, I'd like to go right up to bed.
Yeah, are you home a little early?
Are we?
Is the playover already?
ready? Well, you might say it ended a little unexpectedly. Oh, I see. Incidentally,
be in this Eddie phone this evening. She did. And she was so pleased about your
selling all those tickets. She has a little surprise for you. Surprise. Yes,
she's going to see that you get a part in the next place. Me? Yes, there isn't that
night. Well, I'll tell your mother. And naturally, I appreciate it, but I've
suddenly lost all interest in appearing on the stage. You have. Yeah, all you do is get up there and
make a fool of yourself. Oh my goodness, I'm going in and make you a glass of hot milk with
butter. On top of everything else I'd go on through. Henry, please answer the phone. Who I?
Father, suppose it's a member of the cast. Answer it, Henry. I have to finish this report. But they
They bring her for three months.
Oh boy.
Hello.
Hi, Hannah, old timer.
Homer, is that you?
Sure.
What they do to you after they roll down the curtain.
I'd rather not say.
Henry, it isn't as bad as that.
They promised to print who the murderer was in the school paper next week.
Homer, what about Gladys?
Wait, that's where I'm calling from.
I just took her home.
You did?
Well, you tell her I'll bring her her purse over there the first thing in the morning.
Okay, Dan.
When the optometrist promised to have her glasses fixed by three o'clock tomorrow.
Something happened to them?
In a way, Homer.
They somehow came into contact with a window pole.
So am I.
And Homer.
Homer is Gladys very mad.
Mad.
Because I wasn't with her all evening.
Well, she doesn't seem very mad.
She doesn't?
No.
As a matter of fact, she said she had a wonderful time.
We'll cut it out, Gladys.
That too.
What's that?
Oh boy.
Oh, boy. Homer, what's going on? Nothing, and nothing. Only Henry. Yes? I just want you to know you've got a 75 cent refund coming to you.
[music]
Oh, I went up to make a new grassy certain party I know turned out to be.
Snake and the grass, Agnes, are you referring to good old home?
I'll say I am.
What Agnes, you're talking about my best pal?
Your best pal, your best pal.
Oh, sure.
Oh, okay.
Then what was your best pal doing with his arm?
I'm glad it's all he knew.
She was so, that's what happened.
Boy, what a snake and the grass.
Well, sometimes that's the way it goes with the best of friends.
But ladies, when it comes to desserts,
Here's one that never lets you down.
Jello tapioca puddings, a miracle of goodness,
a marvel of speed.
Jello tapioca puddings are ready prepared,
nothing to go wrong.
All you do is add milk,
and they take just about five minutes to cook.
There's Jello vanilla tapioca, luscious light and mellow.
Jello chocolate tapioca, rich and candy good.
Jello orange coconut tapioca,
tangy orange with rich tropical coconut.
Jello tapioca puddings,
three delicious new reasons why more women by jello puttings than any other
prepared puttings in the world
more
you'll be in your living room and hours next week at the same time
the
the older family starring as the stonest Henry was jackie kelter's home
is written by namato car and ed joris
The music by Jack Miller.
Mr. and Mrs. Olridge, our house, Jameson and Catherine Roth.
And this is Dan Seymour in New York saying,
"The Olridge family is brought to you by the Jell-O family."
(upbeat music)
♪ Oh, the big red letters stand for the Jell-O family ♪
♪ That's Jell-O, yum, yum, yum ♪
♪ Jell-O, pudding, yum, yum, yum ♪
♪ Jell-O, tats, the och, a pudding, yes, sorry ♪
New as new as a whole boat of banker's convention.
Amazing, the only one of its kind.
That's minute rice.
Minute rice for magically quick, quick meals.
No washing, rinsing, draining or steaming with minute rice.
Just drop it in water and bring to a boil.
Absolutely no more cooking needed.
Minute rice is quicker to fix than potatoes, and it always comes out perfect.
You'll think of scores of wonderful, one-dish meals with minute rice.
So remember the name minute, minute rice in the red, white and blue box.
Ladies and gentlemen, stay tuned in for Alan and Ben.
Gracie, it's Burns and Alan. They built me first.
They do?
Sure.
Oh, and I'll have the deal for now. You have sent to you.
Ladies and gentlemen, stay tuned to Alan and Burns, next on NBC.
(bells ringing)
(gentle music)