[SOUND]
[LAUGHTER]
Thank you.
Help me, always.
Come here, Evan.
That is the headless family.
That's the headless family.
And now, for the older family.
[LAUGHTER]
[Music]
The trouble of the semelordic consider is this doesn't think one fellow is still girls with sort of a club.
If you guys come down to my little house and you know what this is, how could you get another fellow to your little house?
Well, how about this?
Oh, you mentioned that guy, he's your best friend.
Oh, Homer.
That's it, what's he like?
Oh, uh, these are 12 kids.
You good, little kid?
I'm 12 kids.
They're all trouble with these people over to have a city with his family to visit his uncle Oscar.
Oh, that's extraordinary.
Well, what about your mother's born?
That's good, your mother's born.
Excuse me, a second, mother's. I think she's in the kitchen problem.
Thank you.
Father's, I'll tell you what. You were hanging out with the lucky phone around with some of the guys right now.
Oh, yes.
I thought these were down town.
I'm about to, but first, do you have enough clothes for me, again?
What?
You?
Oh, yes.
Now are you doing it? Gotcha. How's he? Oh, cool. What are you? Money. Have you got the mention of money and clothes? Tell me what's gotten in here. I don't think I'm going to come to town. I've been happy with the best client I've got. I just want to be honest. I'm going to have any. I should be screaming here for me. Why would I be there? I open myself up. That's why I don't have any. I don't want you to hold me down there.
I thought you were going to visit your uncle after.
That's why I was talking.
You like to save my life.
I better talk to my mother together.
No, I get to have to tell.
There you go.
Me bring an operator somebody in this town that's being offered.
Hey, where are you with?
Is that a moment?
That's a moment.
I thought you were going to visit your uncle after.
That's why I was talking.
You like to save my life.
So, can you tell her who's got something very urgent to do today?
You mean you don't want to go to your uncle or uncle?
Well, certainly my uncle. It's my cousin, Hipsabaw.
Every time I go over there, she makes a million wrestling.
I send half my time on the floor.
You're doing it, old pal.
Well, I'm hoping you're all wild. I'd be tickled to.
And as a matter of fact, we have got something very urgent to do.
We have a lot.
Well, how would you like to go on a well-daked protection now?
I guess I didn't have a chance to tell you about this. Well, girl, I met the other night. The name is Bubbles. Bubbles? What kind of a name is Rob? What's Roblin? Nothing. Your package is self-placed.
Well, it happens to bigger personality, exactly. Anyway, I've got to date with her for the second now. And I'm a little isolated.
Well, she has a sister thing.
Now wait a minute.
You hold on.
I'm going to just let her out with anybody's sister and that's all.
I'll tell her everybody is somebody's sister.
I'm not.
Wait a minute.
You like to see a picture of her?
Okay.
It was taken up a camp hocal as Johnny.
It's their whole camp.
Now look here.
Oh, you're so old.
Oh my, you're looking at the lifeguard.
(laughing)
Look, look, look, look, will you hear
right under the "oh" when Poco was shot?
Uh huh.
Good.
Sometimes call it a sense of humor.
What do you mean?
Let's see right around and get him under the "ee" too.
(laughing)
No, no, that's your sister.
No, it's the same girl.
Oh, can I mention that?
I'm answering her all.
Well, hold you there, sister, or a twin.
Oh.
She's five lines.
Yeah.
What do you say?
So let me ask you how to touch your gun.
This is mine right here.
It's cool.
Have you got a night and a time ago?
Oh boy.
Come on, I called a chicken or coke.
Too many times to take chances.
(audience laughs)
Yes, Bobbie.
You'll love your little one, please.
I'm home, but you just keep looking at that picture.
Okay, but you'll say,
"That's cool, make it a little bit of a film."
Let's see him there.
Yes, Bobbie.
Better do you have your little arm.
Sure, Bobbie, do you need some clag?
(audience laughs)
I just want to be sure that you have no reason for trying to get in touch with me.
What are your plans?
Well, if I can get a moment, a listen to reason, we've got a date to go walking down town with a couple of girls.
On a nice day like this, well, how are you? I'd have the girls, I'd be like, "Oh, they're not into the country."
Well, definitely. And she holds a dollar for a couple of years, so that's expensive.
Well, team, team, thanks, Father.
This is a kind of reason in how my understand.
Oh, and guess what I've got?
Well, now I think you'll think things differently.
You're trying to make me try and go?
That would very nice of you.
Uh-huh.
Oh, well, I'd like to see the boy.
You cannot be the owner.
You know what I mean?
Oh, of course.
And if you buy the plug,
then you can't bother me.
I'll breathe in your pool.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Is this your bye time friend here?
Well, I'll tell you a little bit.
Why don't I go up by myself, Bertie?
Sort of place the ground.
What do you mean?
Well, don't you think it's better if we
stem the sister adjusted to the IBM?
The IBM law of you?
Oh, just wait a minute.
I think I should film my girls now, I think.
You think you're high, well you're gonna put yourself together.
Well, be with my dog!
There he is.
What's wrong?
That one is trying to shoot.
I mean, the first impression is that you don't mean a thing.
You know what I'm asking for?
We need about the most generous person I know.
And, Angela, you said your sister was pretty desperate to make some noise.
You're not so desperate.
Well, you made out here while I was a little careful, Bubbles.
You were not Bubbles? No, I'm too.
But it's just me, the Bubbles, wait. I mean, I'm too. You got the help.
Oh, boy.
Hey, what's going on in your?
You're in.
What did you tell about me?
Why, um, nothing.
You are?
I was actually sorry, huh?
[inaudible]
Oh, my God, I'm going to do that.
Not yet.
What do you think of them, Bobo?
I'm always going to do this at that time.
So you're going to do anything I want.
Get straight to it.
How about us getting your bites out now, Bobo?
Okay, then you can add.
So do what you want.
What I'm going to do is you're going to go,
I think I'll go and get over to you.
You can do it too.
Yes, in many ways.
You look like my dumbest friend.
In what way?
What?
You're going to have to do it at an imagination.
Now just to say, if mommy is a little age,
You know, you have no way to look at your ears.
I thought you were going to throw the things out then
so you have to make one little talk about your ears.
I don't know if you have any rather amount of time.
You will, and the next time you wear it,
I'll be a little drama.
You know what I'm saying?
Well, alright.
Oh, well, I'm good.
Oh, sorry, you must say, "Hey, what happened?"
I saw you in your lunchroom,
and then in back of the garage,
to hear me, "Well, we should get up,
"and we're gonna call."
Look at me driving!
No, we just, it couldn't leave me, right?
We found out.
But if you have a job, we could lift the whole rear end up
and get the wheelbar out from under the muffler.
And a little more, we can lift it
and get the garage door back there.
Oh, my goodness, oh my goodness!
[Music]
The 912 backyard you have here, baby, so...
From...
[Music]
This is puffing your father off of all his parents.
I'm fine. I can't hear you, sister. I'm so all bent to you. How long have you feel about school? Oh, I don't know. But just the way I can go. How do you think I'm going to say those things? I don't know. You're right, too.
I'm sure.
You got any movies tonight? Oh, everyone's name.
Can I tell you what I'm doing, and I need to listen to the dog now.
Oh, I need to listen to the dog now. Oh, I need to listen to the dog now.
Oh, boy.
[inaudible]
My goodness, he's still talking to you.
Yeah, he keeps taking a muckler who is on the wheelbarrow.
[inaudible]
What's the matter?
I don't want to go in that town.
What's wrong with it?
She doesn't say anything.
You want to make anything you say?
Who lives in a million the one that talks when losing with the right firepoint?
So what difference will it make? There's just a couple of things in the pond.
Absolutely not.
Oh, Daddy, you go back to my outside!
Okay, Bubbles.
I'm like a child. You can't even tell we can build a pond.
Right? And how?
Well, we're all looking at them. One of them's next door.
So you look to her, much more what?
I don't know, but the other one's next door.
[Laughter]
Why can't I tell you a little while?
What did your father say, girl?
He said, "You might have his mind here,
but he really does.
You guys wouldn't leave everything I'd wear here."
But what about your bike?
Well, my sister and I were just told,
if you didn't mind, we could keep tribes with one of you.
Oh.
That's a cool idea.
Okay.
You lied with me.
No, wait a minute.
Go on.
I'm good with you, come see.
Go.
Listen, Homer.
Go ahead and follow me.
My right, when you come out of the ground, I'm coming.
Listen, I hope you're not mad at my husband this way.
What, you know?
You know, you know, I don't see it.
I just like to know what you've got to make my family close.
That's right.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
[Music]
here. I thought it was a great gentleman. I'd like to tell this night about the march with the
[ Inaudible ]
>> Oh, wow.
>> Not my name.
>> Oh, the other one.
It's here to the brilliant girl.
And I'm going to get a fire hydrant.
>> Is it the one that would be?
>> No.
>> What's that?
>> The hydrant.
The hydrant.
That's my department.
>> No.
>> The mother was, you know,
Mr. Satt,
and he was not the master.
Go ahead with his next one.
>> I don't know.
That was what I'm on overtime.
I think it's a radical war commitment to take care of.
Oh, no, no, that's the fighter part.
It says when I hide from some of the furniture.
All I know is I'm getting a fighter.
It's like a title.
I'm dying that time.
Go, I never die.
And I'm going to take serious consciousness.
And if you're a mid-to-land, could you mind reading outside?
Because I'm a mid-to-land man.
I'm a mid-to-land man.
[Music]
I know, I've got to get back to the company, but I'm really good.
You're living the same way, and the three of us,
and the three of us, and the three of us,
just outside of the building.
Now I think this is your love,
it's such an evening, I'm dreaming, I'm dreaming.
Well, it's something, I'm dreaming,
well, isn't it, how am I?
Oh, uh, oh, I've got a perfectly wonderful idea.
After my father took her age, I just love to embrace.
After all, you're a wonderful idea.
Oh, what do you think of this?
We have plenty of opportunity.
And we're all my stuff in it.
I'm going to do something of questions.
Oh, hey, that's a very good idea.
Helping things?
Come on, wait.
Right now if you and I go back to the bikes and get so much
Hey what boys I'm done checking in at questions
You mean you fell in line
I'm fine, how are you doing now?
I'm doing a week ago
I'm not going home
You know even when I'm not even lunch alone
I don't play in school and that's not goodbye
But we have stopped jumping up a little like that
You don't have to eat with friends
Sing an I will
And I can hear the bubbles sure
What's wrong with her?
[laughter]
On the hard-wearing side, you know,
"Dilow, the cantile and the pardon
"not only that suck with transceling them,
"you know, that's the way to tell them apart."
"Hm, island of Kiple?"
[laughter]
"Bubble did wearing a red cross,
"but my favorite, didn't it?"
"Oh, okay, lady!"
"Which one is that?"
"Why don't you get some little closer?"
"Hello there, uh, Bubbles?"
"If you give me the nice little ten,
I was a deputy man.
- Are you sure?
- I think you can hear me.
- Say, that red cross button looks nice on that sweater.
- So, how about you and Lucy the rogerling?
- Oh, this is a nice one.
- And, well, there were a rumor in front of me.
- See that tree out on top of the hill?
- Okay.
- Let's see what I'm gonna do.
- You know, just a little bit.
- All right.
- I will meet right here in the background.
- Okay.
- I'm so sorry.
- It's a little bit more fun.
I'm a better brother than a cop, but I'm so nervous.
I'm so nervous.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[LAUGHTER]
Hey, what are you doing up here?
We had to pay for these, and I noticed.
I know.
I know I was supposed to be down there with bubbles,
but Homer wanted to be with it for a while, so I--
[INAUDIBLE]
I'm looking up mad at you.
Take your what?
Oh, yes, it's a bomb.
Okay.
Follow me.
What's the trouble?
What a little bit of a zombie.
She's very nice.
Very nice.
Well, of course, when it comes to look,
there isn't much to do between them.
But those are those little bitches of technology?
Oh, no, I think she has a nice one.
Although there is no way she could improve it.
I'm sure you're not going to be able to do that.
I'm sure you're going to be able to do that.
You don't have to follow me, Homer.
He was a devil.
He wouldn't know he better than to touch you, Mr. Deere.
Oh boy, but don't you remember the whole thing was not out here.
Oh, it's not!
Sure you see, I just want to give Homer a break.
You mean a break to me, is that it?
No, from Francine.
I'm Francine.
Don't you remember your bubble?
Don't you think you'll get to the party, Bobo?
You mean you can't tell yourself the party?
No, I mean...
But no, you couldn't be because...
Well don't you remember you were sitting here asking me all about your... I mean... Oh, oh.
[audience laughter]
If you remember, it's a long work I asked to do.
So if you've had any idea that you weren't friends,
then we all get to try and tell them to tell them to double it.
And you know, let me talk about that.
Your family is not telling a cow!
[audience laughter]
Oh boy!
They're in her mind!
Well, but please, well, say it is our own sausage when all the women...
[cheering]
Well, anyway, I'm glad you're cold.
I'm over five, bang.
No, just sitting here going over the steam catalog.
Oh, he's not good enough, bang.
Although, so, while there's really nothing going,
Yeah. Oh, 105. And of course I don't need to say it. You didn't get a bit of milk or that lot.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Hi, did you see what's up to go on? Oh, no, no.
You just said to read a good sentence, Lord.
No, I mean, someone wants to go on.
Don't do a whole thing, Lord.
Yeah.
You can't be not a little person, but I'm sure it is.
What's wrong with that?
[inaudible]
We could say that from him.
What happened?
Call us, say to him, "I know you know what some other people are.
"So go down around this environment.
"You have any role.
"What do you do?
"Go down.
"And I'll go down there too.
"Do you say you have to go to my garden?
"Do you have to go to my garden?
"Do you have to go and call?
I just had to bond. I'm gonna back in.
You know, I'm just kidding.
Can't you just tell me how many people you've been in?
Oh, boy!
How many?
Anything longer?
Ladies, you know what I'm doing?
Can you just tell me?
Really?
Hold on a minute, Emmy.
I made that scene for you.
I'm upset about why.
Well, I know you've been in the confusion.
Please, I know you've been in the confusion.
Ladies, I know you've been in the confusion.
But I think you said you'd be willing.
Let me say, hello, Emmy.
I'll call you back.
Call your back.
Where is this thinking?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, now let's set it down in the minimum.
Uh, Mr. Allman, come the way back here.
I mean, come to a dream that we all owe you an apology.
That's technically all right.
Absolutely all right.
That's your job.
Yeah.
Well, no Mr. Allman.
Oh, thank you.
I'd like to begin by telling you a little story.
You know, perhaps I better just skip that part.
You know, I'd like to begin by telling you a little story.
Do you ever have to have that?
I'd better just skip that part.
You know, I'd like to begin by telling you a little story.
Do you ever have to have that?
I'd better just skip that part.
You know, I'd like to begin by telling you a little story.
Do you ever have to have that?
I'd better just skip that part.
You know, I'd like to begin by telling you a little story.
Do you ever have to have that?
I'm going to break my head to the boat.
I'm going to need all the men to lay our hands on.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Just a little more, Homer.
A little more to the top.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
A little more.
(screaming)
Okay, come on boy, come on inside, oh,
(sighing)
here's where the girl, alright, here's the,
oh boy, here we are, oh boy,
you're going to go, come back with all the lights,
go, hey, girl, what's up, fine friend,
oh he's gonna get home now, come on,
we can touch the knees, we'll cut right across the pond
here and head them all down below.
Slow your car, of course now, walk across,
while I'm looking at the slides,
we can make it across the nose rocks,
Come on, easy, huh?
It's good, well, it takes good time.
I don't know if I can find some actual
potential you can just follow me.
Okay, see? It's easy.
(screaming)
Hang on, I'm having enough trouble.
Hold on 'til I get, okay, let's go.
(screaming)
Hold on, hold on!
Oh, boy.
(screaming)
and to bring some name and talk of the class.
You know I'm a long-term slowly.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
All right, now hold.
Good evening, Tom.
You let me have a hug.
Thank you, Alice.
Thanks you very much.
On the straight-on, maybe a little late is good now.
Well, don't bother with dinner, Alice.
You're going out for you.
So far.
I'm not your boyfriend.
The power of the concert had time and I was thinking about willing to deliver the bond.
Oh, that's wonderful.
It was a delightful scene.
As an average life, I never got the message.
What?
Well, it's time to have to go out on the dance call.
It is a lesson.
Hello.
I never did buy the presents, but while I went out there, it came across a couple of boys.
He was climbing around the village pond.
And that's the best interest they could have had of what I think is what it is.
No, I couldn't.
The house gets ready to go out.
Only thing is, I don't think Henry's in the mood to celebrate.
I'll worry, he will be.
He will?
I think so.
We're going out on the contrary.
I think it happens to have two of the prettiest,
most brilliant, most amazing ever talk.
[LAUGHTER]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[crowd cheering]
[Music]