[Music]
Henry! Henry Oldrich!
Coming, Mother!
The Oldrich family! A special rebroadcast for you soldiers, sailors and Marines of the United Nations.
[Music]
They say that when you grow out of the teenage, it's like being expelled from paradise.
You can't ever go back.
But you can recall that time of your life in the misadventures of Henry Aldrich.
The scene opens in a neighbor's living room.
Look out, Henry. Look out. You know how to work it.
Homer, will you please keep your hands off the storm bank?
-Hinch even with me, Pimpus. -Sure. I'll let you pump it when it's your turn.
Now just keep your feet out of the way.
See that, Henry? See that? You don't even know how to start.
I don't too. Now, look out.
Boy, how do you like it? How do you like it?
What's so wonderful about that, Henry?
I give little little power into it that you can.
How'd you win?
Homer, did you push something? What'd you do that for?
I didn't do anything, Henry.
Are you getting them all alright boys?
Wait, yes, spring Miss Sparrow.
Fine.
Are you sure you know how to work out play a piano?
Oh, yes sure. We're just trying to find...
Which...
Now here, let's see whether you have this role of music in, right?
The trouble doesn't seem to be with the music, Miss Sparrow.
It's more down here around Henry Speed.
Yes?
Oh, now, wait a minute.
This lever here is what you started with.
Oh, that!
And if you wanted to go faster, you press this.
Oh, yes!
Here we go Homer, you'll do it Tuesday.
You need a hand, just go.
Hands me, Pharaoh.
I'll cheat with.
Why did it blow down, Henry? Let me play.
I've got to have a control home.
Now listen, Homer, that's a nice thing to do.
Push me right off somebody's piano store.
I didn't push. I just wanted to sit down and play it.
Boy, you might have broken my ankle.
Listen, Henry, which did she say was the lever to start this?
You go ahead and figure it out for yourself.
She was hmm is this what I press and imagine you've taken piano lessons all this time
And you don't even know how to play a player piano just as if I didn't know
Look, he's this!
My dad is going backwards!
I like it backwards!
What do you like about it?
Listen, Warren, you should sort this person first,
so I like that, and he's gonna make the car!
He's not going for a stop!
What's the matter?
I'm not going for a stop!
Look out the window!
Someone's coming out this way!
Oh boy!
Oh boy, Henry!
Who is she, Homer?
Who is she?
That's Ethel Murphy.
And boy, is she a good-looking girl.
Is that Ethel Murphy?
Why didn't recognize her of course you didn't she took the bands off her teeth last week
Boy, I haven't trying to get a date with her ever since hmm
Do you know a real well Henry because if you do boy sure I know or sure I know where I opened the window
Oh
Playing the piano
My friend homework come on over here to the window a man
I want you to meet somebody that's outside.
- Who me, Henry?
- Ethel, this is Mr. Brown in here.
- Hello.
- I'm pleased to meet you, Miss Brown.
- I mean--
- I just told you to play the piano.
- Oh, sure, he plays.
Homer, go on back and play that piece for us.
- Now listen, Henry.
- Yeah, don't be bad.
But now listen to you from out here on the Lord.
I'm crazy about moving.
- You are?
- Well, okay, maybe I will.
- Play it loud, Homer, so she can hear it out there on the lawn.
(upbeat music)
Hear that, Ethel?
I'm going to be wonderful!
Hey, Oliver, give it the word!
Okay!
I'm going to be the director of "The Magic and the Magic!"
Didn't I tell you?
Hey, Oliver, play it fast!
Okay!
See, I'm listening, good.
He's beautiful!
There, that's all I'm going to play, my feet hurt.
What do you say, Henry?
He says that's all he's going to play.
I'm going to come right in the dream.
You were so new as it comes.
He didn't.
Did you know I play the violin?
You do look how'd you like to go to the movies tonight?
I don't think I could go tonight very well, but I'd be glad to have you come over to my house if you guys do
Okay, sure. And maybe you could play the piano a little. That's your house. Yes, sure
Why don't you go Homer and play for now listen Henry? She was you can play duet. I do rap?
Oh, you know the blue Daniel the blue Daniel. I say that sure Homer can play anything
Listen Henry. I can you're been taking lessons lessons for ten years Homer. That's only because my mother's stubborn
You get out of time and we'll have a whole night of music.
I know, but Gee whiz, listen.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Mary, could you come in the living room a minute, please?
I'm telling you, Henry.
I'm telling you.
It's no use.
Listen, homie.
You're crazy about the girl, aren't you?
And you're water-to-like, you don't you?
Why can't she take me from myself without my piano?
What is it you want, Henry?
What's the matter with Homer?
Mary, can you teach Homer how to play the blue Daniel?
I guess I could.
Homer, could you come over sometime?
I'm here.
What's that?
I've got to learn to play tonight, Mary.
The blue Daniel by tonight?
Yes, you've got to play it for the Moffett family.
What's that?
For the Moffett's.
Homer's crazy about the oldest girl.
Homer, you can read me.
Is it catchy?
Not anything that's any good.
My teacher's always kept me in the classics.
She has.
Sure.
For two years, the only thing I've even been allowed to touch is Patarooski's Minu-Wes.
Alright, then why not play that?
I can.
genius and besides murder special request of the blue daniel sure the only thing
I can play is this
it's all there is
former you mean after ten years that's all you can play and we don't you
understand up until this happened to me I didn't have any interest in music
well my goodness how much you can play that much you can certainly play the
blue daniel
here I'll show you
See that? It's easy.
That'll live us to explore and play some more.
Well, Gee, I ought to be able to do that.
How do I start?
Here, Homer, give me your left hand.
My left, Mary.
My left isn't as good as my right, my teacher says.
Well, we'll start with the left.
Now, Homer, you try it alone.
Your Homer, okay.
Is that right? Is that right?
And your head.
Wait a minute, Homer.
Homer!
Hey, hey!
Yes, Father!
What's going on down there?
Wait, then Mary's helping Homer get ready for the Moffet.
Hey, what?
The Moffet!
He met Ethel!
Well, whatever it is, it's time to stop it!
Listen, Mary, there's no sense in your trying to teach me.
Well, we just started!
I know, but look how long my teacher's been working on me.
Henry, please call Ethel and tell her I'm sick.
Who I?
She was after fitching this whole date up for you.
Homer, if you don't go over there and play it, you'll just make me look ridiculous!
Well, how do you think you'll look if I do play?
[Music]
Mother, I can't do it. I can't possibly do it.
And Homer plays the piano so beautifully.
No, Ethel, I'm sure you'll understand.
And it'll be very good practice for you to play with someone who really knows music.
Now, I'll put your violin under your chin and follow me.
What do you mean?
Mother, I can't possibly do it.
But of course you can't do it!
No great thought in the same talk, Molly, saying.
Ethel, what did you tell Homer you'd play with him?
Because, Mother, I think he's the nicest boy I ever met.
I must have just lost my head.
What, certainly quite a way to lose your head.
a head.
Would you like to look at the evening paper Sam?
No thanks Alice.
I have something else to read here.
Where?
Where's Henry?
He went out a little while ago.
Well Alice, you mind if I bring up an old question once more?
What's the matter Sam?
Do you really feel that Henry gets very much from his association
with Homer?
Why Sam Aldrich, do you realize how many worthwhile things Homer is really interested in?
Frankly no.
Why he loves music.
And tonight he's going over to call on some girl to like music just as much as he does.
Yes?
Mother!
Yes Mary!
You know who it was, Henry was talking to on the phone just before he went out?
No, I don't, Mary.
Why do you ask?
My mother, he was talking very low and making plans to do something I just know he shouldn't be doing.
What's that Mary?
Yes, he was, Father.
I heard him say he'd be in somebody's house right across the street from someplace looking out the window.
And if somebody got into some kind of trouble, he was to go to the window and pull down the shade, and Henry would see it and do something.
Mary, may I ask what it is you're talking about?
No, Sam, the whole thing is perfectly clear. If Henry had gone with Homer instead of where he has gone, you wouldn't be sitting here worrying about what he's going to get into.
(whistling)
Good evening, Homer. Would you come in?
Good evening, Mrs. Marco.
We're so glad to see you.
I don't know where we look forward to anything so much
as we have to. You're coming over tonight.
Have?
Yes. Now, who's taking things off?
White.
I don't think there's any sense in taking them off.
You can't say with your coat and gloves on.
Yeah, let me have this.
Well, hello there, young man.
Oh, hello, Mr. Ma.
Why, they tell me you're something pretty special
on the piano, my boy.
They do?
Well, gee, I'm not really that good, Mr. Ma.
Well, come on, let's go in the living room.
Is Ethel here?
Ethel?
Oh, yes, my goodness.
Where is she?
Ethel!
She had a spitting headache before dinner.
Oh, Ethel!
Oh, well, look, in that taste.
Don't you think I might just as well go?
I mean--
What are you here?
I mean, how am I having real idea right here?
Well, she was Ethel.
I was hoping...
I have the worst news for you, Homer.
You have?
What do you think happened?
I just discovered a few minutes ago that every string on my violin is broken.
It is?
I mean they are.
Boy!
But now, that's all they couldn't be all broken.
Yes, they are, mother.
Well, that doesn't make any difference.
Right over there in that table drawer, there are a lot of strings.
Not anymore, Father.
They all got thrown out by accident.
Well, that's too bad.
Let's go to a movie.
Yeah, young man.
We've heard that we'll play the violin, but we've never heard you play the piano.
Come on, sit down now and give us a treat.
Yes, dear.
Well, not go on, Homer.
Well...
She was.
It's something to matter, Homer.
No. No.
Homer, that was very good.
You like that?
Would you excuse me a minute while I pull a window shade down?
This shade?
What do you have to do that for?
There's a street light outside of shining in my eyes.
Oh, I didn't realize.
Of course.
Do I... do I hear anything?
Do you hear anything, Homer? What is it?
What is it?
- Right, it's not strange.
I thought I heard the telephone.
- Really?
- Hey, did you hear the phone?
- No, and I don't believe homework
would have heard it either.
The phone's down a order, all evening.
- It's out of order, and you mean?
- Oh boy.
- Oh, but were you expecting a call?
- Wait, no, just in a way I would.
- Oh, come on Homer, let's hear the blue daddies.
You didn't need coaxing like this this morning.
My goodness, you just ripped right into that piano.
- Oh, I don't need coaxing.
It's just--
- Now young man, all I've heard all day
is that's what telling how you know your music.
I know but I know.
Right now Homer.
That window shade is hanging crooked.
I want to let it up and pull it down again.
Oh, did you hit yourself?
I'm all right.
Steve, get the poor boy out from under that shade.
I can't get off from under it, Mrs. Moffrey.
She whizzed.
Homer, what are you waving that hat inside of the window for?
Oh, am I waving again?
Yes, dear.
And if I were you, I'd put it down before you break it.
Yes ma'am.
She whizzed.
Well, I guess you want me to play the piano
Don't you think that's right?
Well.
Did I hear something just the piano, dear?
There there it is.
That's the doorbell.
It is.
It's the doorbell.
Whoever it is, don't answer the door until Homer is played.
Now that's what we can't do a thing like that.
All right, I'll go to the doorbell.
But Homer, don't play like it.
I won't.
Hello, what's the matter with your telephone?
I mean, where's Homer?
Where is he?
I can't even know the thing room.
Oh, hello, Henry.
Boy, isn't this a coincidence.
Listen, Homer, I've been trying to get you on the phone.
You've gotta come out with me right away.
I have, okay, where's my coat?
Now Henry, homie, sit starting to play.
You can't have him till he's finished.
But Homer, you should've been out here long ago.
Is it something pretty serious, Henry?
Boy, I'll say. Now get your things on.
Well, we'll just have to take Ethel's way for it, Homer,
about how well you can play.
Or G, Mrs. Moffatt, you don't have to worry about that.
Boy, when Homer sits down at the piano--
Come on, Henry.
Do you know how long he studied music, Mrs. Moffatt?
Ten years.
Ten years?
That's right, Mr. Moffatt.
That gives you some idea.
Come on, Henry.
And, jeez, you are here in turn to Pat Aruski's menu at.
- Really? - Henry, will you come on?
- Goodbye, Homer. - Goodbye.
Nice young man.
Yes, Steve.
You know what I think?
The problem committee has been trying to get somebody
for the Women's Club meeting this Friday,
and he's a very person for us to have.
Well, they've got to be one of your children.
We're going to have some readings,
and if Mrs. Hardy's going to give a talk on native flowers,
and a solo from Homer would be just the thing to top it all off.
[Music]
We'll be back with the Aldrich family in just a moment.
Right now it's intermission and time for our intermission guests.
The one and only Tommy Dorsey.
Okay Tommy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
(orchestral music)
(music)
[Music]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(saxophone music)
(music)
(vocalizing)
(orchestral music)
(music)
(somber music)
(dramatic music)
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(music)
(dramatic music)
(somber music)
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
(somber music)
(SINGING)
(music)
[Music]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich and his friend Homer Brown.
Just because Homer led his girl into believing he was musically inclined,
when he was really operating a neighbor's automatic player piano,
he has now received an invitation to play a solo at a meeting of the local women's club.
The scene opens in Homer's living room. His mother is speaking.
Homer, I don't want to hear this subject even mentioned again.
Yes, mother. You're going to play it that meeting of the women's club
and you're going to do a very nice job of it.
Put 'em on the women and look at it this way.
Doing a thing like this to me can make me hate music forever.
Homer, do you realize what this whole thing means to me?
But ten years I've been coaxing you, I've been begging you to keep on with your lessons.
And now I don't have a clear sky, somebody certainly appreciates you,
and you ought to say no to them.
But don't you realize Ms. Snyder gave me up as hopeless?
She said she wouldn't even give me lessons anymore.
And that's why I want you to go in this concert with your chin out and show Ms. Snyder.
Oh boy.
Now don't take that attitude here.
When I think of all the money we've poured into Ms. Snyder...
Oh boy.
And before you do anything, please answer the phone.
Yes, mother.
Hello.
Hello, Homer. This is Enrich.
He was where are you?
I'm at Robinson's music store.
I think I found something for you.
What is it?
It's called Learn to Play the Professional Way in Less than a Day.
What's that?
Less than a Day?
Sure.
And you've got a Day in a Half.
Boy, you're sitting 30.
Well, gee.
Does it cover the blue Daniel?
Oh, wait a minute.
Now look in the book and see.
No.
No, there's no blue Daniel.
None at all.
It gives you Mary Anne-Lilam.
What's that?
And in Flocially Sweet Afton.
But no blue Daniel.
What's the difference, Homer? The sweet atom's a river!
But the point is, Henry, I've started to learn the blue Daniel,
but I don't want to switch rivers practically in the middle of a concert, do I?
- Homer! - In just a minute, Henry. Yes, Mother?
Could you mind the door, please?
Okay, Henry, I'm gonna go. Goodbye.
Oh, my God, I asked her to start your practicing.
Mother, I was talking on the telephone.
I was trying to make a decision about which river.
Hello, there, Mrs. Brown. Hello, Homer.
Hello, Mrs. Murphy. What'd you come in?
Hello, Mrs. Murphy.
My goodness, I've never been so upset in my life.
I came right over to tell you.
Really? What's the mathematics?
I don't know what we're going to do.
We've set the announcements out for the program and everything,
and now I learn that we can't have any piano where we're meeting.
What's that? No piano?
Will she...
No piano at all?
Well, really, Mrs. Moth, did I?
I don't yet think you can just call me a house or thing like that.
But home has been planning to do this and getting ready for it,
ever since you invited him.
Oh, why don't you go down to Robin's music store and ask them to loan you a piano?
They'd be glad to do it.
They would.
Now, wait a minute, Mother.
I mean, how would you get the piano over there?
Your father can loan you one of his trucks.
And you can get Henry as every other boy to help you move.
I know, but now Homer.
Whether the will is a way, you're going to get that piano
and you're going to play.
- Sam, will you have some bacon? - No, thank you, Alice.
Now, the adults sit there and salt
Just because I want you to go to that concert this afternoon.
Alice, I am not sulky.
I simply want to point out that you're asking me to sit through a program
in which I'll hear some readings,
a talk on native plants and home of brown play the piano.
But, Margaret, for charity.
Yes, and I've supported that charity no blip for seven years,
but this is asking too much.
Hi, Henry.
She was Homer's at you?
Yes, sure.
Good morning, Homer.
This must be quite a day for you.
Boy, I'll say.
I didn't sleep a wink last night.
We're all looking forward to that concert.
You are.
Hello, Mr. Aldrich.
Good morning.
Henry, can I use your phone a second?
Sure, come on out here in the hall.
- Will you have some breakfast, Helma?
- No thanks, I couldn't eat a thing.
Who you gonna call, Emma? Who you gonna call?
- Ethel's mother, there's just one possible chance.
Hello?
- Number please.
- Ellam 212.
- Ellam 212?
- Henry, come back and finish your breakfast.
- Yes, mother. Homer, I'll be right back.
- Hello?
- Hello, is this you, Ethel? This is Homer.
- Oh, hello, Homer.
- Look, could you tell your mother it looks as though
we can have the piano?
- Oh my goodness, why not?
Well, we can't use my father's truck, see?
It's a pretty new one, see?
Well, he's afraid the piano would scratch you.
Homer, what are we gonna do?
Well, what I was gonna suggest was, why don't you play the violin?
Oh, I... play the violin!
Sure, at least you wouldn't have to hold it in the truck.
And listen, Ethel, would you like to go to the movies tonight?
To the movie?
Sure, but I don't think I've got a call for you.
I'll meet you down at the movie, see?
Oh, but Homer!
Bye-bye!
Hey, Henry!
Homer, did you get old people?
I'll say, boy!
Homer, are you sure you won't have a little breakfast with us?
Wait, as a matter of fact, Mrs. Old, which I think I would enjoy a little.
Whether you take this plate out in the kitchen, you'll find some scrambled eggs.
And give me some too, Homer. Okay.
Well, do you know how I suddenly feel? They never felt better in my life.
What happened to Homer?
Sam, I think Homer has a right to feel rather pleased with himself today.
Now, Henry, don't you wish you'd gone on with your music as I begged you to do?
Well...
Down at the bottom of your heart, Henry, don't you wish just a bit you were in Homer's shoes?
Well, I... and Sam, it's really your fault as much as it is, Henry.
My fault.
Yes, dear. If you backed me up five years ago,
then you'd be hearing Henry instead of Homer
when you go to that concert this afternoon.
What do you mean when I go to it?
I'll answer the phone.
As a matter of fact, Henry, I think it's a shame
for you not to try to piano once more.
Hello?
Hello? I want to speak to Homer Brown.
To who?
Palmer?
Yes, sir.
To Homer.
Hey, Homer.
What Henry?
What is it?
You weren't on the telephone.
Do you want to just an impulse mother, is it?
No, it's some man.
We'll hear Homer eggs.
Hello?
Homer, may I ask just what this is all about?
What's that? Who is this?
It's your father!
Have you been spreading rumors behind my bag?
Spreading my father?
When did I ever tell you that I was afraid of piano?
What scratched my trunk?
Oh, did they say that?
Mrs. Muffin just phoned me here in the house.
And Homer, your mother says you're going to get the boys together
and go down to Robinson's music store and get that piano.
Understand?
Yes, father.
And you're going to play in that concert?
Goodbye.
Goodbye, father.
Here's your eggs, Homer.
My eggs.
What would I do with those?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I'm sure that these guys are the reason we do just listen to.
In fact, up to now, we've enjoyed our entire program,
I'm sure.
Before introducing the next number,
however, there will have to be-- I'm
afraid-- a slight inhibition of a half a minute or so.
So if you'll just excuse me, I'll have to step back stage
make sure about something.
Sam, what are you supposed to trouble is?
Alice, how did we have to sit right down here in the front row?
Because, dear, I thought it would please Homer's mother.
Look, it will brown over there in the next row.
Anyone would think Homer was something wonderful.
Now, Sam, can you blame him?
Perhaps a year from now, you'll feel just as proud as he does.
How do you say that?
You seem to snider over there.
I just had a talk with this amateur.
She's promised to come over to the house tomorrow
so Henry can start his lessons again.
Watch that, Alice.
Now, there, ladies and gentlemen.
I may as well tell you quite frankly what the trouble was.
The summer isn't a piano we're trying to borrow.
It was not delivered when it should have been.
However, I'm very pleased to announce that I have some good news for you.
The boys have arrived with the piano,
and if you'll bear with us for another half minutes,
they'll roll it on to the stage.
- Then there's Henry. - I see him. Don't quite, Alice.
After all all he's doing is pushing the piano.
I know, dear, but he hasn't any next time.
Alice, why doesn't all my help push the piano?
Because he's probably saving himself.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
I'm sure we're all going to have a great deal of pleasure in listening to one of our
sounds of forthcoming musicians shall I say.
Pomer Brown, whose selection will be the Blue Danube by Spouse.
But perhaps I should say by Jay Spouse.
Homer, I'll turn the rest of our program over to you.
[APPLAUSE]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hey, hold on, I'm back, remember, please be the other one.
What?
Oh, oh, oh, yeah, remember.
Hey, Henry, Henry is getting away from me.
(audience applauding)
(upbeat music)
[Music]
This re-broadcast of the Aldrich family is a presentation of the Armed Forces Radio Service.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(jazz music)
(upbeat music)
[Music]