The Oldridge family based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Ezra Stone as Henry with Jackie Kalk as Homer.
Henry! Henry Oldridge!
Coming, mother!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
And now for the Olridge family.
The phrase "never a dull moment" certainly describes a day in the life of a typical teenage American boy like Henry Ulrich.
And it more than describes what happens to everyone who comes in contact with him.
The scene opens in the Ulrich front hall. It is late afternoon.
You! Anybody here?
Hello, Otter! Sam! What are you doing, Ho?
I finished early at the office. Where have you been, Otter?
Why, out. Just out.
- Do you have a good time? - Lovely.
As soon as I take my hat off, dear, I'll make us a cup of tea.
That'll be nice.
Was... what, anyone with you?
Where, dear?
- Out. - No. No, I was all by myself.
Oh. Not that I care where you went, Alice.
Naturally, your time is your own, but you look a little funny.
I do. Well, Sam. - Yes?
That is... did you have an interesting day, dear?
- That's good. - Did you?
Oh, yes, I had the most... I'll go and make the tea.
Alice, where were you?
Well, Sam, I wasn't going to tell you just yet, but I'm so excited I'd been to an auction sale.
I hope you didn't buy anything.
Now, do you know perfectly well I bought something?
Oh, right, let's have it.
Well, they're sort of chairs.
What kind of chairs?
They're the kind that they'd be just grand in our...
Grand in our... well, any place we put them.
How many chairs?
How many?
Sander, genuine early American, and it sounded as though they went back to 1840.
They went where?
And they were awfully cheap, dear, and there's a good deal of wood on them, I know that.
I see.
But, dear, before you set your heart on them, they may not be chairs.
What?
Sam, I was way at the back of the hall and there was a woman with a feather right in front of you.
So, I'm not quite sure what I bought.
What?
In the living room, Henry.
Oh boy, have you heard about the Browns?
Have you heard about the Browns?
What Browns?
The Homer Browns, gee, was guess what happened to them?
What happened?
I don't know.
What?
I just ran into Willie Marshall and he said something practically unbelievable happened to them.
And he didn't say what it was?
He doesn't know either.
But boy, it's all over town, so somebody ought to know, I'm going to phone in!
That's odd. I had lunch with Will Brown today, he didn't mention anything.
- Whatever's happened to them must have...
Oh my goodness, is that a truck pulling into our drive?
- It looks like it. - Send that must be my chairs.
- Alice, walk, don't run! - Come and see them, dear!
- 117 Elm Street, all rich. - That's right. Just set them right down here.
Oh, my, are they beautiful?
- All right, Alice, what are they? - Looks, and they are chairs, ladder backs.
- Wow, here, lady, sign here. - Yes, of course.
- Thanks. - Good-bye.
And thank you.
Sam, look, five dining room chairs.
Genuine antiques. Aren't they beautiful?
- Grand? Just grand? - I'm so glad you like them, dear.
Oh, I do, I do.
They're just one small point I'd like to bring up.
Yes?
We already have a set of dining room chairs.
Now, isn't that just like a man?
It is.
Need in all kinds of places we can use them.
Such as?
Such as...
And besides, Sandy's chairs are really a wonderful investment.
Oh, they?
Of course they are, dear.
Antiques always have a high resale value, didn't you know?
And you always said, "I don't have a good head for business."
But Alice, come on, dear.
Let's go in the living room and take a look around.
Oh, four.
Maybe there's something we can get rid of to make room for the chair.
Alice, we're not going to start throwing out my favorite furniture.
No kidding, Agnes.
Oh, boy.
Well, goodbye, Agnes.
She was the way Agnes understands it's Homer's uncle who died.
Oh, that's too bad.
No, it isn't. He left a will or something. Agnes says she hears the Browns of inherited a couple of fortunes.
Henry, aren't you being rather mercenary?
I know, but...
Well, she was, do you realize what that means?
Dear, you're entirely too excited.
The mother, don't you agree it's pretty wonderful when your best friend suddenly becomes successful?
I'll answer the phone.
Henry, I want you to go and comb your hair.
Comb my hair?
Just when Homer's falling into some money?
Hello?
Hello, Sam. This is Will Brown.
Well, I just heard the news.
Which brother was it?
What's that?
Or was it your uncle?
Who's uncle?
Is this Sam Aldrich?
Will, didn't you just come into some money?
Well, yes.
And I want you to know how sorry I am.
Sam, what are you talking about?
There's nothing new wrong with my brother.
Oh. Then what's the story that's going around town?
How should I know you tell me?
Never mind.
Look, Sam, why don't you and Alice join us for dinner at the mansion house tonight?
The mansion house?
Hana, Sam, hana.
That sounds like a good idea.
That is provided I can reserve a table.
Well, Alice and I can provide the chairs.
That's funny you should mention chairs, Sam.
That's where we picked up some money today.
Oh?
Elizabeth unloaded an old set of chairs on some sucker at an auction sale.
Well, now, well, isn't that...
Well, what was that again?
The five old chairs, eh, that we got stung on 15 years ago,
and they've been kicking around in our attic ever since.
Uh, well...
Some fella told us they were genuine entities.
Well, what exactly did these chairs look like?
I'm short of early American ladder bag jobs with straw seats.
And knobs all the way up the legs?
[chuckles]
I'll give you a stage every song.
Yeah.
[laughter]
I'd sure like to see the expression on the face of the poor guy that got him.
Well, I don't think we'll be able to make it for dinner tonight after all.
No, I'm not.
Frankly, I suddenly don't have much of an appetite.
Henry, never mind making whirlpools with the cream. Just eat your cereal.
Sure, Father. I'm eating it. Only, frankly, I'm a little worried about Mother.
What about me?
Ever since last night, you've been looking kind of sad.
Henry, finish your breakfast. You'll be late for school.
No, I won't, Mother. There's plenty of time before Homer gets here.
Homer's coming over?
Sure to call for me. Mother, look.
Are you worried about something I've done?
Of course not, Henry.
Henry, will you run upstairs and get me a handkerchief?
Isn't that a handkerchief there in your coat, Parker?
Please get me another one.
You want to, handkerchief?
I feel a cole coming on.
But, Father, please go!
But please go!
I don't want Henry to know a thing about those chairs.
He doesn't think...
And I don't want Homer to know about them either.
You've shot straight back to Will with the news.
Now, Sam...
Don't you understand I'll never be able to look
Will Brown in the eye again.
Is that why you hid the chairs down in the coal bin?
Yes.
I want you to get rid of them today, do you understand?
But, Sam, have you looked at it this way?
The longer you keep antiques, the more valuable they become.
But Alice, those chairs are not antiques.
They will be if we keep them long enough.
Alice.
Here's your handkerchief father and some aspirin.
Aspen, what's off?
She was your cold.
Here, I'll pour you a glass of water.
Henry, I don't need any water.
You mean you just swallow them straight?
Hey, Henry.
I'll be right there, and I'll--
--come by everybody.
Henry, come back here.
Well, what is it, Father?
Henry, naturally, if you're walking to school with Homer,
you'll be talking to him.
Sure.
Well, then remember this.
If he asks you any questions about the family, you know nothing.
Absolutely nothing.
About what?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Father, is something wrong?
No, of course not, Henry.
But no matter what, Homer asks you, just don't answer it.
Hey, Henry, we're going to be late for school.
I'm coming, Homer.
Goodbye, everybody.
Don't forget your books.
I want Mother.
Goodbye.
Bye, Henry.
Have a good life.
Homer, are you asking me?
Because of you all, I know nothing.
About what?
Never mind.
Let's have a good life.
Hey, you don't have to take the whole word.
But look at the size bag you have.
Boy, that's nothing.
Will you see what I've got in my pocket?
Yeah.
Look, licorice, bubblegum, cigars.
Cigars?
The street.
Sure, they're solid chocolate.
Boy, what happened?
Although my father said your uncle didn't die after all.
He didn't, but we had a windfall just the same.
This morning my father called me and said,
Homer, how about stepping up your allowance this week?
He did?
And listen, why don't you ask your father to do the same thing?
Now wait Homer, what are you trying to pump me about?
Pump you?
How?
I've noticed, I've noticed.
All you've done is ask me questions.
Why doesn't my father increase my allowance?
Will I have a gumdrop?
Shall we cross the street?
Exactly what is it you're driving at?
Are you crazy?
See that, there's another question.
Well let me tell you, my folks told me to keep my mouth shut
shot and I'm going to you mean it's that bad. Homer if you'll change that from a
question to a statement I'll tell you otherwise you'll just have to wonder okay
things at your house are pretty bad aren't they I mean things are bad boy
they sure are do you know what I overheard my mother tell my father last
night she said she wouldn't ask him for one cent to run the house on for the next
six weeks yeah and she said she had a good head for business too why'd she say
I don't know anything like that.
Maybe she's going to help my father out.
She may be I ought to find a way to help out too.
Henry, you're the very guy I want to talk to.
How'd you like to go into business with me?
What business?
Look, I'm not asking you this. I'm telling you.
Did you know there's a terrific demand for secondhand furniture in John?
Huh?
Whatever you can dig up, somebody is darn full enough to pay money for.
Homer, since you're not asking me what I like to go into business with you,
is yes I would.
If you'll just come with me, Mr. Smith.
Uh-huh.
The chairs are right here in the cold bin.
There they are.
Uh-huh.
As you see, they're ladder backs.
And quite old, I believe.
Uh-huh.
This is what I'll be perfectly honest with you. I paid $25 for them.
Well, you got a good buy. These are valuable chairs.
What?
Yes, ma'am.
You don't say, "Wait until my husband hears that. He insists I have no business sense."
Uh, where's the sixth chair?
I only have size.
Oh, too bad. If you had the set of six, I could pay you $65 for them.
You would as much as that.
If you had six.
Oh, my goodness.
Five are worthless.
Worthless.
To me, they are.
Oh, uh-huh.
Now, wait. It just occurred to me, Mr. Smith, as the slightest possibility I might be able to get the other one.
Yes?
The couple who used to own the might have it kicking her. That is lying around.
Homer, are you sure that auction sale is going on for two more days?
Hi,
Of course it was hand carved.
Yeah, but the only thing carved on your bed is your initials.
So why?
Somebody might come along with the same initials and be crazy about it.
But supposing you did get $100 for the darn thing, what would you sleep on?
Who'd want to sleep?
I know, but...
And he decides, Henry, are we trying to raise money to help your folks?
Yeah. Okay then.
After all they've done for me, the least I can do in return is sleep on the floor.
a floor.
My father will certainly appreciate it.
Henry, who's that out in the hall?
I don't see anyone.
There was a woman of some kind.
She was sort of tiptoeing along.
All of a sudden she slid into my mother's bedroom.
She suppose it's a cleaning woman?
Here she comes out again.
Well, hello, boys.
Is that you?
Father and I have not been for a little visit with the browns.
My, but a lovely room you have here, Homer.
Well, my goodness.
What's an animus' all, Rich?
Homer, that little stool with a straw seat over there in the corner, it looks like...
That's the seat part of an old chair we used to have.
What?
Well then, what's the matter?
Homer, where's the rest of it?
The back part?
My father uses it for a pipe rack.
You don't say...
Oh, my...
Homer, I... I suppose you're quite attached to that lovely little stool?
No.
She was, I only used it to rest my foot on when I'm shining my shoes.
Really?
Sure. How did they ever do that?
Oh, that was wonderful.
I wish my mother took that attitude.
And the back of the chair is your father's typewriter?
Sure. Well...
Will you excuse me, boys? I'm going downstairs and speak to your father.
Henry, do you think you're a folks have lost their home and they're moving in here with us?
Gee, whiz.
Gee.
Homer, you're putting that old stool in the back?
Sure. We're gonna sell it at the auction.
- Matt Darnfett? - Why not?
If it looked good to your mother,
it might look good to somebody else.
- You're crazy. - Now listen, Henry,
do you really wanna help your folks, or don't you?
(upbeat music)
(audience applauding)
Yes, getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
Alice and Sam Aldrich discover that the five antique chairs she had bought at auction were
worthless without the sixth, which they are now trying to get from the Browns.
As a result, Henry and Homer believe Henry's parents are in financial difficulties.
The scene opens at the Browns.
It is a little later the same day.
I was saying, "Well, I've certainly become attached to that pipe rack of yours."
"That darn thing?"
"Yes, it sort of grows on you.
Why, it was only five minutes ago.
I first laid eyes on it."
"It took fifteen years for it to grow on me."
"Is that right?"
"I certainly wish it were mine."
"Well, Sam, you smoked cigars, don't you?"
"Oh, I've suddenly taken up pipes."
"I'm going here now."
"I thought pipes made you deathly sick."
"Well, they used to, but not anymore, Will."
"Well, in here.
And let me make your present."
"What?"
"Here's a pipe I've never touched.
My wife's brother said it to me.
I wouldn't smoke it with a ten-foot pole.
But, well...
It's your, Sam.
And here's some new tobacco picked up.
Yeah, fill it up for you.
But you see, well...
Sam, would I ever give you anything if I really wanted it?
Yeah.
I hope I haven't packed the tobacco into tight.
Oh.
Here's a light.
Thank you, Will.
Thank you very much.
Now, there's a smoke with authority.
(laughing)
The only thing is, now I really need a place to keep this pipe.
- What, Sam?
- I'll buy that pipe rack from you, Will.
- Well...
- Sam, did you...
Will, what are you two so busy talking about?
- Why, we're simply...
- Sam, I never saw you smoke a pipe before.
- You didn't?
Well, you're seeing me do it now.
(laughing)
- What are they now?
Is that in the kitchen with a little bit?
- No, I just went back upstairs to...
Sam, do you feel well?
Yes, I feel...
Isn't it just a little close in here?
No, you don't notice it too.
Let me go open the front door for a minute.
Sam, it's gone.
What's gone?
The stool up in Homer's room,
the other half of that pipe rack.
It is?
Yeah, don't you even care?
Yeah.
Sam, I'll tell you what.
If you want that dog gone pipe rack so much, I'll sell it to you.
Yes, sir.
Give me a $10 bill and we'll call it square.
Sam?
Sam, speak to me.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
So sold for $0.25 to the boy with a lady in the sailor fan.
She went.
Now, just wait a minute while we get the next few items up
on the track.
Boy, Henry, did you see that $0.25
from my old left roller skater?
Imagine aren't people done.
Oh, say boy, they'll buy anything.
Now we come to this very interesting item.
Homer, it's your school.
The one my mother was so crazy about.
We have here folks a very valuable looking, uh...
Well, it might make a fine milking stew.
Or for shining shoes.
Did I hear a bit of two?
No, she was, I just said.
Homer, keep quiet.
He didn't say so.
Who I have? Who'll make it three?
Oh, boy.
Do I hear $3?
Three is bid? Three is bid? Three is bid?
Who'll make it three dollars?
Sure, who'll make it three?
You will find $3 I had.
No!
- What are you doing? - $3 I'm bid for this unique and fascinating little item here.
$3 is bid. I'm bid $3.00. $3.00, who make it for?
- Give me what I do. - No one says $4.00?
When it looks as if the young man in the front row was in luck.
- For me? - Going for $3.00?
- Then it's costing me $3.00. - Oh, he finds my own stool.
- It's going for... - Hey, what's the commotion back there?
- What's happening? - We're the gentlemen who just came in, please find a seat.
Perhaps he'd like to bid on this object.
- Yeah. - Can't me somebody wants to buy it.
The bid stands at $3.00. - Red, red, red, red.
- No. - I can't accept the 50-cent ray, sir.
Why not?
There's a young fella here in the front row
who's very eager to have this too.
No, no, no, no, no. - $10.00?
- What? - That's more like it.
So, for $10.00 to the gentleman without a seat in the rear.
[laughter]
Boy, who wants to block the stool?
I don't know.
I can't see back that far.
See, you know, if I didn't happen to know my father
happened to know my father was having financial difficulties.
I swear it sounded like him.
Oh, excuse me.
Could you help me right away, please?
I want to have this chair.
Why Gus?
No, Mr. Horridge.
I thought this was the cabinet makers.
It is.
But Gus--
I'm the new apprentice.
A apprentice?
Yeah.
You know, they take on young fellas and teach them the trade.
But just last week you were an exterminator.
Yeah, I'd give it up.
Is that so?
Yeah.
There I'd be and there a poor little aunt would be.
I'd give a--
[WISH]
There I'd be and the little aunt wouldn't be.
[LAUGHTER]
I'd give it up, Miss.
I see.
Went against my nature.
Well, um, uh, got you.
See this chair?
Is that what--
Well, it used to be.
Now, can you take this too, brother?
Well, that reminds me of a chair I fixed once for my Aunt Hepsa bar.
What a wreck.
It was?
You know, she was.
But, Gus, look, the chair wasn't really damaged.
Wasn't any?
Oh, yes, it was.
My Uncle Horace, he went clear through it.
The back part was used for a pipe rack, you see.
No, no, couldn't have been used for that.
'Cause Aunt Hepsa bar, she never smoked.
What's that?
Least way is not a pipe.
- Now look, Gus. - Although her mother...
...great-and-jesible,
'96 she was,
she wouldn't be caught without a concord.
Now, wait a minute, Gus.
[music playing]
Well, Sam, there go the chairs.
Thank goodness I hope I've seen the last of them.
You look tired, dear.
Alice, do you realize I went through three generations of Gus's families to get that chair glued together?
Well, let's go in the living room and sit down and count by $65.
Your $65?
Naturally, dear, I'll give you the 25 I paid for the chairs in the first place.
Thank you.
And that leaves me a clear profit of $40.
And Sam, even you'll have to admit that's a very good business to you.
Exactly how do you figure you cleared $40?
That's simple arithmetic, dear.
Twenty-five from sixty-five is forty, isn't it?
Well, how about the ten dollars I paid will for the pipe rack?
Oh, that.
And the ten dollars I paid at the auction for the stool.
My goodness, you mean I owe you twenty dollars more?
Simple arithmetic, dear.
Very well, here you are.
That still leaves me a twenty dollar profit.
Did I mention it cost twelve dollars to have that six chair repaired?
$12. That leaves you eight.
Well, eight dollars profit is eight dollars profit.
I must get a cost to have the chairs carted up here to the house.
Well, not very much, just four dollars and forty cents.
You mean all I have left is three dollars and sixty cents?
I'm afraid so, Alice.
Perhaps after this you'll leave business to me.
Sam, I have a clear profit of three dollars and sixty cents,
and any business that doesn't operate in the red is a good business.
Henry, where have you been?
Henry, you're a little business, Steel.
You're in, boy. Did we clean now?
You too.
And Henry has something to say to you.
No, Mother.
Homer had something to say. It was his idea. Go ahead, you say.
Hey, you're a folks, Henry. You say?
No, you.
Well...
Go on, Homer. Don't be bashful.
You've always been pretty nice to me, Mrs. Aldrich.
Mr. Aldrich, you've been nice to me too.
At times.
And now that you've had some high luck
and we've had some good luck,
we'd like to give you half of what we've made.
Homer, what are you talking about?
Mother, I caught on.
You didn't think you could keep it from me, didn't you?
Keep what from you, Henry?
Mr. Aldrich, Henry and I are in kids.
We can read between the lines.
Didn't we just see a whole load of your furniture
being hauled away?
Yes, dear. We sold it to Mr. Smith.
That's what I mean.
Gee, if you need money that bad, here, take this.
Five dollars and twelve cents. Half of what we took him.
Homer, we won't do anything of the kind.
But, Father, that's the way Homer wants it.
That's why he sold a valuable stool right out of his bedroom.
What?
Sure.
Dear, that's very generous of you. Thank you very, very much.
You're welcome, Mrs. Orridge. And I hope you don't have to sell any more of your stuff.
Come on, Homer.
But if you do, will you let us handle the deal for you?
I think we could do a lot better than you could.
Sam.
And I thought I'd live to see everything.
Sam?
Oh, Alice, don't cry.
Dear, I never knew boys could be so wonderful.
Think of it.
Sharing what they made 50/50.
Yes.
Dear, under the circumstances, don't you
think we should do exactly as much for them?
You mean give them half of your profit?
Half of just 360?
Oh, no, Sam, half of all the money we got for the chairs.
What, Alice? What about our expenses?
Sam, did the boys did up their expenses?
Sometimes, dear, I think you don't know the first thing about business.
[Music]
Listen again next week, same time, same station, for another sparkling half hour with your favorite youngster, his family and his pals.
The Aldrich family starring Ezra Stone is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
[Music]