Thank you for this time, excuse me for men in the armed forces of the United Nations,
the special service division of the War Department of the United States
presents a re-broadcast of one of America's most popular radio programs,
the Aldrich family.
And we'll be coming, mother.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Next to actually being young again,
There's no better way to recap through that feeling than to know a teenage boy like Henry Olgrich.
Or he acts just like you used to when you were that age.
And so his troubles become your father.
The scene opens at the Olgrich breakfast table.
And he has led us to you, Sam.
And another for you.
Thank you, Alice.
Henry has won for you.
For me, mother, for me.
Alice has an advertisement from some of her thoughts, Blimmer Lake.
Really?
Father, I certainly hope we aren't going away anyplace this summer.
Wait, certainly or not.
and I agree with both of you.
Oh, you know what I'm gonna do.
This thing is a matter.
Henry, what's the matter?
Nothing, mother.
I was just reading a sweater.
No, it really did you care.
Yeah, you were only.
Huh.
Father, what about working at any of the rest of this sweater?
Could you make out this word right here?
Well, I, um, that's Cindy.
Oh, yes, of course.
I thought it was friendly.
Mother!
Yes, Mary.
I'm gonna help her, maybe this morning.
No, dear.
Oh, oh, you got letter from?
- Why, it's just hardly anything.
- Mary, will you please stop trying to read over my shoulder?
- Every all I was doing was innocently looking to see
whether you'd open one of mine that is by mistake.
- Well, I haven't.
You don't even know who this was from.
- Hi, Mary.
Are you a few requests for it?
- Oh, where did you come from?
- Johnson, tell me, tell me, tell me.
- Hi, Mr. O, which one of these are five?
- What, then?
- Go ahead, it has one next to you.
- Oh, but when you please take that bag
from under my nose.
- Oh, excuse me.
Oh, I couldn't eat a little.
Henry, you look me as your egg.
We have a little piece of flood down the side.
Mrs. Aller, you may know.
- Oh.
- Mother, could I speak with Homer confidently
out in the hole with (indistinct)
Do you have any thought of your breakfast?
Mother, my engine's hot.
Say, I mean, it's not cold enough for me to eat my,
I'd like to talk to Homer about this,
about a certain matter.
And will you be right there?
Yes, Mother, I'll be out of here in the hole
for exactly two minutes or not.
One second long.
- What is it, Mary?
- Is it a report card turned?
- Oh, my hooky.
- So what?
- I'm a girl.
- A whole weekie.
I don't know. What do you mean you don't know? I know if you have the one out of the city.
What do you say? Dear Henry Olga, I suppose you think I am very bold right in your
boring letter like this, but I'm simply so bored I can't help it.
Or what's the matter with it? I guess you know your friend Nancy Adams who was visiting here,
and yesterday he happened to film in her school yearbook, and I said, "Who's that
Who's that picture?
He said, "Why that's can reality."
And I said, "It's such a boring day.
I'm going to write to you."
And he said, "All right, I dare you."
And I said, "All right, and here I am.
What's that?"
"All go on probably no way before doing it."
"Can we let you down?"
"Oh, will you please take your hands off?"
All I want to do is read it.
In the first place, Homer,
some of it is confident leading some more.
Leading some more.
He says, "You could certainly be glad, Henry.
You don't live in this boring place.
It's friendly. I mean, I can hardly wait until summer comes, and we've got a beautiful
light cat for two when there is something doing every minute.
Who are you going to be this summer?
Yes, mother.
Can I be eating the rest of this?
Public property.
I'm coming right now, mother.
And boy, mother, what do you think your father said a little while ago was a good
idea what he said about blood Henry about ongoing away this summer when did I say
we were going away I thought you said
see father those things are places going boring in the summer sorry I don't do
you like it here mother would see it it's what's
and the summer I think we ought to go the right path but then they passed the
You never heard of it.
I'm Homer.
I'm assuming it don't have anything.
I could be looking around.
No.
Now, Henry Homer is your guest.
You go find him a magazine.
Yes, well, we'll get it for him, either way.
And mother, it's like past the two.
There's something doing practically every minute.
Well, there's nothing wrong with our whole life here.
Hey Henry, let me see just one more page of it.
OK, Homer, it's just promise not to handle.
Where were we?
At like past the two.
Oh, yeah.
Here's a good part.
The way this was good.
It is raining out and has been all day.
The fact it's been raining most of this week.
Is it raining in Centerville?
Isn't it seeing this?
If there's one thing I find boring,
it's a sit indoors all day with nothing to do when it's raining.
That's very interesting.
- Hi, Kathleen Anderson.
Why don't you want a telephone?
- Oh, me, Mary.
Oh, well, hello, I can't talk with her.
I'm very busy right now.
- Hold on, Henry.
Why do you keep stopping?
- Why?
- She goes on and says,
Naturally, I am asking you all about yourself.
And Nancy tell me your very interesting.
Do you please promise to write?
Please, oh, please, oh, please.
Oh, boy.
I hope I have not bore you.
As ever-- as ever in this journey, yes?
Homer, can you make that first name now?
Let's see.
I can figure out the last name, OK?
You can.
Yeah.
Three-quarter.
Three-quarter?
That's what it looks like to me.
Oh, there are two always in there. Could it be drop water?
Well, I see what that middle letter is in the first name of Steve.
See? Could it be Walter? Walter? Walter drop water.
Why would a girl have that name?
I can't see what it is. It's just as clear as day. It's Myrtle.
Oh. Oh. Myrtle drop water.
Can we turn it frankly? Do you think you want a right to her?
Oh, no! It's because...
Just because...
And beside Coma that isn't old in the last name, it's an odd.
Oh, why?
It's drip water.
Drip, seal or not drop?
No wonder you had the wrong impression of it.
Drip, drip, and then...
Yes, mother!
When you feed the last in the kitchen, get your father drink of water...
A drink of...
Who was that thing?
Why?
It's Myrtle Drinkwater.
Isn't that a beautiful name?
[Music]
Sam, I don't like to bother you, but I do have something I like to talk over with you.
Yes, but the trouble.
Oh, it's about Henry. He's been so upset ever since he got another letter this morning.
And about a half an hour ago, he asked whether I did anything he could have his allowance in clean.
Come on, guys.
Yes, Mary. Did you know Henry got another letter this morning?
Yes, we know all about it. Mary, turn around.
What's wrong? Here, I think you ought to go down to the hairdresser.
Mother, I'll do it. She said that matter was from some loan company. Mary, what's that?
What's that?
What did you say with Palm Mary?
A loan company in Avoc City.
I saw it right up on top of the page.
And then he came to me and asked if he could borrow some money.
And he was all excited.
Yes.
Father.
Then what do you say, does it matter?
Come on, see you along for--
Oh.
Oh, hello, Mary.
Hello, Mother.
Hello.
Well, this is nice that we can play together.
We really film and get together.
And right.
Yes, Father.
What was it you came in here to say?
Boy, I'm trying to bother.
Oh, boy, I was in the door.
I knew that problem isn't--
No, it isn't, mother.
I think it's someone that's seen me.
I'm sort of a business arrangement.
Oh, my, how I tried to come in.
What's the idea?
What's what I did?
I'm keeping your door locked.
How do you expect your friends to come in?
Wait, my father asked us to keep the rock every morning
until he goes to the office.
What's in home?
I think that's a 35-10.
Yes, dear.
Now, where's the land?
Why do you turn it to me?
Oh, no.
I didn't say I'd let you read it.
I said, I'd read it to me.
What did she say? What did she say?
Don't push me, Loma.
Because my dear head, oh boy,
I received your 14-page letter and it was a wiz.
Oh, I have a mind, Loma.
I hope you'll excuse my losing my father's business,
stationary, but my newspaper with this
and every of the wiz hasn't come yet.
You'll have me to describe myself,
and I'll do the best I can.
Although there are some things I can say
because you would think I was terribly confused.
First of all, I am five feet nine.
Thomas, about to be nine.
He was in the only five feet eight.
I think you're quarter, Homer.
Besides, I didn't know I had to say it was clear as day.
Looks like a learning to me.
Scoring.
I am five feet two and have rather pleasing eyes, I think.
Otherwise, you would at times, my eye lashes weren't quite
so long because they were always somehow getting in my way.
What did you have to do, Tom?
And Thomas, that's a roughing.
After the color of my eye,
I was here to judge for yourself.
Some boys say they are gray.
Some boys say they are green.
Let's do that.
We can have your toys.
Homer, lots of things say color and different lights.
Where was I?
Right here.
What color were you having?
Oh yes.
As tonight here, which is black,
I have recently had done into a feather cut.
What does a whiz, even if I do say so?
- Henry.
- Yes, mother.
Are you busy?
- White.
I'm carrying out a little transact
and you might say with Homer.
- Well, Mary, I stayed with you right now, mother.
- Listen, here you have me for your convenience.
- I'll be back.
This is what you want for 35, friend.
- Henry?
- Yes, mother.
- Dear, I just want you to know that if you really need money
and would be willing to tell your father what you needed for,
he might seem to be way greater helping you out.
- Thanks.
- Mother, I appreciate your bringing it up,
but you've got so many things on your mind.
I'd say you would be better than I just didn't bother you.
- Well, if you're not, if I'm not gonna point
with your head yesterday, someday this week,
no, not at all.
- You're Henry, pass me an attitude phone you again.
She's in.
She was our main Senate Bill girl, but just before it.
- Henry.
- You're a phone where I'm coming.
Mary, are you going in the hands of her today?
Hey, why don't you give a feather cut?
Boy, that's hard to the wind.
- A feather cut, Henry.
I thought I let my hands go this way.
- Henry.
- I'm coming, Homer.
Where was I?
- She just got me a hand pool or something.
You're crazy.
You're where I stopped.
But I think your idea of phoning me is a win.
I'll probably be thrilled when I hear that old telephone ring.
Your case or a murder drink water?
You know, it's her new really drink water.
Why not?
Why?
You think she could be partying again?
Now what's from Homer?
What's that at the bottom of the page?
I think it was I hadn't seen that.
Huh.
Instead of your phoning me,
why don't I phone you if I never know where I'm going to be next?
So I'll call you outside and take five of that.
You need to leave my money and we'll give it back to you.
No, Homer, I will not.
Suppose he called me correct. Don't you think you expect me to be a gentleman?
Well, if I were to keep it, can I be here when we call?
No, Homer.
Oh, I just think.
Tomorrow I hear Myrtle's voice from the first time.
- Santa, have you thought anything more about our going away this summer?
- At least I thought we decided not to go.
- Mother!
- Yes, Henry!
What time of a now?
It's exactly what it very surprised.
Thank you, Father.
I'd like to take a cottage someplace for a couple of weeks.
I'm sure I have no objection.
Yeah, there's somebody.
I can't remember who it was.
They said something about Lake Pastor II being a nice place to go.
Lake Pastor II?
Somebody named it.
In the last couple of days, he said it was wonderful.
Father, are you enjoying your watch this ride?
I'm positive.
Would you please tell me why you asked what time it is every 60 seconds?
The reason, Father, I was just waiting for it to be five o'clock.
Henry, why do you have your new Bluetooth on?
Well, he wouldn't think I got that on.
This is a phone phone, oh boy.
Henry, good luck.
You was looking back here, dear man.
Henry.
I'm sorry, Father.
I'll pick it up when I come back.
Father, just say where you are.
Please, I beg of you.
Henry, what's the matter with you?
Nothing, Mother, it's just a...
Come on, why won't you listen?
What's that?
Who is that you?
Get off the line, the phone will be a play.
You're on calling you.
Have you found yet?
No, why won't you point your hand off?
I'll say and I'll be right over.
No, you're not to come over.
I don't want you even around here.
I think I'm going to be talking to her on my 35th day.
Oh, please, what's the reason?
Look, if I'll tell you something,
she said no letter this morning.
Will you say where you are?
Is it any good?
Sure, it isn't.
So I said it better than any telephone conversation would be.
Well, all right.
She says you want me to come to a bound map.
Come on.
To a what?
To a bound map.
That's a map to Ray party.
I went to have a study.
- Hey, what do you think it's safe?
- What do you mean, say?
- Are you going Henry?
- No, I'm going.
- Henry?
- Yes, mother.
- Here you have to hang up right this minute.
- I will.
Homer, my mother says I have to hang up
and I guess she's right.
Goodbye.
- Henry.
- Hey, mother, did you save my life?
- Yeah, I want you to jump on your bicycle
and go right down to the meat market.
Mr. Phil, as I, as I, hello.
- Number three.
- Operator, this is Henry, all the guests.
I'm expecting a very important call from Abbott City City.
When it comes to this little after the picture stop.
(upbeat music)
Hey Mr. Wilson, Mr. Wilson.
- Why there, Henry?
- Now my mother's me, Freddie.
- It is right here.
- Good boy, Frank.
Can the telephone call come for me?
- No, not 'cause I've been on duty.
- Yeah, I'm expecting an important call.
But boy, that feels right now.
- You better let me ask her, please.
Well, keep a teller right here, won't you?
Hello? Henry?
How are you?
I'm glad I guess I got here just the right time, didn't I?
How are we just going distance?
It is not. Henry?
Well, how about you? What's something that happened to him?
And something happened to who?
He's calling me.
I am.
As long as you're downtown, I want you to run over to the Haven's drug store and get some cigars for me.
No.
And hurry home. Goodbye.
What's wrong with you?
Hey, boy.
What's the one who want to all this food call come for me?
come for me because you could you tell them they can catch me or would you
haven't dropped store?
I don't know why I couldn't. What's the name of the party's calling?
Her name is Myrtle Joyce. Why?
Well, don't do that for me.
Alice? Yes, Sam.
Did you call to Havens and leave that message?
Yes, I did. But was it you started to say about Lake Pazepu?
Only that I'd heard of someone downtown who owns a couple of parishes up there.
Oh, that's fine, Sam, because I don't know whether it's just one of my pre-manations or not,
but it seems to me if we forget Henry Awaison this town this summer,
he might not have quite so many problems.
Yes.
And goes the telephone again. I'll see you at it.
It's Henry telling the police, honey.
Hello?
Is this Elm, 303?
It is?
This is Long Distance. I have a call from out of city, so it's a Henry Aldrich.
Henry Aldrich isn't here right now.
May I ask who to call it from?
Why, it's a party by the name of Drinkwater.
Drinkwater? Oh, thank you.
And who was it?
Someone from Abbot City, but the name of...
Alice, I know who that was calling him.
I know exactly who that was.
Who? A fellow by the name of Drinkwater.
And he's connected with that lone company over at Abbot City
that him has been getting letters from.
Oh, my goodness!
Mr. Behaven, are you too busy to wait on me?
I guess not, Henry.
This person's a phone call coming for me.
Yes, two of them.
Two more guests, sir?
No, they were both from your mother.
He wants you to get a quart of milk at the grocery
and then stop at the cleaners and pick up your father's soup.
Oh, keep waiting.
Oh, boy.
Just a minute.
Now, wrap your father's cigars for you.
I'm expecting your call from a girl
and it's coming here to your drugstore.
That's right.
There's a big math grade over in Abbott City tomorrow, and I--
And either way, I'm going to wear it.
No.
It can better unfold, you.
What's that?
Oh boy, Mr. Heyman, could I have to your phone? It's probably.
What must be?
Hello, is this long distance?
Hello.
Oh, Marty?
Hello, could you work up a bottle of paragord right away?
Hello?
Hello, Addison Market and Loan Company.
May I speak with Mr. Drinkwater, please?
I'm sorry, but Mr. Drinkwater is hidden right now.
Well, could you tell me whether my son has been trying to borrow money
or old you any what's the name and they are already
all well we are allowed to get our confidence in this
I know but he's my son and he's
I'm sorry you're happy to get the drink out of personally
and here's it is I see well thank you bye bye
- Then how much was Henry old? - He wouldn't tell me.
She said, "As a matter of fact, I know what I'll do."
- What, Sam? - Now, when any comes in,
don't say one word about anything.
- You don't think he should? - I got to drive over to Abbott City
on some other business in the next few days, anyhow,
and I'll drop in and have a talk with drink water.
- Really?
- When did an I-your father say Abbott's
gonna be a very cold for a man race?
When did you get there?
- Okay, I wasn't qualified. - Henry, I was simply
talking about going over to Abbott City sometimes.
- Oh. - That's all.
- That's enough time.
- Father, do you have any ideas of,
to say when you might be driving over.
Oh, any time in the next few days?
Well, they have absolutely good movies over there sometimes.
Wouldn't you like to take Mother and go over to Mar and I can have a good time?
He's out of the night? Yes, you are.
And I might go along with you.
Well, we'll see. We'll take it over.
Oh, there it is.
That's Henry with you. Please, walk.
Why don't you want to miss him?
Well, here's Henry.
Hey, what's the matter?
You think Mother, I just went into the telephone table.
Well, get up off that floor.
I can talk right down here.
Hello, Henry. What did you say?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
I came in and see if you found that costume for me.
Oh, yes, Henry. Here it is.
It's Lieutenant uniform.
Is your last Confederate outfit I have in the place?
Yes, that's exactly what I wanted.
That'll be $2.
$2? Just for 24 hours?
That's right.
Couldn't you let me have us play a dollar or a dollar and a half?
If I bring it back, why should I?
Well, how would you like to go as an 1890 policeman for a dollar-dendly five?
I don't think it might.
My girl tried to get me by phone yesterday.
I mean, we couldn't get together and I saw in a hotel room that I'd be there the matter
of the Confederate phone.
Yeah.
She'd like to get as well as a policeman, wouldn't she?
No, I think you can never met, and I don't want to confuse her.
So, Mr. Johnson, do I get a sword with that for two dollars?
I want M787.
M787.
Yes, please.
Mr. Johnson, do I understand correctly if 50 cents left without the forward?
Hello, have a moment, biggie.
Father, I think you said that I had a fan of coat pants and sword, a third piece for two and a half dollars.
What's that?
Just for one night.
Who is it?
It's your son, Helen.
I have a chance to go to a costume board and I just have General Lee for two and a half dollars.
dollars. When the sword two dollars without good. Only don't try to get
somebody from a stranger. Where will I get it from me? Goodbye. Mr. Johnson I can take it.
Mr. Johnson where are you? Henry how do I look? What's in that card? What are you doing with that
uniform all? I'm gonna rid it. Eddie I've already said that you have not. Eddie give me that.
Now listen, Henry, you take your hands off that.
What do you stop listening?
Now wait boys, what's the idea?
Mr. Johnson, I want this uniform.
Mr. Johnson, I said I say it.
Well, Henry's right, Ed.
Don't give it to me, Ed.
Henry, for the last time, take your hands off me.
You bet he's drawing your hair.
Hey, stop.
Now listen, Henry.
Now wait boys, let's not have another war over this.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
How you feel, Henry?
All right.
Here, put this cloth on your other eye.
Boy, did you take a beating.
Well, I got the costume, didn't I?
I mean, that's corny, doesn't look so hot either.
Where's the costume?
Let me put it on.
It's still down at Mr. Johnson.
After we got for a week that he thought it would look
a little better if he gave it a brushing and a brushing.
- Thank you.
- Yes, mother.
- Mr. Medical, are you?
- Oh, for me?
Yes.
Are you quite sure you can yellin' up
to go to that dancing idea?
Look, I never felt better in my life.
You know that, Dr. Paul?
Homer, why?
This is the front of the fence, bro.
You're looking right at it.
Oh, yeah.
You can dial it and reload it to you with your eyes,
feeling the way they do.
Now, Homer, I can read it perfectly all right.
And dear Henry, as long as I know exactly what you're going to look like,
I think it is only fair that you know what I'm going to wear.
And so I'm enclosing a photograph of me and my costume.
Where is it?
There it is.
Hi, kid.
Oh, boy.
Let me see that child boy him waiting for you.
Come on, I got to knock you down soon.
Take a look at her.
Boy, is that a sight for sure?
I...
He was home with us.
Is that...
Yeah, Penrose.
Metal drink water.
No, but he looks like a medical.
No, but...
Look at that face.
Can you think that might be a mask that goes with the costume?
No, homeward's real.
Hey, man.
Yes, father.
You better be ready to go over with me.
I'm leaving in a few minutes.
to Abbott City?
Yes.
Well, he's going for his father.
Frankly, I don't think I'll be going to that day.
You're not going?
Why not?
He just had some bad news, Mr. Alden.
And you're just saying you aren't going?
Mother Mike, my eyes are sort of tired.
I don't think I'd want to go over there and train them.
Well, I'd like to better get your things on.
Then I don't think I want to take that tippy down.
I know, but Alice, I've got to go over there
and keep that appointment with--
Well, you do right on over and taping.
Mother, if anybody's home for me to see me,
I thought you wanted to go there.
Someone told me that afternoon we wouldn't know.
There's no one told me that afternoon we wouldn't like it. There was a white path to love.
Why in the world do you want to go to that place?
Well, that's what I'd like to know. They say it's simply changing.
I mean...
Well, what I'd like to know is what I'm driving all the way over to Abbott City alone for.
Hello? Hello?
Hi, Henry. Is it you?
Yes, it's okay.
Ed Carney, I just wanted to tell you why father went down ahead and talk to Mr. Johnson.
I'm going to wear that Confederate uniform after all.
You are to the mass-grade Mavic city.
Sure.
And you're going there.
Once I am.
And if you show up, I'll knock your block off.
Hey, as a matter of fact, let me give you a sip.
If you get bored, look around for a girl in a murder-like drink water.
She's got a feather bob and boy sees a wind.
[Music]
The psychic service division of the War Department of the United States has presented this re-broadcast of the Aldrich family for you service men of the United Nations everywhere.
now and after the show. The orchestra plays the music name most popular in your request.
Adound these please.
(dramatic music)
(gentle music)
(wind blowing)
(audience applauding)
(dramatic music)
(gentle music)
(music)
You have just heard a delayed broadcast scheduled expressly at this time for the armed forces
of the United Nations by the special service division of the War Department of the United
States of America.
[Music]
(dramatic music)
(silence)