[Music]
And now, Jell-O Puddings present...
Henry Henry O'Rourke!
Coming, mother!
[Applause]
The Aldrich family, based on characters written into my triple gold medal,
and starring Ed Sreston as Henry with Jackie Countess Homer.
And here they are!
Just a taste of jello puddings and believe me you will know they are made by famous J E L L
Oh yes that was Henry and Homer in their own particular cheer song for jello puddings
because you never tasted anything better jello chocolate butter scotch and vanilla puddings
chock full of old fashioned homemade goodness try them compare them see if you don't say
that jello puddings are richer, creamier, more all-round delicious, and they cook to perfection
in just about five minutes. Above all, when it comes to jello puddings, you never taste
in anything better.
Now for the Aldrich family.
Happy times are sometimes pretty difficult to recall,
but to many of us the happiest days of our life were those of our youth.
An assured far way to relive them is to make the acquaintance of a typical teenage boy like Henry Aldrich.
It's evening, and the scene opens at the Aldrich dinner table.
Sam, will you have some more potatoes?
Yes, please, Alice.
Thank you.
Will you have some Mary?
No, thank you, Mother.
How about you, Henry?
More potatoes?
Henry?
Henry.
Mother?
Yes?
Well, please have some more potatoes.
What?
Henry, do you feel well?
Sure, I never felt better in my life.
Oh, my goodness.
You look as if you're half dead.
Is that the phone?
That's the phone.
Henry, pick up that chair.
But the phone's ringing.
Henry, don't run.
Turn that running.
You'll stick on the whole rug.
No, I won't.
Oh, oh.
What happened?
I just slipped on the rug.
Hello Henry. Hello Cynthia. What are you doing?
Having my supper. Really and truly.
What are you having?
Lancha.
Aww.
What are you?
Well, to tell you the truth, I can't remember.
Well.
Goodbye, Henry.
Goodbye, Cynthia.
Henry, where are you?
Here in the living room, Father.
What are you doing?
I thought I'd listen to the radio a while.
But Henry, what about your supper?
Supper? Oh, oh gee, I forgot.
You forgot. You forgot you were right in the middle of supper?
Okay, Mary. If you're so interested in eating, why don't you go on and eat?
Henry, there's no need to snap at your system.
But father, she snapped at me first.
I did not. My goodness, a person can't even ask you a civil question these days.
All right, Mary, that's enough.
Well, I wonder how Kathleen is enjoying her little vacation.
Oh, is Kathleen away?
My goodness Father, don't you remember how Henry soaked around here for days after she left?
All right Mary.
Have you written to Kathleen recently Henry?
Henry?
No one?
Oh, no thanks Mother, I don't care for any.
You don't care for any of what?
Whatever Mother was offering me.
Fear I wasn't offering you anything.
I merely asked if you've written to Kathleen.
Kathleen?
Yes dear.
Kathleen Anderson.
Oh her?
No, she hasn't.
She hasn't what?
He hasn't what?
Written to me.
Dear, that isn't what I asked you.
I mean, she hasn't phoned.
Oh, that reminds me.
Where are you going?
Now it's my turn to phoned Cynthia.
Henry, you're dinner.
Henry!
Well, my goodness.
Sam, what are we going to do?
There's anything to worry about, Alice.
They all go through it.
Not like this.
Ever since he met that Cynthia, he seems to have completely lost his mind.
That's what I say, Mother.
How far is he's just lost his part?
It's a perfectly normal reaction.
Reaction to what?
Spring, Alice, spring.
It's just a little late catching up with Henry, that's all.
Well, if Summer doesn't get here soon,
he's going to starve to death.
Just look at his plate.
And Sam, I'm sure he's not studying.
That's not abnormal.
And now Sam.
All right, if it's going to worry,
you just forbid him to see the girl for a few weeks.
Oh, no, Sam, I couldn't do that.
Why not?
Well, Henry's extremely sensitive.
We might give him a complex he'd never get over.
nonsense Alice. The thing to do is diverting. If I could just keep him from going over to Cynthia's for one evening.
My goodness, look at the time. I'll have to hurry.
Where are you going there? No, down to the church. I promised Helen Forbes I'd vendor something blue.
Something blue? What is it?
But just something, Father. Oh. Oh.
When is she getting married there?
On Saturday. They're having the rehearsal down at the church tonight.
Helen Forbes. Is she that pretty girl who's been over here a few times?
Yes, Father, she's a friend of mine.
Well, a friend of yours, and she's getting married.
Wow.
Sam, how are you looking at Mary like that?
Father, she's three years older than I am.
My won't hella make a beautiful bride with that lovely blonde hair.
Mother?
Well, hello there, Henry.
Nice to have you with us.
Yes, sir. Well, goodbye.
Yeah, where are you going?
No place, Mother. Just over to Cynthia.
Again?
She was, Mary. I haven't been there since last night.
Hey, Henry.
Well, here's Homer. Isn't that nice?
Huh? What does he want?
Hi everybody.
Hi, Henry.
Hey, Henry, I'm afraid you won't be able to see Cynthia tonight after all.
I won't.
I want you to run an errand for me.
Mother, Mary, please run and get that puzzle.
Let's go to the chair.
Oh, but Mother, now Mary, I think Henry is definitely the one to deliver it.
Oh, oh, I understand.
You understand what, Mary?
Mary, are you doing anything to learn?
Mother, look, I've already promised Cynthia.
Now, dear, I'm sure you think more of your own mother than you do with Cynthia.
Even though she's a very nice girl in her own way.
Oh, sure, but...
Well, sure.
Now, please go and get your coat on.
Well, sure, but...
Henry, do what your mother said.
Good fun!
Yes, Father, I'm doing it.
Oh, dear.
What's the matter?
Just occurred to me, Sam, a wedding rehearsal.
What about it?
I wonder if I should expose Henry to an atmosphere like that in his present frame of mind.
On the contrary, Alice, I think it should do him good.
You do?
Yes.
Might make him realize the finality of it all.
Sam, what do you mean by that?
[Music]
Now then we'll begin the rehearsal at beginning. The room stands here. Here Mr. Carson, that's right Tom, and the best man here.
That's right. Now the ushers leave the procession. The bridesmaid is next door.
Yes Mr. Carson.
And of course, the bride.
And may I take this opportunity, Helen,
to say that a prettier bride has never graced this church.
Thank you, Mr. Carson.
Now then, we'll start with the procession.
You don't want me to walk down the aisle now, do you, Mr. Carson?
Oh, no, Helen, it's bad love.
Of course.
Doreen will take your place.
All right.
Would you mind if I stepped out to the vestibule
for a little air until you're ready for me?
Go right ahead, Helen.
We'll let you know when we're ready to rehearse this,
everybody.
Thank you.
Now, are we all ready?
You ready at the organ, Mrs. McLean?
- Yes, we can talk.
- Let's go, let's go round the head and start.
- Oh, hello.
Are you looking for somebody?
- Yes, I am.
I'm looking for some girl, co-op.
Co-op.
Jean, what is?
- What's the matter?
- Hello.
- See, I didn't expect to see anybody as pretty as you.
I mean, you know what a wedding everybody
is usually pretty old.
- Oh, yes, I guess they are.
Who did you say you were looking for?
- I...
I can't remember.
You can't.
Well, what's your name?
Why?
Henry?
Henry!
My name's Helen.
Helen Ford.
Well, you're the one.
You're the one I have to give this to.
Well, very much.
What is it?
My sister, Mary, wouldn't tell me.
Oh, I understand.
This is from Mary Oldridge.
You're her brother.
Yeah.
She's my sister.
[LAUGHTER]
She's getting married anyway.
Oh, there she is.
Walking down the aisle.
The Eleanor who the poor guy is. Oh, you don't believe in marriage? Well, I don't know. See you get married and all the romance goes right out of life, except in certain cases that is.
Well, how do you mean it? Well, you take... you take... are you married? Not yet. Me either. I mean... well, she was, I guess I'd better be running along. Goodbye, Miss.
Miss...
Goodbye, Anna.
Goodbye.
Ellen.
Hi, Hannah, old timer.
Homer, what are you doing here?
I just...
I just happen to be passing.
See, what a coincidence.
Say, "Hend me."
And...
Say, "Listen, do you know what's on at the B-Shoe tonight?"
What?
The best cowboy movie you ever saw.
I've seen it three times and it gets better every time.
Excuse me, Homer.
Will you stop jumping in front of me?
Oh, boy.
When you're still going over to see Cynthia? Cynthia? Yeah. Cynthia who?
Good morning, mother. Good morning, father. Good morning. Sit right down, Harry. Your breakfast is all ready.
My goodness, I'm starved. She isn't there for a lovely morning.
My, I can't remember when I've seen her nice, so day.
Yes, looks just like an ordinary day to me.
Well, perhaps it's because I feel so happy.
Sam, did you know my little plan worked?
What did it land?
D'youverting Henry last night by sending him over to the church.
He's completely lost interest in Cynthia.
Now Alice, a reversal like that could hardly take place in a few hours.
Well, it has.
Cynthia phoned here this morning and Henry asked me to tell her he was out of town.
Really, Mother?
Is that so?
You mean he's back to normal?
Absolutely, dear.
Well...
Good evening, everybody.
What? I mean good afternoon. I mean what time is it? It's morning.
Oh. May 1948. Friday. Friday? Oh then I have to go to school. Well goodbye everybody.
Henry you haven't eaten your breakfast. Oh I haven't. Okay. He's out of town all right.
He's out of the world. He's saying you're mistaken about the whole thing. Yeah. Henry.
Yes, Father?
Done your Christmas shopping, Dad?
And not yet, I'll get around to it sometime this week.
Mom, my goodness!
Hey Henry, are you going to school?
I'm coming, Homer.
Henry, haven't you forgotten something?
Oh, sure. Merry Christmas.
Hey, Mommy, how are you?
My head old pal.
Hi.
We are so dreaming.
I know, hold my books a second, Mommy.
Sure, old Tyler.
Hello?
Hello, is that Henry?
Yeah, who's this?
Oh boy, oh boy, Homer beat it.
Well, she was.
Hello, Helen.
Hello.
How are you?
Imagine you phoning.
I mean, how are you?
I'm just fine, thank you.
Could I speak to Mary, please?
Mary?
Wouldn't I do?
But you could give her the message.
I just wanted to thank her for that package she sent over last night.
Well, gee, I'll tell her.
All right, thank you, Henry.
Goodbye.
Wait a minute.
Yes.
I mean, while you're on the phone, boy, isn't this a nice day?
Yes, it's lovely. I only hope it's a nice tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Is anything special happening tomorrow?
Right. In a way, yes.
Oh, I guess you have to go to that darn wedding, huh?
Yes, I think I should.
Well, Gee, do you really have to? Couldn't they get along without you?
Henry, do you happen to know who's getting married tomorrow?
Who cares? And listen, Helen, you can take it from me.
whole things pretty boring. Sure, she was all the same. You've been to one, you've
been to them all.
Henry, why don't you come along tomorrow? I don't think you'll find it boring.
You're inviting me?
Yes, will you come?
Well, I come, well, I come. I'll say. And look, what are you doing afterwards?
Well, I'll see you afterwards, Henry.
You will? You will?
Goodbye now.
Oh boy, goodbye. Oh boy, Homer.
Hey, Henry, we're going to be late.
Homer, guess who that was that just phoned me?
Helen Forbes.
Helen Forbes?
The Helen Forbes, it's a friend of Mary's?
Yeah.
Henry, why are you looking like that?
She's old enough to be your grandmother.
Oh yeah?
Well, I'll tell you how old she is, Homer.
She just made a date with me for tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
Yeah, for a wedding.
And then we're going out someplace afterwards.
Well, Henry, tomorrow is a perfectly good Saturday.
I plan on us going someplace swelled them on.
Let's see, where could I take her?
I thought we might go on a swelled picnic.
Say, a picnic.
What do we have to do?
Oh, that's a wonderful idea.
We'll go to a ball game.
We will.
I got a hell of love ball games.
We only have to take Helen.
Homer, I'm sorry, but there won't be room for you.
The room?
Could Henry want to be come of me?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
For something very special in grand desserts, try those exciting new members of the famous
Jello pudding family.
Jello tapioca puddings, a miracle of goodness, a marvel of speed.
Get that luscious-like jello vanilla tapioca, or that rich candy-good jello chocolate tapioca.
And now newest of all comes Jello Orange Coconut Tapioca.
Man, that tempting orange flavor with coconut added is the most glamorous dessert yet.
It's cramp full of fresh, tangy goodness.
It's wonderfully rich and creamy.
All three Jello Tapioca Puddings are ready prepared, quick as a flash to fix, and nothing
to go wrong.
All you do is add the milk, then cook in an ordinary saucepan, and Jello Tapioca Puddings
cook to rich perfection in just about five minutes.
Vanilla tapioca, jello chocolate tapioca, and newest of all, jello orange coconut tapioca.
Ask for jello tapioca puddings, a miracle of goodness, a marvel of speed.
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
In the spring a young man's fancy, well you know the rest of it.
This particular spring, Henry's fancy, has turned to a young lady who happens to be getting
married.
But Henry thinks she's planning on spending the day with him.
The scene opens in a center of ill, florist's job.
Now set that basket of lilies over here where it's cool.
Careful of the roses.
Oh Mr. and the bride's bouquet, I'll do that myself.
Yes, sir, may I help you?
Yes, sir.
Please, I'd like to order a corsage and I'm in a hurry.
A corsage?
Please, a flower?
What kind of flowers?
Well, I'll tell you, it's for a girl to wear to a wedding scene.
I've spent most of my money for tickets to the baseball game.
How about a nice spring corsage of daisies?
Well, gee, I don't know.
You take daisies.
They're the cheapest we've got.
They are?
Well, yes.
Yes, I think daisies would be just about perfect.
Sure.
I'll make up a corsage right away.
I hope you don't mind if I rush you a little.
We're very busy getting ready for the wedding this afternoon.
The wedding?
Yeah, I'm getting ready for that too.
You have to get a haircut and get my shoes shined.
I sure am be the lucky guy that wins Helen Forbes today.
Helen Forbes?
Well, she wins, that's me.
You?
Sure.
Go on.
Yeah, boy, I can hardly believe it myself.
But I thought you'd be--
well, aren't you a little--
well, congratulations.
Thank you.
I certainly wish you all the best of luck.
And may all your troubles be little ones.
Yes.
What, sir?
But say, what do you want these daisies for?
Why, they're for Helen.
Miss Forbes?
But her flowers have already been ordered.
Van? What kind did she order?
White roses.
White roses?
How much is that going to cost me?
Oh, they're all paid for.
They are? They're paid for?
Well, gee whiz, that's considerate of her.
Hey Henry!
Oh, Homer.
Gee, old timer, what a coincidence.
I just happened to be passing in just by coincidence. I saw you in here.
Yeah, well, it's been nice seeing you, Homer.
Isn't this a swell day, Hen?
Yeah. Just forget about those daisies, mister.
Okay. Isn't it a perfect day for a picnic?
Hand? Boy, you see out of his mind, he doesn't know what he's doing.
He does seem pretty young to be taking a step like this.
Well he does the same thing every spring.
Every spring? Sure. One thing though, it doesn't last long.
How long? About a week. Now wait a minute, do you mean to say he only stays married for a week?
Mary. Mary.
- We're sure. Didn't you know he's getting married today?
- Who told you? Who told you?
- He did.
- Oh boy, I knew I would come to this. Oh boy.
(upbeat music)
- Halle!
- I'm in the living room, Sam.
- Where's Mary?
- She's upstairs getting ready for Henry Ford's wedding.
- Oh, is that today? Well, I'm glad we don't have to go.
Don't you like weddings there?
One's enough in any man's life.
Mother! Mother!
Yes, Henry?
Where's my blue shirt suit?
It's in your closet, dear.
Well, I think maybe I'll go out to the golf course.
Mother! Mother!
What is it, Henry?
Who hid my polka dot tie?
Then nobody hid it. It's in your top drawer.
No, it is, and I dumped out every one of my drawers, and it is.
Oh
That's where's he going this afternoon. I think to a baseball game. He's wearing his blue-seared suit to a baseball game
What's he going to do umpire?
I haven't wanted to worry you, but frankly the whole thing has me puzzled to how do you mean well first thing this morning?
He borrowed a dollar for a cosage. He said his life depended on it of course I
Sam I asked him who it was for and do you know what he said?
What?
Sam he heads.
Well, he's probably taking some girl.
But dear, if he's just taking a girl to a baseball game, why wouldn't he come out and say so?
And do you know he hasn't eaten a bite of food since yesterday?
Hey Mrs. Aldrich!
Ah, this can't we keep that front door locked?
Every time I try it, Sam he comes in the dining room window.
Oh, there he is, why?
I just want to say Mrs. Aldrich and Mr. Aldrich that you can count on me.
Wait, such as the can.
You'll miss Henry at first, sure.
But I'll try to be a real son to you.
I beg your pardon.
Only boy, after all these years, wouldn't you think he would at least have told me?
Tell you what?
Well, I'm not holding it against him, Mr. Aldrich.
Gee, if he wants somebody else to be best man, Gee, I understand.
Now, wait a minute.
Homer, what are you talking about?
Well, you know when Henry gets married.
Oh, well, I'm sure you'll be best man, dear.
But Henry won't be getting married for some time.
She was, don't you think this afternoon's pretty close?
This afternoon!
-Sant!
Who is it?
Oh, Father!
May I come in, son?
Sure, Father.
Come on in. I hope you don't mind if I go on getting ready.
You go right ahead. You are getting ready for something pretty important.
I'll say. Boy, this is the biggest day of my life.
I see. Going to the baseball game, I saw?
Yes, sir. That's one of the things.
I see. Well, now, I hope you won't think I'm trying, but
would you feel like telling me what the other things are?
Just something I'm doing first, Father. I don't think you'd be interested.
I might be.
Well, you don't leave laugh at me.
Oh, why should I laugh?
I think I was too young.
I mean, just because a girl happens to be a couple years one way or the other.
I suppose I give you my word, I won't laugh.
Well, I'm just stopping off at the church for a little while.
[LAUGHTER]
That church.
I see.
Deep father, it's the funniest thing.
I never even thought she was interested in.
Boy, right out of a clear blue sky, she asks me point blank.
She asks you?
Sure, that's the wonderful part.
Boy, I never could have gotten around,
get up enough nerve to ask her.
She even paid for her own flowers.
Henry, did it occur to you that your mother and I
might have liked to meet her?
You have met her father.
Her name's Helen Forbes.
Helen Forbes?
But she's going to-- Helen Forbes?
What's the matter for him?
Excuse me.
Gee, he was.
Alice.
Sam, what did he say?
Did you find out?
Alice has nothing to worry about.
I don't know where he got the idea,
but he thinks he's marrying Helen Ford.
- Huh?
Oh my, Henry.
- So all we have to do is to tell him point, Blake,
that she's marrying somebody else.
- Sam, we can't possibly do that.
- Why not?
- A sensitive boy like Henry?
Sam, we'll have to find a way to soften the blow.
A shop like that could turn him against women for life.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, mother.
I'm phoning from the Haven's drugstore.
And look, do we have any rice at home?
We don't.
But mother, I have to have some.
And listen, if your best friend was getting married, what would you think of a pair of
stuffed rattlesnakes for a present?
One for each of them.
Well, Miss Forbes, Miss Forbes, the minister is waiting.
Everyone's ready to stop.
Everyone will just have to wait, Mr. Burgess.
Please hold everything up for a few minutes.
Now then, Mrs. Aldrich, where were we?
Well, first of all, Helen, I'd better be the one to tell him.
Yes, I think so.
And then I'll give him his new wristwatch.
Yes, Mary.
And then I'll tell him that he's going on a nice trip to visit his Uncle John.
And I'll tell him about doubling his allowance.
And then Helen, you step forward.
Yes, and I'll say, "Henry, we want to be good friends of yours, Tom and I."
That's good.
"We want you to know that our house is open to you and we hope to see you there often."
Why, that's lovely.
And Helen, I'll promise to keep him away.
No.
Has anyone know where...
...where Henry is?
I think he's out in the vestibule.
Come along, everyone. Oh, not you, Helen. You wait a minute.
- Henry. - Father.
- And mother. She wins. What are you doing here?
- Well, dear. - Hello, Henry.
- Henry. - Yes, mother.
- Henry. - Excuse me.
But does anybody happen to know why the wedding is being held?
- Yes, Doreen. - Margie.
Hello. Hello. And my name is Doreen. I'm a bridesmaid.
Yes, you are. See, you're about the prettiest bridesmaid I ever...
See, hello. What's your name again?
Doreen. What's yours?
Doreen. I mean Henry.
Henry.
Look. Look. Would you like to go for a little walk out on the lawn?
Why, that would be lovely.
Henry we did have something to tell you but uh Henry Henry we can go out this way
oh well watch out for your van oh thank you here take my arm let me help you down
the steps hi aren't you thoughtful here let me give you one of my flowers oh boy
oh my god hey what's that boy throwing at us?
- Happy wedding day.
- Homer.
- Congratulations, and many of them.
Long life and happiness.
Happy wedding day.
- Hey, cut it out!
What are you throwing at us?
- Macaroni, I couldn't get any money.
(audience laughing)
- No, listen, Homer.
(audience applauding)
(upbeat music)
Boy, Homer, after what we've been through, do I need a pick up?
Come on, let's go down to dehaven.
Sure, him.
Only thing is, gee, we've only got a nickel between us.
Come on, think fast, Homer, think fast.
Well, Henry, when I came through your kitchen.
Yeah.
Just by coincidence, the refrigerated door sort of opened.
And just by coincidence, there was a bowl of yellow butterscotch pudding.
marshmallows on top.
Boy, Homer, what are we waiting for?
That's a swell idea.
Why, of course, jello puddings always are a swell idea,
because you never tasted anything better.
Jello chocolate, butter, scotch, and vanilla puddings,
a trio of treats.
And that's why folks enjoy them so much.
Sure, jello puddings are nourishing.
Sure, they look tempting and luscious,
and sure, they're easy to fix.
But the main thing about jello puddings
It is they taste so grand, smooth as cream, chock full of old-fashioned homemade goodness.
They're made with milk and nourishing.
They cook to perfection in just about five minutes.
But first and foremost, when it comes to jello puddings, you never tasted anything better.
hoping you'll be in your living room and ours next week at this same time tonight
folks
the old rich family starring Ezra Stone is Henry with Jackie Kelker's Homer is
written by Patricia Jaudrey and Dell Dinsdale with music by Jack Miller
Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich our house Jameson and Katherine Rott
Ezra Stone is currently appearing in The Alchemist at the New York City Center Theatre.
And this is Dwight Weast in New York saying,
"The Aldrich Family was brought to you by Jell-O Pudding."
[
The follows immediately are the most of these same stations.
This is NDC, the National Broadcasting Company.
(eerie music)