[Music]
Coming, Robin.
[Applause]
Yes, it's the Oldridge family based on characters
by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Edward Stone as Henry with Jackie Kelker's home.
And now for the Aldridge family.
Typical teenage boys are too busy even to sit down and remember way back when.
Like Henry Aldridge, they live only the exciting here and now,
with only everything to look forward to.
It is late afternoon in the scene opens in to Haven's drugstore.
But, Agnes, aren't you even interested?
Of course not, Kathleen. Of course not.
Fasting up with Homer is the best thing that ever happened to me.
It is?
What's Henry saying to Homer now?
Nothing.
Mr. de Haven just delivered something to Homer.
What?
A banana split.
He's gonna eat a banana split?
Kathleen is not supposed to. It makes him break out in bunks.
Now Henry's saying something.
He's leaning over and pointing his finger right in Homer's face.
What's Homer doing? He's eating it.
And his finger? No, the banana split.
Oh my goodness, what's the matter?
He did take a bite of it. The banana split?
No, Henry's finger.
He got it too close to the spool.
Now he's feeling the convincing Homer.
Why not that I'm the least bit interested?
Oh my goodness, Henry's coming back.
I'll let you decide, Kathleen.
Now let you decide.
Does the end of my finger look like a spoonful of banana split?
Why, of course it doesn't.
And that's a good example of how pig-headed Homer is.
Sure, Agnes.
And if you ask me, you're much better off without him.
I am.
After all the beautiful years they've been stuck together.
Sure.
Hey, did you explain that Agnes had no idea
that his home is red-boarding, she put the papery in.
Sure.
And we're just sitting there in the school cafeteria
without a bit of a identification on it.
And I thought... I thought...
Did you ask him what happened to his sense of humor?
Sure.
And you know what he said?
- What do you say? - What?
Huh?
What?
(audience laughing)
I told you, Kathleen, I told you it was no use
coming down here.
Agnes, wait.
And I wouldn't have if you hadn't pointed out
a dimple like a fight with people.
Agnes, we can't give up this easily.
And we will have to go back and talk to him again.
- But carefully, Harry.
- Harry, we can't sit by and see our two best friends
go over the dam.
Go ahead.
- Well, okay.
Excuse me.
- Just watch out for your finger this time.
- Homer, excuse me, Charlie.
Homer, old timer!
Henry, aren't you ever gonna give up?
(audience laughing)
- Not a Homer.
- I'm gonna do the Haven, another banana split.
- Another one, Homer.
Don't you think you ought to go easy on that stuff?
- Henry, I'm no child.
If I don't mind being a mess of bumps,
she was who cares anyway.
- Agnestah?
- Sure, sure.
- Or I mean to her as someone she can play jokes on.
- No, Homer, she's very fond of you.
- Fun.
- Henry, there was so much pepper in that pudding
When I got to French, I couldn't even say mercy, Vocoupe.
Sure, but that's what it's like to have Agnes Fern, love, you know? Thanks.
I can't afford to live that dangerously.
Okay, all right. Okay.
That's the way you feel. That's the way I feel.
That's the way you feel. Okay.
Only you can't blame Kathleen and I for being depressed.
Gee, when you think of those wonderful times the four of us adds.
Wonderful times?
What wonderful times.
She was how about that summer we all spent it like which I'm a clatching.
Remember those picnics down by the water?
A rowing parties in the moonlight?
Yeah.
Dancing on Agnes' veranda?
Standing in our heads on the raft?
Yeah, sure.
And Henry the way Agnes visited me in the hospital every day?
Hospital?
Don't you remember I had that bad case of poison in the ivy?
Well why, I'm a wise guy.
Put it in my bed to play a joke on me.
- Son of a joke. - Homer.
Boy, I scratched for weeks.
Homer, there's a perfect example of how you exaggerate things.
Agnes didn't even know it was poison ivy.
Agnes?
No, she thought it was skark cabbage.
I was Agnes who did it.
You mean he didn't know?
I can tell her to go jump in like what you're mclatching.
Homer, you mean nothing do.
But Homer, you may be throwing away someone who could share your old age.
Tell me if I sit to Agnes, this is a good chance I may never reach my old age.
[Music]
Hold the box straight, Henry.
Gee, Agnes, I think you're foolish to throw up the sponge like this.
Listen, Henry. If Homer feels the way he does, and I feel the way I do,
well, she was, why sit around with a lamp in my window? You know what I mean?
Sure only you don't.
Gee. She sure was cute, though.
'Cause that postcard he sent me when you booked
that trip to Washington.
Put a circle around the room where you slept.
- That's our room?
- That's what it says.
- Geez, my memory serves me, Agnes.
That's the elevator shaft.
- His next cue.
Poor Homer didn't even know where he slept.
Put him in the box with the rest of the junk Henry.
And here, here's that cupidow we wanted the carnival.
- You're returning that too?
- Why not?
- But you wanted.
You were the one who hit the bell with a sledgehammer
four times in a row.
That's why I wanted to have him.
She, you're the first thing he ever gave me.
It's swimming medally, gotten camped.
Oh, yeah.
He nearly drowned winning.
That's fine.
I was never so touched.
Gee, Agnes.
Gee, I'm certainly sorry you've had to end this way.
Agnes?
Yes, mother?
Could I see you for a moment?
Sure.
Excuse me, Agnes.
I'll be getting everything together.
OK.
Yes, mother?
Dear, I put up some hot milk for you.
Hot milk?
Yes, dear, with butter.
It'll make you feel a great deal better.
But mother, I'm not supposed to feel better.
At a time like this, I'm supposed to feel miserable.
Dear, I don't think that's necessary at all.
Why, look at the way your father took the news at home
or wouldn't be coming over anymore.
He just swallowed his disappointment
and actually managed to smile.
He did?
He even laughed.
Incidentally, dear, we heard from your uncle Clifford
in Arizona.
And do you know what he's sending you?
Mother, not one of his horses.
Agnes, he spends a great deal of time on them.
He was in my condition.
you think he'd come across with a present I can use instead of a heart he draws on
his typewriter.
Dear, in some circles, they're very highly put off.
Agnes, I'm about ready to leave.
Thanks, honey, Henry.
I'll see if you're a male kiss boy.
Mother, I beg of you.
Boy, will Nell Polone make me think of Homer more.
Is there anything else you want to send back to Homer?
No.
Boy, if that doesn't make a whole thing complete.
What does?
My uncle's sending me one of his darn horses.
Oh, boy, is that right?
And listen, Henry.
Shake his hand, will you?
I don't even know your uncle.
I mean, Homer.
And just tell him there's no hard feeling, see?
There isn't.
Not a bit.
And to prove it, you know what?
What?
Tell Homer if he wants to, we can keep my boxing gloves.
Who was that on the phone, Alice?
Elizabeth Brown, Sam, and she's very upset about Homer.
That's understandable.
What is it this time?
Well, dear, it seems he stopped eating.
Homer? Yes.
The same Homer that's been eating us out of house and homes?
Sam, this is no time for jokes.
Elizabeth is very much concerned.
What are you going to do with that bowl?
Take it into Homer.
Boys, are you still in the living room?
Yes, mother.
And I want you to know that Homer's
going to take that box off a coffee table just as soon
as he's finished going through it.
I don't mind the box.
I'm just looking for a place to put this bowl of figs.
Would you like one, Homer?
No, Mrs. Aldrich.
I don't feel much like a fig.
Well, maybe you'll feel like one later.
Sure, Mrs. Orange.
Gee.
Gee, so Agnes really sent back all these things, huh?
Yeah.
Although if you want me to, I'd be glad to return them to her.
Why would I want you to do that?
Boy.
Boy, there's some very valuable junk in here
that I've been dying to get back.
They're in?
Sure.
Take the swimming medal, for instance.
Do you realize I had a swim door near 20 yards to win it?
-Sure, only about an minute or two. -(audience laughing)
Homer, this is the wrong time to break up with Agnes.
Did I tell you what Agnes' Uncle Clifford is sending her for...
A horse!
-A horse? -Sure.
A horse? A horse?
Who are you trying to kid, Henry?
I heard it with my own two ears.
Her Uncle Clifford is sending her one from Arizona.
-Yeah. -Really?
-Really? -No kidding.
No kidding.
Sheeee, a horse.
So now don't you agree it's worth patching Agnes up?
No.
But Homer...
Okay, okay. So she's got a horse.
What's so wonderful about that?
You didn't hear her call me up and offer to share it with me, did you?
No.
Or even offer me a ride?
Or even a walk?
Homer, you didn't call her her even.
Can we stop taking her side?
That's probably the reason she wanted to break up in the first place.
Well, if a horse means more to her than...
Well, she can have...
Homer.
And they ought to make a very nice couple at the spring dance.
Hand me my box.
Agnes, dear, it's such a nice afternoon.
Why don't you glott and get a breath of air?
Mother, if you don't mind, I'd much rather read.
But, dear, besides, don't you think these blustery winter days are too much for my constitution?
Agnes, I hardly--
Listen to this.
Yet who'll complain?
My heart and I, and this abundant earth no doubt,
as little room for things worn out.
Did you ever hear anything that was more darn soul stirring?
Agnes, what book is that?
The poems of Elizabeth Barrett Brownie.
My goodness.
I'm feeling quite worn, Mother.
I think I'll go upstairs and lie down in my wheelchair.
I mean my bed.
Agnes Lawson.
Now please see who's at the door.
Isn't my condition?
Here, if you don't stop this nonsense,
I'm going to give you a good dose of sulfur and molasses.
I'm going, mother.
There's a limit to how foolish you can get about southern life.
Mother, I assure you, Homer has nothing to do with the way I feel.
Oh.
How do you do, Miss Lawson?
How do you do, Mr. Browning?
I mean, Mr. Brown.
Aren't you step inside?
You're very kind.
It's just that you're creating a draft.
Would you care to come into the living room?
Well, I can just stay a minute.
I just stopped by to return this box of things you gave Henry.
You want me to have them back?
That's not the point, Miss Lawson.
I just don't want certain parties getting the idea I'm an Indian giver.
Oh, well, thank you.
You're welcome.
Well...
How have you been?
Okay.
Except, gee, I don't know. I haven't been sleeping too well.
- Yeah, neither of us. - Yeah?
Yeah.
I guess some germs been going around.
[laughter]
I guess he had.
Well...
Yeah?
Well, I guess I better be going.
Holler.
Yes, Agnes.
Darnit.
Would you excuse me while I answer the door?
Sure.
And you try to remember what you were going to say.
And do you have anything to eat around the house?
I've suddenly gotten her over.
Sure.
In just a minute.
Hi, Kathleen.
Agnes, I just heard the good news.
I'm ready for Homer just to arrive.
Homer?
He's in the living room.
I don't know what brought him around, but I have a feeling we're going to make up any
minute.
Agnes, Homer's one thing to get excited about, but do you really think he compares to a horse?
In hot way.
In any way.
[LAUGHTER]
My goodness, but hey, me tell me you were getting one from your uncle Clifford.
I almost dropped, you did.
Uh-huh, right there in my veranda.
You did?
About a thing like one of my uncle's horses?
Agnes, how can you be so glad they?
What's so special about a picture of a horse?
A picture?
Agnes, the horse you're getting is a picture?
Sure, drawn on a typewriter.
Oh, my goodness!
You mean you thought it was a real one?
What did you say?
They did.
They thought...
Wait a minute!
Agnes, what's wrong?
So fast.
So that's why Homer came sneaking back.
I had my Benedict Arnold.
I just...
You and Homer came around because he saw how Kathleen...
Homer!
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna get even. That's what I'm gonna do.
Homer!
What are you calling me, Agnes?
Yes, Homer, doll.
What's that?
I've been thinking Homer. We don't want to fight, do we?
Boy, especially now that I'm getting a horse.
A horse?
You knew I was getting one?
Boy, I've heard rumors.
That's what I saw.
In honor of our making up, you know what?
I'm gonna write to my Uncle Clifford and ask him to send you one of his horses too.
What?
Agnes!
Haffling, it's no more than he deserves.
But, but, Gee, do you think you're sure?
Why not?
He's got more horses like that than he can give away.
She, Agnes, Gee.
Is it a deal?
Sure.
And Agnes, I want you to know I've never seen anyone with a nicer nature.
[Music]
I'm now getting back to the troubles of Henry Alberts.
Agnes correctly guessing that Homer made up with her because he thought she was getting a real horse.
It's now getting even. She told Homer he too would get a horse from a uncle, but what she didn't tell him is that the horse in question is a picture drawn on a typewriter.
It is the next day in the scene opens in Homer's garage.
Have you got the tape measure against the edge of the wall, Henry?
Sure, start stretching it toward the other wall.
Okay.
Boy, Henry, can't you just see us in our boots and saddles galloping off into the sunset on Whitey?
Whitey?
That's what I'm gonna call my horse.
Suppose he's black.
I'll call him dusty.
Have you got the tape to the other wall?
Not yet. This post is in a way.
Go around it.
Around it?
We'll never find out how wide my garage is by going around post.
Sure you will, huh? When you get to the other wall, take off a foot.
Oh, okay.
No, my father's car is in the way.
Well, go over it.
Over it?
Yeah, and subtract another foot.
Okay.
How wide does it say the garages?
I'm putting the hand.
I'm 12 and a half.
I was looking at the wrong side of the table.
12 and a half last two feet for the post and car last another two feet for lawnmowers, barrels and stuff.
Oh, that leaves only two feet for the horse.
That isn't enough room.
Even if it's a small horse?
I know, but--
How big is a small horse?
Homer, it still isn't enough room.
What do I do?
This is the only place where I can keep spotty.
Spotty?
That's why I'm going to call him if he comes in two different colors.
Who's in there?
Gee whiz.
Hi, Father.
Homer, your son.
That's what I thought.
It'll do you no good to hide.
From why and it'll do you know good to play innocent either didn't I ask you to rake the leaves nearly a week ago?
Wait, I believe the subject did come up and idle conversation
Oh my grab that rake off the wall and start sure father
Boy if a father asks a son to do something that's one thing that should come before everything else if the son's a son
And a father's his father and I want you to feel his freedom come to me as you want me to come to you
Don't you oh my what are you up to he looks like he's up to something mr. Brown
He does father. I don't want you answer right off
But would it be too much trouble to move certain things out of the garage so I could move a certain thing
Move out of what certain things right?
Your car say and keep it in the driveway
Absolutely not you promise not answer right off. Oh, but you realize what leaving it in the driveway
We'll do to my cars finish, but if I have to leave my horse outside
So I think what it'll do to his finish horse. Did I say horse horse father?
before you close your mind.
Would you consider this angle?
You can't give a horse another coat of pain.
The mother was just a joke.
Very well, dear.
If you want Homer to hate you for the rest of his life,
it's no concern of mine.
He'll hate me when it's so funny.
Agnes, Homer isn't going to think it's funny.
No.
Well, I suppose I better tell him that it's all a big joke
and that I don't expect a real horse.
- Agnes, he'll explode. - He will, of course.
Well, couldn't I say Uncle Clifford's had a...
a crock failure and ran out of horses.
You're going to lie?
Good mother, if I can't tell the truth and I can't lie, what can I do?
Agnes, this is your problem. I wash my hands of the whole thing.
[music playing]
I'm sorry, Agnes, but I don't think I could.
She was.
Why not?
I'm not asking Sheila to give up her career.
I know, but the thing.
All I want you to do is render.
Tell me when she's through pulling your junk wagon.
Well, the fact of the matter is, Agnes, Sheila's just not the kind of a horse to take to a saddle.
She's not?
That goes a real outlaw.
But she pulls your junk wagon.
Well, that's something else again.
Besides, she's getting along.
When it comes to horses, Sheila ain't no chicken.
Oh, sure, but I retired a year ago only.
She enjoys her work, so...
But, gosh!
Oh, she loves to hear them bells jingle.
Oh, God, I have to get a horse.
If I don't, I'll lose homework permanently.
That's bad, is it?
I'll say.
Well, now let's sing.
Say, tell you who my do.
Yes, God's who?
'Cause he wouldn't be entirely up to specification.
Oh.
Although with little imagination,
he might be just what you want.
God!
What?
Whoa!
(upbeat music)
Do you need any help up there, father?
Father?
Gee, it's your gonna be a swell shed.
And I certainly wanna thank you for your cooperation.
Father?
Father, what are you doing now?
Shingling.
Why?
Shingling, shingling, and shut up!
(audience laughing)
Yes?
Here's a glass of water, Will.
Yes.
Step back.
I'm coming down the ladder.
Homer, I just came from the Centerboat Feed Company
and they want $9.
Mm-hmm.
For what?
A sack of oats.
For just one sack?
Although these are the best you can get, Mr. Brown.
They're not only nutritious.
They're delicious, too.
You don't say.
Yeah?
I even brought along a sample.
Mm.
They are delicious.
Homer!
[LAUGHTER]
You don't even know that it was sugar.
Mother, do you have any cream in the house?
Yes.
You spoil your dinner.
And if you're bothered by the tongue, they're even cheaper.
A tongue?
Henry, you buy just one sack.
Yes, Mr. Brown, I'll go down right now.
And Homer, it's coming out of your allowance.
Moring?
This family costs me enough without my having to shell out
for anything that eats like a horse.
Now step aside, while I go back up the ladder.
Hi, everybody!
Well, Chiwiz, it's Adam.
What?
What's that cheese leading?
So, before you say anything, remember, it's time to do the job.
What is?
But when I realized you had your heart set, I couldn't disappoint you.
- That's the best thing. - I'm afraid this is the best I can do.
His name's Otis and he's a very good friend of Sheila.
- Yes, but... - He's not an outlaw or anything.
Gee, so gentle sometimes he doesn't move at all.
And you can have him every afternoon when he's through delivering vegetables.
- Thanks, Jim. - This is what you're giving me.
- Homer. - This?
Homer, there's no need to take that attitude.
A mule is as much a horse as any.
(dramatic music)
- Come on in and have a soda on me, homeroom time.
- Oh, Henry, a darn old Mothys new.
- How are you?
- You're just getting upset over nothing.
You know what my father's gonna do with that stably built?
Turn it into a wood shed.
- Yeah? - Yeah.
- And you know who's gonna have to chop
enough wood to fill with me?
- Oh.
- A sack of oats.
What do I do with that?
Here, here's a booth over here.
Oh, gee whiz.
Agnes.
What do you want?
What are you doing with that lampag?
What do you think?
I'm scratching out this heart with our names on the lampshade.
You are?
After what you said to me in your backyard, I never want to have another thing to do with you.
Even on a lampshade.
Well, same here.
But if anyone's crossing that out, it's me.
How many of us have this lampag?
I came in all the way.
Oh, my.
And this quam.
How is this?
Oh boy!
You broke it!
That's all that.
Homer sit down next to me quick and watch for.
Do you want Mr. Dehaven to notice it's broken?
No.
What do we do?
We'll have to get a fix somehow.
We...
You and I...
I and you...
Let's go about that.
Listen, we can't desert each other when we're in common danger, Kenley.
No.
Let's call it temporary truths.
I guess it makes sense.
Sure it does Homer.
Oh boy.
Thanks.
I'm going to show you holding my hand.
I'm just trying to hide the lamp with my sleeve.
Oh.
In a way.
Hold her.
Would you like to make the truth more of the temporary?
Boy.
Gee, sure.
Oh, her.
Just to make it official, would you like to...to...
Oh boy, would I?
Oh boy.
(audience laughing)
- Miss Holler, you can have my apple-copper's picture of that heart.
- I can...
- In that case, would you have any use for a sack of oats?
(upbeat music)
[Music]
The Aldrich family came to you through the worldwide facilities of the United States Armed Forces Radio Service.
(dramatic music)
(lively music)
(upbeat music)
[Music]
(buzzing)