The Olrich family based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Ezra Stonas Henry with Jackie Kalk as Homer.
Henry! Henry Olrich!
Coming, Mother!
[applause]
When you take a typical American family, plus some friends and neighbors,
You don't have to be a teenage boy.
Well, you needn't bother to stir things up.
The boy will always attend to that.
Henry Olridge is no exception to the rule.
The scene opens in the Aldrich living room.
It's early morning.
Now, Alice.
Now, Mother.
Sam, I'm not crying.
Of course not, Alice.
Of course not, Mother.
Here, take my handkerchief.
Alice, you knew Mary would be doing a thing like this,
eventually.
Yes, only.
Sam, she's so young.
You and Father wouldn't want me around the house for the rest of your lives, would you?
It's just a matter of getting used to the idea, out of it.
You'll get over it in no time.
Of course you will, Mother.
Henry Oldridge!
Oh, Gee whiz.
Henry!
Henry Oldridge, how long have you been there under that piano?
Why are you not long, Mary?
Dear, please get off the floor with your clean sweater.
Yes, Mother.
And what's in that gunny sack beside you?
Gunny sack?
Mother, that's no gunny sack.
No.
Gee whiz, no.
Then what is it?
Hi Mrs. Aldrich.
My goodness!
Santa Coma!
An understandable mistake, Alice.
And would you mind telling us what you and Homer were doing under that piano?
Doing, Father?
If you please.
Why you?
You might say we're looking for a golf ball, Father,
that accidentally rolled under there from the hall.
A golf ball?
Yes, sir, and I was helping him.
You don't say?
Yes, sir.
Then may I ask why you didn't let us know you were there?
Why, uh...
We didn't think it was polite to interrupt you.
Henry Aldrich, I never thought you'd stupid-slow with spying under piano on your own sister.
Spying? Mary, I was spying?
Yes, you were.
Well, honest, Mary, we hardly heard a word.
Did we, Homer?
No, hardly a word.
Well, then, suppose you each take an apple and go outside.
Outside? Yes.
Before we find out why Mary's leaving home.
Homer?
Mr. Aldrich, I'm not nosy.
I'm just naturally curious.
When the time comes for you boys to know, you will be told.
Now run along, Henry.
Yes, Father. Come on, Homer.
Well, other...
Mother, won't you please give me your permit?
Boy, Henry, why do you suppose they're throwing Mary out of the house?
Homer, they're not.
No. She's throwing them out?
No, she's just leaving peacefully.
What for?
Don't you get it?
Mary's finally getting married.
Mary? Sure.
To a fella?
Homer.
It's just that I've always looked at her as just a member of your family.
Not someone in person would marry.
Why not?
She was when you forget your prejudice.
Mary's really a darn good looking girl.
She is?
Sure.
Henry, who do you think she's doing it to?
Doing what to?
Getting married to.
Gene.
Kermit Hannigan, I guess.
The Kermit Hannigan who's a reporter on the time.
Well, who else could it be?
Oh, boy.
- Hi Henry, you'll be able to get your name in the paper any time you want.
- Not exactly, Homer.
Kermit sort of specializes in obituaries.
- No, Mary, I must thought my housework.
- For what you say, you'll let me first.
- Alice, why not?
- Sam, I told you, Henry, why aren't you outside?
- Why, we're just about to go, Mother.
Come on, Homer.
- Okay, and good luck, Mary.
- Homer, we're not supposed to know.
- You see, Mother, even Homer approves.
Dear Homer is not your mother.
Why not say yes and get it over with?
Well, Mary, will you ask Alvin to let you come home to lunch every day?
All the way home?
Well, Mary, I'm sure he can spare you for that long.
Well, I'll ask him.
And tell him I insist that you take a nap in the afternoon.
No, Alice.
Sam, she's always been a little weak since she had her tonsils out.
That was when she was 12.
I know, but she's never completely recovered.
Mother.
No, Alice, I was 14 when I got my first job, and it did me a world of good.
Yes, Sam, but your tonsils were like iron.
Alice, why get so upset over a little thing like Mary getting a job?
Sam, old rich, if your only daughter were going to work in a hard list
or filled with saws and chisels, you'd be upset too.
- Area your sodas, boys. - Thanks, Mr. Dehaven.
Now, I let be, Mrs. Kilmer.
She was... imagine. Poor little Mary getting married.
Homer, what's so terrible about that?
She was all people have to get married sometime.
Show me one person who isn't.
You're in Harriet.
She's a rare case, Homer.
Besides, she's going to marry Alvin Springer someday.
The one who owns Springer's hardware?
Yeah. When?
Someday.
She better hurry if she's going to.
Homer, she's not that old.
She's just around 40.
Sure.
But where around 40?
Just around it, Homer.
She's been that way for as long as I can remember.
Well, 40's a good place to get stuck, I guess.
Gee, you know, it's going to feel funny with Mary out of the house.
Funny how?
Oh, no.
Oh, mister.
Gee, there's one swell kid, Mary.
When I think of all the swell arguments we've had together,
gee, there's one swell kid.
Henry, you'll get over it.
Sure, but just the same.
Every time I pass your empty room, I'll get a pain right here.
Excuse me, Henry.
Did I hear you say you had an empty room?
What's that, Mr. de Haven?
If it's for rent, my nephew might go as high as $6 a week.
$6?
Take it, Henry.
Take it.
Now, wait a minute, Homer.
Mr. de Haven, we're not renting the room.
It's just that my sister Mary is getting married, we think.
You don't say.
What's that Mrs. Kilmer?
Do you have to give a body to help me die?
Yes, I'll be right with you.
Well, if you decide to rent that room, Henry, let me know.
Gee, Henry, six dollars. Why did you turn him down?
Because it's ridiculous, that's why.
What's ridiculous about it?
You said yourself every time you pass her room, you'll get a pain right here.
Oh, sure, only what would my father say?
Henry he'll probably double your allowance if you bring in six extra dollars a week.
I don't know.
You might even get more than six dollars if you throw in breakfast.
Breakfast?
Home or my mother would never agree.
Why not?
What's one more stranger at breakfast?
But that takes all the profit out of Henry.
How much can one egg and one orange and one cup of coffee cost?
Ten cents.
Fifteen at the most.
Twenty tops.
Suppose he wants two eggs.
We'll put that in the contract one egg or his rent goes up
Well, it's a matter of fact if we're getting ate for breakfast think of all we could get if we throw in dinner now
Listen home Henry if your mother doesn't object to breakfast. Why should she did dinner?
But Daisy
Who was that on the phone Mary? Daisy Hoffman.
And mother she's never said anything so strange to me in my life.
Strange? How?
Well I know sooner lifted the receiver when she said, "Why didn't I tell her first?"
And then she burst out crying. What? Then she hung up.
What do you suppose me to say that? I can't imagine.
Unless... Unless what?
You don't think she wanted that job at Springer's too. You think so?
Well my goodness she certainly has her nerves.
Especially when she knows I'm taking the job because of Kermit.
Kermit, yes. He asked me what I did during the day.
And mother, I've never been so tongue tied in my life.
Well, I've seen who that is.
Hello?
Alice, this is Sam. Do you know any other orchards in Centerville?
Are they orchards?
Yes. They might rent rooms.
No, Sam. Why?
I just had a call from a man who heard from another man that we have a room for rent.
We?
With breakfast.
My goodness.
What did you tell him?
- The city obviously had the wrong party.
- I should say so.
My goodness, we just about have enough room for ourselves.
(upbeat music)
Can you hear me from under the car, Chester?
- Yeah, sure.
Hand me that hammer.
- Gee, sure.
- I'll get it, and I'll get it.
Here, Chester.
- Oops.
- Oh boy.
Did that get you, Chester?
Well, not quite. It was a good try though.
What's the best offer you've gotten for the room so far?
Gia fella went to eight dollars, not more than ten minutes ago.
As high as that?
Did we mention breakfast was included?
Yeah. And it's a nice room?
I'll say it has double exposure.
Oh yeah?
The person who's moving out had it for nearly nineteen years.
You don't say. Where is this room, Henry?
Well, if I get permission at our house, yours, I didn't know you had an extra room.
We don't. But we're losing Mary.
Mary, your sister? She's sick?
No. She's getting married.
Oh, you don't say. Who's a lucky guy?
Well, I'm not absolutely positive.
And, gee, I wouldn't want to start any unfounded rumors.
Oh, naturally. Henry, I'll take the room.
You will?
Oh, boy, Henry.
I'll tell you the truth. I'm not very happy where I am.
Well, I'll tell you I'll have to get my mother and father's permission first. Well, that shouldn't be any trouble student
Well, I don't think so. Henry you won't have any trouble at all. Okay. Nobody excuse me when I make a phone call
Sure Chester old kid Henry, why don't we celebrate with a soul?
L nine nine six
Henry were you calling on Chester? How are the acoustics and Mary's room the acoustics?
Well, Mary never had any trouble with him.
Oh?
Mrs. Smith, this is Chester.
You know, the fellow who has your front room?
Yes.
Mrs. Smith, are you still against my practicing in my room?
I am.
Well, in that case, Mrs. Smith,
that my interest you to know that I'm taking my instrument and moving.
Well, I'm certainly glad to hear that.
I've got at least 20 people waiting to snap up that rule.
[Music]
Mr. Dehaven, could I have a tube of toothpaste please?
By sure thing Mary. Here you are. I guess you're looking forward to the big day.
My goodness, how did you hear about that?
Oh, I heard. Congratulations.
Thank you, Mr. Dehaven.
It must be pretty excited.
I am. It's my first.
I assumed it was.
Here's the money for the toothpaste.
Thank you.
Who's the lucky man?
Aren't you nice?
I wouldn't call him lucky exactly.
I'm very inexperienced.
What is Alvin Springer?
Who?
Alvin Springer.
The Alvin Springer that's put...
Alvin Springer?
Yes.
I've got to run along now.
If you need any hardware, drop in.
Yes.
Yes, thank you.
I will.
I'll catch you.
Oh, she was.
She watched me.
Come on goodness, it's you two.
She was.
Hi, Mary.
Henry, I'm in a hurry.
Goodbye, Mary.
And we know that I take a good look at her.
You're right.
She's darn pretty.
I know.
She the more I look at her.
The more I wish I'd noticed her when she was available.
Are you and Mary?
What's so crazy about that?
Well, hello there, boys.
Hi Mr. Dehaven, two double skyscrapers.
Yes sir.
And Mr. Dehaven, in view of business conditions,
I don't think we can let your nephew have it for six.
At what? Mary's room.
Oh yes.
Well Henry, you could have bolded me over with a feather
when she told me who she was married.
She told you?
Sure.
And the last man in the world I'd think of would be Alvin Springer.
What?
Alvin Springer.
Old Alvin Springer?
Oh, gee whiz, Mr. Dehaven, you must be mistaken.
She's not marrying Mr. Springer.
She's marrying Kermit Hannigan.
Henry, she just told me herself.
Whose guy's scraper's come to help?
She whiz, Henry.
Mr. Springer.
Homer, of course, it has its good side.
You'll never have to worry about nuts and bolts again.
Don't be ridiculous.
Mr. Dehaven must have misunderstood, Mary.
What?
Gee whiz, Mr. Springer's promised to my Aunt Harriet.
Why would he marry Mary?
Henry, tell me the truth.
If you had your choice between Mary and your Aunt Harry,
at which would you take?
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Olbridge.
Henry and Homer have unwittingly started a rumor that Mary is about to be married.
But when the story returns to the boys, they're dumbfounded to learn that old Alvin Springer
has entered the picture as Mary's prospective bridegroom.
The scene opens in Alvin's hardware store. It is later that day.
Hello there, Mr. Springer.
Well, hello, Mary.
I thought I'd stop by and tell you I can take the job.
Well, that's fine.
My goodness, I had a terrible time before they said yes.
Where's everyone so against women working?
Speaking of that, Mary...
Yes, Mr. Springer.
I hope you won't think I'm prying, but once you start working here, you'll stay, won't you?
My goodness, why shouldn't I?
Well, I've been hearing a rumor that you see, Mary, it takes time to train someone,
and once I do, I want to be sure...
You're not planning on getting married, are you?
My goodness, no.
Good.
That is my goodness, yes.
I mean, naturally, I hope to marry someday.
But the young man I have in mind feels he should work his way out of obituaries first.
And you know how long a thing like that can take.
Now, don't get the idea. I'm against marriage.
As a matter of fact, can you keep a secret?
Oh, yes.
I proposed your Aunt Harriet last night.
You did?
Mm-hmm.
Well, my goodness.
I'm so happy I'm going to kiss you.
Oh.
There.
Uncle Alton.
Mary, right in the front window of the store.
Mary, my goodness, why not?
We're practically in the same family.
Yes, now that you mention it.
Well, I've got to be going.
Oh, goodbye, Mary.
See you Monday morning, 9 o'clock.
9 o'clock sharp.
Mary, wait a minute.
Mary, shouldn't you carry the tin first?
Three.
My goodness, why are you so flushed?
Mary, I didn't believe it when I heard it.
And boy, if I hadn't seen it with my own eyes,
I'd never believed it.
I believe what?
Naturally, you're free to do whatever you please, but you certainly ought to think of your family.
What are you talking about?
You know very well, and I certainly don't blame Mother for not wanting to give her permission.
Henry, why should you object to that?
Why not? Boy, I'll be the laughing stock of Centerville!
Just because I...
Why, Henry, I never imagined you were that old-fashioned.
What?
And this is your free country, and I'll thank you, remember the Bill of Rights.
Okay, Mary. Okay.
But wait until father hears about this.
- Can we come back?
And may interest you to know we already had.
- Mary.
- Yes, Homer?
I may have a way out.
- How to what?
- Mary.
Mary, if I were to ask you to wait for me,
would it sound ridiculous?
- Wait for you to what?
- She already sounds ridiculous.
(audience laughing)
- Homer, you mean wait for you to marry me?
- Are you mad?
- Well, no, of course I'm not mad, Homer.
You're not. Oh boy.
The only thing is, of course, I'd have to keep going to school until maybe Sunday I graduate.
But if you're helping with my algebra, that shouldn't take more than three or four years.
Homer!
And naturally, you'd have to get my parents consent to give me away.
But that shouldn't be too hard.
Homer! Yes, Mary.
Dear.
Homer, naturally, I'm very flat.
You're very sweet to ask me, but I'm afraid it's out of the question.
Well, if it's money you're worried about, Mary, I think I can get my father to raise my allowance.
Oh, I don't have time to explain now, but I'm afraid I have someone else's mind.
I know, but, Mary, don't you think I'm an improvement?
Mary.
Now, Chester, control yourself.
Control myself, Mr. Orr.
Do you realize what your son's done to me?
Mr. Smith has already rented my room.
I appreciate that, Chester.
I've got my bags and my instrument case outside
where I'm going to put them.
Instrument case?
Mr. Orr, I'm afraid I'm going to have to insist
that you find me someplace to live.
But, yes.
And until then, there's just one thing I can do.
Move in here.
Here, in my office, I can sleep on the couch.
No, Chester.
As we move the water cooler in here, I can shave by the window.
Now, wait a minute.
Your father here?
Henry, come in here.
Oh, boy, Father, do you know what's happening?
Would I know what's going to happen? You're going to march right out of here and not come back until you found Chester a room.
Chester? Oh gee, will you?
Oh, you sure got me in a fine pickle Henry.
I know, but it wasn't definite.
Henry, let's not waste time. Mark.
But father, you heard him, Henry. And make sure the room's big enough for my glockenspiel.
Mother, I could die. I could just die.
Mary calmed down.
Mother, how can I?
You will have to try.
Your nervous system won't be in any condition for dinner.
But, Mother, don't you realize what I heard on the bus?
What?
I'm getting married.
Isn't that wonderful?
Dear, you mean just because you overheard
some idle conversation on the bus.
You were jumping to a conclusion like that.
Mother, it was Mrs. Kilmer, and she's never wrong.
Oh, yes, but who is it?
I don't know.
Mrs. Kilmer got off the bus before I found out.
For my goodness.
Do you suppose those roses had anything to do with it?
What, Rosie?
Well, they came for you a little while ago.
From who?
I don't know.
There was no card with them.
But do you know what was in the box?
I'll answer the door, mother.
Try to control yourself.
Dear, your hair's coming back.
I'm controlled, mother.
I'm controlled.
But in a business tree--
what, Kermit?
Hello, Mary.
Hello.
Come in.
Thank you.
Did my roses arrive yet?
Oh.
Oh, you're the one!
Well, after I heard the news, I thought...
...there to show you how I feel, Mary.
Oh, my goodness.
But the reason I came over is...
...did you happen to find my umbrella among the roses?
Your umbrella?
It wasn't until I got back to the office that I noticed I had the car that went with the flowers in my hand and my umbrella was gone.
Oh, I'll certainly keep my eye out, poorness.
Thank you.
And you didn't have to go to anything as expensive as flowers.
That's okay, Mary.
After all, a thing like this only comes once in a lifetime.
And Mary.
Yes, Kern.
We'll always be friends, won't we?
I certainly hope so.
And I'm sure you will be very happy.
I hope you will be too.
I'll try, but frankly, it may be a little hard.
Well, Kern, Miss.
Mary, I guess this is goodbye.
Good-bye, aren't you coming over tonight?
Well, Mary, after all, I mean, do you think I should?
My goodness, why not?
Well, I mean...
What will Mr. Sprinter say?
Mr. Springer, what does he have to know?
Mary!
Just because I'm going to work in his hardware store?
Work! You're going to work after you're married?
Well, of course, Kermit, that's up to you.
Me?
Yeah. I feel the husband should always decide things like that.
Mary. Mary, do you mind if I sit down on this umbrella stand? I suddenly feel weak.
Of course not.
Mary, aren't you marrying Alvin Springer?
What?
Oh, that's what I heard. I mean someone told me Henry said that I think.
Well, if that isn't the most ridiculous thing I ever heard.
You mean you're not.
Now, Kermit, why should I marry someone like Alvin when I knew you were just around the corner?
I mean...
Mary...
What, Kermit, why...
I'm stuck in the umbrella stand.
Hi there, can I have my supper now?
Henry, oh, did you come in here?
Mary, I haven't got time to...
What are you doing here?
Henry, what are you going around saying?
Well, I'm saying something, Mary.
Henry, Mary is marrying Alvin.
She is?
Of course not, I'm just working for him.
Wow, Gee, way!
And you should know better than to start rumors like that.
Mary, I give you my word of honor.
I didn't start it.
No.
She was.
No, I heard it from someone.
Who?
Let me think now.
Who was it?
Henry, is that you?
Oh, Gee, with...
Yes, Father?
Henry, have you...
- Father, aren't you going to say hello to Kermit?
- Oh, yes, hello Kermit, Henry.
- Mr. Aldige, while I have you here.
While I have you here, sir.
- Wait until I've done it Kermit.
We ever discuss things with Father on an empty stomach.
- What's that?
- And Father, if you're worried as to why I'm home,
all I'm going to do is get a little nourishment,
then I'm going to put my nose right back
to the grindstone and fine Chester a room.
- You haven't found one yet?
- Father, honest, I've looked everywhere.
The only empty room I could find was in the YWCA.
I see.
And they won't let Chester above the ground floor there.
Hey Henry!
What's Homer doing here at a time like this?
It must be dinner time.
Hey, where can I have Chester a room?
You have? Oh boy, Father, did you hear that Gee whiz Homer? Where did you find one?
Homer in my house.
Your house? I didn't know you had an extra room Homer.
We haven't. I'm renting a mine.
You're?
For $14.
So, Hinn, could you come outside and help me with my trunk?
What?
Your trunk?
What's your trunk doing over here?
Well, Jean, Mr. Olrich, I've better have some place to live.
Now, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Once and for all, we are not renting any rooms in this house.
But, Mr. Olrich, that's the beautiful part of it.
I don't intend to pay a cent.
[applause]
[music]
Listen again next week, same time, same station, for another sparkling half-hour with your favorite youngster, his family and his pals.
The Aldrich family starring Ezra Stone is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
[Music]