[Music]
Henry Henry Audrey!
Coming, Mother.
[Music]
The Aldrich family, starring as Restoned, written by Clifford Goldsmith,
Brought to you by Jell-O-footing, those delicious new desserts all America's talking about.
[Music]
The Aldrich family can be seen now in the current Paramount picture of what alive.
Don't miss it.
And tonight Betty Field, one of the stars of the picture, plays Barbara Pearson, Henry's current girlfriend.
As usual on the air, the part of Henry Aldrich is played by Ezra Stone.
In the living room of the Aldrich home, Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich are talking.
Henry is just coming in through the hall door.
Well, then, remember how worried we were a week ago?
Over Henry.
And that terrible constant mark.
Who's interested in this week?
He's coming back to Barbara Pearson.
Mother!
Yes, Henry.
May I ask you a question?
Yes.
Are you sure you won't mind if I ask him?
Well, no.
Could I have $3?
We're all.
Could I please?
What for?
Well, I've got to get something, mother, before it's gone.
Can't you tell me what it is?
Well, you'll just think it's foolish.
Then I'm afraid, dear.
You cannot have the $3.
You mean you don't trust me?
Well, would you mind not standing directly in my light, Henry?
I'm sorry, Father.
Why don't you ask your father, Father?
I know he wouldn't give it to me.
Would your father?
Would you?
No, would I want?
Well, I'll tell you, this is all I want.
This is all there is to it.
Practically every guy I know that's got a girl
has given her something to wear.
Henry, you mean the boys give their things
to wear nowadays?
Oh, sure, it may sound a little strange,
but I mean things like class pin.
Only my class hasn't got a pin.
- Well, I thought you did give Barbara
some kind of a pin.
- I did, mother, but she isn't crazy about it.
- Why not?
- Well, in the first place, all it says on it
is vote the Democratic ticket.
Would you like it if that was all somebody
could afford to give you?
- But the important thing is the sentiment behind it.
- I know if that's a trouble.
Her father's a Republican.
- A Republican?
- Yeah.
- But I think you'd better stay away
from their house in the future.
This is no time to joke.
Here's the position I'm in.
I told Barbara, in fact I practically promised her I'd give her a pin.
You know, the one I saw downtown, the jewelry store.
Henry, dear, knowing Barbara Pearson as I do,
I don't believe that what you give her is even slightly important.
But she was there, thought you wanted me to take an interest in Barbara Pearson.
I even promised her I'd never go inside Constant Marshall's house again.
Wouldn't you like encouragement?
Henry, you may not under any circumstances have any money.
I'm not asking for money, mother.
You're not.
I've given that up.
When did you give it up?
Just now.
This is all I want.
Now, don't fly off the handle, father.
It isn't as bad as it's going to sound at first.
You know that gold five beta cap of key you wear on your watch chain?
I do.
Well, uh...
Do you wear that quite a little?
You mean to say you're going to ask me for it?
Well, don't you ever get tired of it and wish you could wear something else now and then?
In other words, you want to give Barbara Pearson my five-eighter capacity.
You feel that strong about it?
That's wrong.
I'm just suggesting you loan it to her father and you can go back to the vote the Democratic ticket pin.
Hi, Henry. Mind the black men?
Come on in, Dizzy.
I want to speak to you alone, Henry.
Good evening, Dizzy.
Hello, Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich.
Henry, I've got to speak to you alone.
What about?
Just something.
Can't you tell him here, Dizzy?
Oh, this is in strict confidence, Mrs. Alders.
Well, I'm trying to get a decision about something, Dizzy.
Henry, if I were you, I'd go out and see what Dizzy wants.
Okay.
Come on out here in the hall, Henry.
It's private?
Wait till I tell you.
Can anyone hear through that door?
No.
What are you doing tomorrow, Eden?
Why?
Well, hold on to something.
How would you like a blind date?
A blind date?
Sure.
Me?
She's a dream.
Henry, you never saw a prettier girl in your life.
Have you seen her?
No, but my girl has.
But I've got a date tomorrow night with Barbara Pearson.
Listen, Henry, you can see Barbara anytime.
But this girl?
She's visiting my girl only a few days.
Oh, I see.
Well, you see, does he...
I just got one misunderstanding straightened out with Barbara.
You don't help me out, I'm sunk.
Henry, what are you and Izzy talking about out there in the hall?
Oh nothing mother.
We were just discussing a problem I had Mrs. Aldrin.
If you don't mind, I'll leave this door open.
It's terribly close in the living room.
Well, let's go into the dining room.
Don't you think you ought to get to know other girls?
Do you want to stay in a ruff?
That's what started the trouble I just got over.
Look, will this help?
Supposing I get the girl on the telephone.
Why?
So you can sound around?
"No." "Then what can I do to convince you?" "Well, uh...
Have you got three dollars?" "For what?" "Well, just as a loan."
"Listen, she's begging for a chance to meet you. Meet me?" "Sure!"
"I think you know about me. If I remember correctly, she thinks she saw you on the street
the other day." "Say come to think?" "I wonder if she's
a one-ice walk does she have a high black hat with a sort of a veil that sure
is that right who has a black hat in the veil nobody father would you mind
talking so I either can hear you or so I can't maybe we better go in the kitchen
okay
now do you see what's ahead of you Henry the only thing let me call her up and
ask her whether she's got a bail. Do you have any way of raising three dollars, Dizzy?
I've got to pay you to meet a beautiful girl? I promise, Barbara, that when I see you tomorrow
night, I'll have a pen for it. All right, you wait. You wait. Just you wait until sometime you
ask me to do something for you. I'm sorry, Henry, but you both have to get out of this kitchen
while I do some work here. Where do we go now, Henry? Let's go upstairs. Your father just went
upstairs, Henry. Well, then let's go out and have him been in the living room yet. That's right.
Come on, let's go in there.
Would you boys mind telling me what all this is about?
I'm trying to make Henry see the light, Mrs. Allred.
See, Henry, I've got an idea.
I haven't got a pin you could give, Bobber, but I've got a lady's ring.
Where'd you get it?
I found it.
I found it in a trash pile.
Is it any good?
It's gold with a black stone and pearls.
And if I help you out tomorrow night, you'll give it to me?
Well, I won't give it to you, but I'll loan it to you.
Say yes, Henry.
Well, of shaking, we'll make it a bargain.
No.
If I give you the ring out, right, will you let me?
And I can tell Barbara to keep us sure.
And it isn't going to cost me anything?
Not a cent.
All we'll do is sit around in the house.
Something tells me dizzy.
I shouldn't say yes.
And something tells you that you shouldn't say no to, doesn't it?
Remember that black hat with the veil?
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Hello, operating?
Alfa, fire!
I want Elm, free, free, free!
From now on, Henry, your lucky number is free.
Are you going free, free, free?
Yes, ma'am.
I wonder if she's doing anything tonight.
The only thing is to see, even if you do get this girl, you can't tell from her voice what she looks like.
Why not?
All I've got to do is hear one word and I can size up a girl in a minute.
minute. Oh, what was that?
Listen, if that's the girl you're trying to get for me, does he? You can hang up. Who is this
speaking?
Hang up, my girl's aunt. Oh, what is going on here? Nothing, Father. Hello, this is
Dizzy. All the girls in?
Out? Ask her whether her friend, you know, your girlfriend's friend has a veil. Does your
Nice have a veil. Mrs. Hopkins you can tell that will be all set for tomorrow. Thank you
Mrs. Hopkins. Goodbye. Your boys find the veil. Well only in the way we did father.
Henry could you walk to the door with me? Sure. All I want to say Henry. If you don't
I want to all take it.
Oh, you don't. I saw her first, didn't I?
When do I get that ring?
I'll get it for you by noon tomorrow.
Why not before then?
I've got to get it from my girl.
From your girl?
Sure, she's wearing it.
She's wearing it?
At night, Henry.
Hey, Disney.
I wonder whether Barbara will mind if she finds that out.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
- What's the matter, grandmother?
- What are you flying around so far?
- This is the evening Henry's coming over.
- Huh, you suppose you bring a box candy?
- What is the evening paper?
- Right here.
- Let me have the movie section.
- Grandmother, will you promise me something?
- Huh?
that you won't embarrass me by asking him whether he ever sees any other girls.
Oh my goodness, don't you think you're not alone?
It makes it look as though I were worried.
Oh, God, she should be.
Here's a picture I'd like to see.
All right, if I come in.
Hello, Henry.
I've only got a second, then I've got to be going.
So soon.
Oh, Henry?
Good evening, Mrs. Anderson.
Did I hear you say, young man, you can't stay?
Well, something came up quite unexpectedly.
You don't say how the constant marshal these days.
Oh, she haven't seen her for over a week.
Mm-hmm.
I'm never going to see constants again.
Well, you know, excuse me, I'll go out in the kitchen and make some candy.
The only reason why I have to go so soon is because I have an examination of Marlborough.
And what?
In Geometry.
By the way, I just happened to think I brought you something.
My section doesn't have an examination of Geometry tomorrow.
You know? I wonder how you could account for a thing like that.
Oh, wonder.
Well, here's what I brought you.
What is it?
It's instead of a pin.
Henry, I hope you didn't go and get me something expensive.
Well, I just hope you'll like it.
Henry, oh, look at it. It's a ridge.
Sure.
Oh, Henry, you shouldn't have brought anything like this.
Oh, I didn't pay much for it.
It's a little too large for that thing, dude.
Well, try the next thing.
Too large for that one.
Well, how about the next one?
It's still too big.
Do you suppose you could wear it on your thumb?
I know. I'll wear it on this chain around my neck.
Hey, do I make a candy? Why don't we all go to the movie tonight?
It's a picture called Man Crazy that I want to see.
But Mrs. Sanderson, I've got a geometry exam coming.
I think you've got your schedule mixed in.
I'm sure I am. And Dizzy has the same schedule I have.
Let me give you some advice young man. I never studied geometry in my life
There isn't anything going on that I don't know about well if it's money it's worrying you the trick is beyond me
Oh, that isn't it. I've got you want to go go get your coat on bobber and we'll stop grandmother
Maybe he doesn't want to go. Well, of course, I might be able to you want to call your parents an ask
I don't think you need to you want me to laugh on them. Oh, no, you don't have to
No, you suppose that is.
They were all after the door.
Do you think that you really could go with us?
I'd certainly like to, but if I don't get my studying done tonight, when will I?
Good evening, Mrs. Anderson. This Henry here?
You certainly are.
Is that you, Dizzy?
Hurry up, Henry. We're going to be late.
Late for where?
We plan to study together.
Study what?
Our geometry. Our geometry.
When?
Now you dope over at my house.
Oh yeah! You don't say so.
Didn't I tell you it wasn't tonight that you'd have to study in the week?
Well whether it is or not, uh, Dizzy, I think you'll have to study without me.
Huh? Um, could I have a little conference with you out in the hall?
It isn't necessary to talk it over.
Speak to me in private?
Uh, Bob, would that's a nice ring you're wearing around your neck?
Yes, you are. Let me see it. It's gold. Now, where did you get it?
Hand my baby to me. Oh, is that right?
Uh, I'll go out my hall with you, Dizzy.
Why don't we all stay here and study? Well, I have to be alone when I study,
Barbara. That's why you got to be with Henry?
Are you sure you understand, Barbara? Of course.
If you tell me you have to study, you have to. Sure.
It never occurred to me that I shouldn't understand.
Well...
Goodbye.
Don't study too late, boy.
Oh, we won't, Mr. Sanderfuss.
Hurry up, Henry.
Tony's been waiting for us for 20 minutes.
Who has?
Constance Marshall.
She's my girl, now, you dulpe.
Since when?
Since you finished with her.
This is a fine time to tell me.
I can't go over there.
I promise, Barbara, I wouldn't see her anymore.
I'm not seeing her. I'm seeing her.
You just happen to be going over to her house?
No.
Do you want me to go back and ask Barbara for that ring?
I'd like to see you.
Oh, you don't think I do it, eh?
I'll go right back into my house.
Wait, is he waiting?
Are you going?
I'll stick by you.
But something tells me I'm going to be sorry for as long as I live.
Henry and Disney are just going up the steps of constant smart little town
For some reason or other Henry doesn't look very cheerful
43 high street
Didn't I tell you three years of lucky number?
Hi, ya Connie. Why Henry? Oh, did I thought Connie wasn't ever gonna see you again?
Hi, ya Connie. He got lonesome. I got lonesome. Oh, come on in
Where's uh, where's- Oh, of course. Just a minute now, Cola.
Gwendolyn! Gwendolyn!
Is that her name?
What do you have?
Dizzy, I'm going home.
Well, well, well. If it isn't Henry himself.
And you're just as cute as I thought you'd be.
Gwendolyn, that isn't Henry. That's Dizzy.
You mean... this one here is Henry?
Yes.
Well...
I'm sorry.
What are you putting down your hat for, Henry?
Well, I thought we were going to stay.
Oh my goodness, what can we do here?
We're going out?
Don't you like to go out at night, Henry?
Sure he does, don't you, Henry?
We want to go to the movies.
In the movies?
Yeah, we want to see men crazy.
I know, but...
Come on, little, get our things on.
I better wear my coat in case we get some ice cream after work.
Dizzy, I haven't got enough money to take them out.
You don't have to pay for all of this.
Just for yourself and Glamoury.
I know, but I haven't even enough for that.
For that? For that? Oh, just some. You told me this wouldn't cost anything. And did you take a look at Gwendolyn? One helping of ice cream isn't going to be enough for her.
Henry, cheer up. 25 years from now you'll be able to look back and laugh at this. Sure. 25 years from now, but this is tonight.
Henry, you're beginning to make me sorry I brought you.
But, Dizzy, she's not the girl I saw on the street. No wonder she wears a veil. What she should do was wear it in the house.
Now I am sorry.
Well, we're already dizzy.
Uh, Quentin and you leave dizzy alone. Henry is your property.
I'm her property?
That's what I'll call ya, my prop.
Come on, prop. Let me take you on.
The only thing is I promised my folks I'd be in early.
But you don't belong to them anymore? You belong to me.
Look at them own, Henry.
Yeah. And look at those three stars right up over us. Yeah. Henry, didn't I tell
you three as your lucky number? Let's get on this street. D.C. go Connie something.
Why did you want me to give back that ring? Well I had to do a favor for
somebody. You didn't give it to any other girl did you? No. Say look
Constance here on the corner. What is it? A soda fountain. Yeah? Oh boy do they
They serve terrible sodas in there.
Listen, these are good.
Look in the window there, Henry.
At what?
Those boxes of candy.
Don't you think we're going to be late for the first show?
Oh, we don't care whether we're late.
It looks like an awfully nice place inside.
Would you like to go in and get waves?
Say, you can't get me on any scales.
Well, why don't we stop here after the show?
I never liked to eat anything just before I go to bed.
Come on, Henry.
You might as well go in and get it over with.
Mmm!
Both those roasted almonds smell good.
Don't they?
Where shall we sit?
Let's take this table here by the candy counter.
Okay.
Good evening.
What do you have?
I'll have a chocolate marshmallow.
Same here.
Make it free chocolate marshmallows.
I want glass of water.
Why, Henry.
Aren't you going to eat anything?
I'm in training.
Oh, isn't that true bad?
Read chocolate marshmallows in the glass of water.
Right.
You ought to change your mind, Henry. They're good here.
All right, then?
Why, Henry? What are you worrying about?
Worried? Worried?
Who's worried?
Say, Dizzy, let's go down there to the end of the star and look at those magazines.
Why do we have to look at those?
Oh, please, Dizzy, Izzy.
Oh...
I don't think you'll ask me.
Well, I guess Connie and Henry are all alone.
I guess we are.
Henry, no thanks normal picturesque.
You don't think the longs are these?
Oh, you're not a...
Henry, that Bob repressed in a grandmother.
Constance, would you understand if I should go...
And leave me at the table all alone?
Where's Henry?
Oh, Richard.
Good evening, Mrs. Anderson.
Henry!
Oh, your geometry.
Constance, I guess you know...
Mrs. Sanderson and Barbara don't know.
Oh, yeah!
Would...
Would you like to sit down here with us?
No, thank you, Henry, all of the time.
I wouldn't even be slightly interested.
Oh, you wouldn't, wouldn't you, Barbara?
What is that you got on that chain?
That happens to be a ring, thank you.
That happens to be my ring, thank you.
So that's why he asked me for it.
I didn't ask you for it.
You'll needn't explain Henry Arch. Take your hard ring.
But I don't want it.
This whole thing is a mistake.
You take it off right away.
I don't know anything foolish, young lady. That's gold.
What if it is there?
Oh my. Where did it go?
Henry, all the time. I think you're contentable.
Listen, Barbara, let me tell you.
No. Aren't you going to introduce me to your friends, Henry?
Gwendolyn, please go away.
And what's more, Henry Otis?
I think you're the meanest person who never drew the life of breath.
The life of breath.
Where did that ring go?
What do I kid?
I'm going home.
You're going to let a thing like this spoil the movies for you?
Yes.
Oh, life of breath.
A life of breath.
See, who does she think she is?
Well, what I want to know is who dizzy thinks he is.
Huh! Giving my ring to that little snip.
Pardon me. You hear your Sundays and hears you check.
Say, yeah. Where is Dizzy?
One day came in, he left.
He left? Yeah.
That'll be 45 cents.
You like to pay for it now?
I'd like to, but I can.
This is a nice predicament.
[Music]
Oh, look y'all, Austin! I'm going to the door!
Oh, you!
Yes, Mrs. Sanderson.
Oh, you're the last person in the world, I expected to see tonight?
If, um...
If Barbara hasn't gone to bed yet...
Could you tell her I'm here, please?
Oh, cool. I don't think it'll do any good.
Barbara?
Barbara!
You probably heard you.
Yes, Grandma.
From here a minute.
Where are you?
I'm in the front hall!
Well...
Hello, Barbara.
Oh.
Oh, all I want to do is tell you exactly what happened.
I know what happened.
But you don't.
Come on in out of the cold, Henry.
All right.
I don't think I better come on in.
Come in.
I won't let her hurt you.
Yes, ma'am.
No matter what you say, Henry, it won't do a bit of good.
The only reason I didn't stay here
with you in the first place, Barbara,
was because I had a blind date night.
A blind date?
Wait, you've only heard the beginning.
That's all I want to hear.
You've got to hear it all.
That ring I gave it didn't even belong to me.
A beautiful sentiment to say the least.
Oh, wait.
Now, wait a minute.
It didn't belong to any girl.
If it belonged to Dizzy, he found it.
Where?
In a trash pile.
Yeah, trash pile.
And that's what I was wearing around my neck.
But I still haven't finished.
Well, from the progress you're making young men.
may be just as well if you don't finish.
And if you excuse me, I'm going upstairs.
You don't want to hear the rest of Christ I don't.
She was--
Ah, Henry, old Regeira, genius.
But she's so unreasonable.
She won't even listen to me.
Mrs. Sanderson, what would you do in a case like this?
You want me to tell you what I do?
Yeah.
I'd stop trying to make things up.
I tell her what really did happen.
That's what I've been doing.
That's the truth.
Then I'd start him with something she could believe.
You mean I should lie to her?
No, I'm not saying you should lie to her.
But in this case, I certainly wouldn't tell her
any more of the truth.
What should I do?
Let me tell you something, young man.
And if you remember, it's going to help you just as much
as geometry, ever will.
What is it?
No woman is going to believe what you want her to.
Oh, what is she going to believe?
What she wants to do.
Is that right?
Yes, sir.
At least that's the way it is to every woman I've ever known.
And when I call Barbara down here again,
don't try to push her into believing
what you think she should think.
Well, if you don't mind, I'd rather not see her.
No, no, no.
Now you wait for you.
Barbara?
There's no use in my trying anymore
See what I mean when I say they believe what they want to
You better be careful how you talk young lady up until this evening
I always thought it was the nicest boy I'd ever known and then hello
Didn't I tell you to be careful you've got a listen Barbara?
No, but that wasn't really dizzy's ring now. We have a new story, but it wasn't really his who's was it?
well
That's something I can't tell you I
Asked my mother it didn't ever it didn't ever belong to your mother. Did it my mother? Yes
No
Henry it's dead
Why didn't you admit it in the first place? Well, because I didn't want it. Yeah, man. What?
I got the anymore stories.
She's not making this up grandmother.
How do you know?
Because, Henry, if it did belong to your mother, I'm sorry I pulled the ring away.
Y'all?
Of course I am.
Well, here it is.
Grandmother.
Have you excused me? I think I'll go up to bed.
I hope you sleep well, Mrs. Anderson.
By the way, Henry Aldrich, the story's alright as far as it goes.
Well, what were you doing Constance Marshall?
With Constance Marshall?
Do you want to know the truth?
Of course I do.
Well, that's easy to explain.
We started out and...
You what?
Well, my father wanted me to study my geometry.
But you entered the soda fountain instead?
Well...
And that was where you ran into Constance?
Yeah.
Henry.
Sure.
Doesn't that just go to show you what a person's imagination can do? I'll say
Are you sure you didn't make that up about your father wanting you to stop it? No
your profit trip
Because the whole thing sounds so simple
At the yes, mr. Sanderson your father just bones you want you to come right home and do your geometry. He does
Well, what do you know about that?
Don't ever tell me anything but the truth again, Henry.
I'll say I won't.
[Music]