[Music]
Coming, Mother!
The Oldrich family.
A special rebroadcast for you soldiers, sailors and Marines of the United Nations.
[Music]
A typical teenage boy like Henry Aldrich, lives in a world on his own.
A world of impulses, hectic activity and honest enthusiasm.
And grown-ups always welcome the opportunity of re-entering that wonderful world.
The scene opens in the older living room.
The time is Saturday afternoon.
But Henry, don't you see my point of view?
You have no life to do a thing like that.
But Mary, Charlie, talk to my son.
He's really a slow guy. He's really very good.
Look, he's helping you tell. His hair's always falling down over the front of his face.
Not when he goes out.
No, it isn't. Yes, it's a stuffy point of our habit.
Boy, it makes a step of the board.
Well, let me warn you, Henry, if Charlie Clark comes over here tonight, I won't even see him.
Why not?
Because Henry, you had no right making any such thing for me.
Mary, isn't this a very, but you and Henry, the car price allowed?
I'm not talking about it.
But you know what Henry did to me.
You know what he did to me.
What did he do?
He told me to Charlie Clark is a baseball.
[laughter]
Come, lover.
I assure you, the baseball had nothing to do with it.
And besides, Mary, do you realize how hard a thing like that is to get these days?
Mary, I always thought Charlie Clark was a very nice ball.
Oh, Charlie Clark?
How did he search the draw?
I was a little playmate for Henry, but to send an evening with him.
Mary, may I ask whatever gave you the conception of Charlie Clark is my little playmate?
I am in the ring.
Hi, how are you?
Oh, my God.
I need help to wait for her.
Let's see.
Oh, my God.
I have to wait until I get married right now.
See, I don't want to hear any more about this.
Now, please go outside with Homer and play ball.
Yes, Mother.
I'll go.
Only Charlie Clark thinks you have a play for tonight.
You're made of heaven, Heather.
You're the one who'll have to keep it with us.
I am.
Let's see that boy here, Charlie.
It's right here.
No more flossing Homer.
Boy, are you lucky you haven't got a sister.
You're crazy, Henry.
Don't you realize I'm the only person that I have?
My family can pick on.
Where's the ball?
It's up on the shelf, I think.
Can we run to have some light in this car?
We don't need any light.
She was ever long ago,
and knows exactly where everything is.
How would you win?
Hey, Henry, what was that?
You just knocked off the chow.
Oh boy, you're a boy.
You're a good man.
I'd like to try to find out.
Here, I can't make it out.
Sort of a box.
And there are a lot of little things that came out of it.
Oh, she was like a step on, well, whatever it is.
Her sort of soft and squashing.
Henry, I imagine I should have a white smell chocolate.
Chocolate?
Oh, it couldn't be chocolate.
No, it couldn't be, huh?
It's chocolate, all right?
And boy.
Oh, boy.
Don't you imagine that.
And no good, two-one-says.
Look out, Henry.
Let me get down here on the floor with you.
Now, wait a minute, Homer.
Rush night, the whole works.
Don't you realize this box must belong to someone?
I'm not necessarily.
Maybe somebody put it up there and put that in.
Ten years ago.
You think so?
Well, but don't taste as though they were.
Ten years old?
Maybe they ain't any other.
Homer, come on, help me.
They're all over the floor.
Well, where's the box?
You'll find it. You'll find it.
I've got the lid right here in my hand.
And it's looking for me.
Save all the little papers.
Some little papers?
Sure. Don't you feel this?
There's a little paper cup for her for each piece.
Oh, yes.
That's what I just swallowed.
Oh, boy.
Rob, Mary.
Don't let me tell you something.
Oh, well, don't bother looking for me, Mary.
I'm on my way into you.
Oh, I can't admit you.
I mean, may I ask what it is you're eating?
Why?
Eating?
Well, I'm just running my tongue over my teeth, Mary.
What I started to say was, one reason I don't watch Charlie Clock around tonight is because Joe Graham is coming over.
Joe Graham?
You'd rather see Joe Graham than a kind, generous guy like Charlie.
You realize Joe Graham is just as generous as he can be?
He even sent me a beautiful box of candy yesterday, a beautiful two pound box.
He did, Joe Graham gave you...
Oh, listen, that's mine.
Where is it?
That happens to be not a few business, can we all?
I put it away very carefully in a place where you can't possibly go across it.
Oh, well, I'm certainly sorry.
Goodbye.
Why?
Why are you going?
I have no place in the ticket.
I just have a little cleaning up.
I mean a few things.
I'm sorry I said what I said about you.
We're here in the
Oh boy.
Now listen, why'd you close the door, kid?
Why do you think so? You thought I wouldn't see it.
With Homer, there's no knob on this side.
You know, we can't get out.
She was. We may be in here.
Oh boy, nobody knows how long we may be in here.
Oh, at least, Harry, we will start.
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Hello, is Mary Alberts there?
Oh, Joe, is that you?
No, this is Charlie.
Oh, Charlie Clark.
Mary, did you hear me?
This is your friend, Charlie Clark.
Yes, well, just gonna go ahead and make it.
But I don't want to speak to Henry, Mary.
I want to speak to you.
This is Charlie Clark.
Hello?
Oh, gee, Mary, I thought you pitched me.
This isn't an always Charlie.
We don't seem to be able to find Henry.
But Mrs. Olvers, I gave Henry a baseball.
I mean, it's your daughter, Mary, I want.
Mary?
Oh, why Mary?
Is looking for Henry, Charlie?
She is?
Well, look, maybe you could tell me
What time I'm supposed to come over tonight.
Oh, so I'm not sure that I just married Milly tonight.
Sure with me.
Really?
Well, sure, didn't Henry tell her?
Well, Charlie, I think they say the same thing
for us to do with the Henry phone.
You later in the day.
Henry?
Not Mary?
I'll tell Henry you call me.
Oh, well, thanks very much.
Homer?
Homer, you aren't even going to sleep now.
No, of course I have a friend that's weak.
I just feel sort of funny.
Have you found all the chocolate's over on your part of the floor and some of them?
I'm stepping right in the box over here.
But, Homer, I've got the box over here.
You have?
But what's this I've been putting in?
Now listen, what's the matter?
It's somebody's shoe.
Now listen, Homer.
How's it going, Mom?
You know what we ought to have a flashlight?
Sure.
I even found a couple of chocolate's inside this umbrella.
Homer, keep going.
Keep going.
I have put somebody coming.
What's the matter?
We can work this, my father.
Let's put the box up on the shelf.
Okay.
You put it up.
I think I better move quick.
There.
And wait back in the closet.
It's my father.
He may not notice us.
She was.
Just don't move.
Oh, get your foot off me.
So McPey's your bed enough.
Why?
Yes.
Yeah, Todd.
I heard you were putting on just something.
Henry, what are you at home doing here in this closet?
Oh, my father.
I want to show all of it.
Why are you sitting there doing absolutely nothing?
White.
Oh, we were just trying to see how long we could hold our breath.
Mr. Allrich.
Well, get up.
You both entirely ought to be wasting your time doing that.
Yes, Father.
And please get out of the way.
I want to find an old pair of shoes, if I am.
Yes, Mr. Allrich.
Come on, Henley.
Oh, boy.
I'm coming.
Oh, is there anything to matter with you?
No, Mr. Allrich.
I'll be all right, I think.
Hey, look, as soon as you get by, don't we got to go back and pick up a rest?
- Hey, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
- I asked where you've been to the last half hour.
- Oh, wait, we're just, we're out there on Mrs. Old.
- We're looking for a flashlight.
- Yes, we need a flashlight, mother.
- I'm Mary, have you seen one?
- I mean, I'm not even speaking to you.
- Do I, Mary?
- And I just wanna tell you, if you hadn't done what you did,
I would have let you and Homer have some of the candy,
your grand business.
But as it is, you're not even gonna say it.
- Oh, we're not? - Oh, gee, with Henry.
You wanna see what I just found in the cup of my pan.
- What is it, Homer? - Nothing.
Nothing. - It's--
Oh, Mo, is it in pretty good condition?
Well, to be frank, Henry, we better just leave it where it is.
Henry, have you cleaned up that mess yet?
Is that mess?
Oh, boy.
You know very well that I'm talking about.
That model airplane you left all over the floor of your room.
Oh, is that all?
Is that all?
Henry, what's gotten into you?
Oh, nothing, Mother.
Nothing.
This is all the challenge you're wearing ideas to where we plan to flashlight.
Oh, my Henry does not need any flashlight.
It's straight and things up.
He does, and...
- Hey, which mess you want me to work? - You step up me, all right.
- Mother, would you like to have me go get two pieces of that candy joke about me?
- I certainly hope you haven't opened it. - Oh, no, Mother.
- How did you be careful to hide it out in the whole closet? - In the whole closet!
Your father is always poking around in that closet, and you know how he is when he gets over the box of candy.
- Well, my goodness, I'll get it out right away. - You can find a place in the dining room to hide it.
- All right. - Mary, look. There it is. Right out on the top shelf where everyone can see it.
- This is a strange. - I thought I'd put it right back in there.
I'm not going to let go of me.
Take one seat.
Now, dear, don't even take the cover off that box.
Why not hide it in the dining room and open it until William comes to see.
All right, let me out of here.
Then you can see how much it looks.
Oh, there, Mr. Aldrich.
Well, that's all right, darling. How are you?
That's fine. Can I see him, Mary, please?
You want, Mary?
Mary!
- Hey, Miss. - Yes, Father.
Charlie Clark, here to see you.
Mary. Mary.
Is she getting you, Mr. Aldrich?
I thought she asked her when I first called.
Step inside, we're trying to locate her.
Okay. Mary.
Can I hear her then, Mr. Aldrich?
I don't believe you did.
I would like to see Henry.
Hey, Mrs. Aldrich.
I don't want to see him, Mr. Aldrich.
What, Father?
Charlie Clark, it's asking to see you.
No, I guess you didn't understand me, Mr. Aldrich.
I don't give a dine about seeing him.
Oh, sorry, are you here?
Yeah.
Who did it in the... Oh, Jean, hello, Charlie.
Oh.
Hey, how did you see Mary? He went to the other side.
Now, Father, before I hear me, I want to ask her what time I'm to come over tonight.
And every time I call, I give me your mother and start looking for you.
Well, listen, Charlie.
Like this man, home and I are very busy trying to find a flashlight.
Oh, you want a flashlight? Well, why didn't you tell me?
You mean, you've got one, sure. I hear on my key ring.
Sort of small, though.
What is this happening? A flashlight? A flashlight?
Let me have a beer.
Come on, let's see what we can dig up on the closet.
We're gonna dig something up, fellas.
Can I watch him? Wait a second.
Charlie, how do you work this?
He can't. The battery's dead.
Listen, Charlie. Are you trying to be funny?
I'll locate a battery someday.
The water isn't gonna last forever.
What are you gonna do with that table, Anne Henry?
I'll just go take it for a front-hole closet for something.
But how about Mary?
Ken, you hear me, Henry? How about Mary?
Here, Henry. Here's a floor, Claude.
Right near the closet door.
Look, it lights up the whole clock.
Henry, would I be bothering you now if I asked a simple statement?
Gee, I'm gonna look at them.
- No, I'm gonna pull them off, please. - Oh, no.
We didn't get even half of them.
What are those little black things you're picking up, fellas?
Listen, Henry. I'll hold you in my hand,
and you do the picking up.
Well, hold your hand, big fellas.
- Father, I saw you, Lord, come on, yes! - Oh, boy.
No, Mary, I'm still here. Wait a minute.
- Well, I am! - Oh, please, wait a minute.
Now, listen, Troy, you want to take that lamp for?
I'm all right. Now wait a minute.
Now you put on.
Listen, Henry, what am I gonna do with these two handfuls of charters?
Let me see that in the box. I'm gonna pick up this lamp first.
Alice, is that your gun wrong?
Oh boy.
Was that my aunt, Harry, at the just team in the front door?
Where are you, Alice? In the business room?
Come on. What's the end of the dining room before she gets me at the school?
Henry, what am I gonna do with these charters?
Oh, put them in your box. They're crazy.
Isn't that additional, darling?
Oh, dear. Put them in the next.
Oh, my glad to get rid of those.
Now Homer, don't wipe your hands on the table floor.
I'm not.
I was just feeling it.
See what kind of material it is.
Look out while I shut the dishes of chocolate behind the fruit bowl.
You feel any more freedom?
No, how can you?
Can I try?
No, Mary.
Are you looking for?
I know.
I'm trying to get away from you.
Keep on me after the kitchen.
I went out for that too.
And now I just came in the classroom.
Mary, is that you in the dining room?
Yes, but I'm not so low.
Sorry, quiet.
Was looking for you.
Did he find you?
for you.
I don't think so.
Homer, what do you have on your hand?
White, a man, boy.
Say, look, look, look, look.
I've got him in my puddle now, son.
You better go up and watch him.
Yes, Mr. Hall, make you mind, Henry.
OK.
And if you see your mother off back out of your Aunt Harry,
that's waiting to see her in the living room.
Father, what are you looking for?
Lamping, oh, let's think to be something wrong with one
of my shoes.
Give me my hat, huh?
I have a pair of shoes in the hall closet, and maybe
my imagination, but I think there's
something down in the door of one.
- Nellie, how long did you take it out? - It's probably just a lining or something.
It's soft and it's give, it's not warm.
- Hey! - Are you following me?
- Yes, out of it. How did it wait until you were in the living room?
- Yes. How are you? I'll be right in there.
- Great. - Where did this come from?
- How does it matter? - There's two people standing behind the pool.
Now, dear, you didn't go and open that box your way, I'm glad you did.
- No, no, because remember, I can't pass you on to the pool.
- Mary, I didn't put this here. - Mm-hmm.
- See, you don't want your Aunt Harriet brought it, do you?
- Who thinks she liked it? - Why, of course, he did.
He's always carrying little paper bags of candy around there.
- What do you have a thing? - A mary.
- I've been to my return on clothing in our home.
- Mary, you can't keep coming away from her.
- I'm not going to say here. - No, Mary.
- Come over to you, Queen Mary. - Have I been married, darling?
- I'll have a different ring you want to see.
- Isn't it funny I can't make that clear to anyone?
- It's Mary I want. - Here, dear.
- Will you have a topic? - Thanks. I don't mind if I do.
- Mary, do I have to go home and I'll find a flashlight?
- It's nice, Leiden. - What did you want it for?
- My little particular ring, can we just...
This is all it's one in fact you've got in my seat.
Handy, homo, would you have a seat?
Handy.
Handy, yes, dear.
Go ahead and take one.
Well, homo, I don't think you ought to touch it.
And that's true.
Then, Mrs. Hall, it's failed for an eighth, Nancy.
Don't you think you ought to get the reason?
Sure.
And the night when, maybe, it's better for Mr.
Hall, which is long as they aren't having any way.
I have very blessed, Charlie.
After we've been down on our hands and knees,
I knew he had Charlie.
And perhaps I'd better take these and to Henry's
- Hey, Dad, holly, a brother's house is left.
- Henry, what do you think?
- What about over there?
- Who's gonna leave an awful big hole, Henry?
- Don't you think we ought to try to get them away
from your mother?
- Homer, let's call what she just took into the living room.
- So much water under the dam, and go on from there.
- Listen, fellas, where did Mary go?
- Henry, what are you looking at a sideboard for?
- Somewhere in this household, there's a flashlight.
- Oh, boy. - Let's see, Henry.
- What have you found, fellas?
- Can you imagine that?
- Listen, fellas, what have you found?
Charlie, I want you to do something, Bonnie.
You go up to my room.
Yeah?
And you sit there until we come up.
And then you're going to fix me up with Mary?
Yeah, sure.
Okay, but don't forget me.
We won't forget you, Charlie.
Homer.
Oh, look at why I dug up in the sideboard.
What?
Another box of candy.
And look, it's exactly like the one we still.
Henry, we're all sick.
We just take this into the hall part.
This is for some of these in the Mary's box.
Come on.
Do you think that'll be all right?
Well, you don't want to rob your own sister to me.
And the phone is you don't know who needs belong to?
Okay.
Wait a second while I open the closet door.
Oh, wait.
Where did you leave Mary?
Fine.
Let us out on the top cell.
Wait a minute and I'll boost you up.
Okay.
Boosh.
I'll hurry up Homer.
Henry, it isn't here.
Homer, stop kicking me.
Look out!
Hey Homer, get out.
Oh boy.
Where's the box of chocolate?
Under me, darmin'.
[music playing]
We'll be back with the Alders family in just a moment.
Right now it's intermission.
Time for our intermission guests.
The one and only Tommy Dorsey.
OK, Tommy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
[Music]
♪ It's the man ♪
♪ There's the name of the show ♪
♪ Each time I crave the answer ♪
♪ I am music goodbye ♪
♪ And then ♪
♪ I'm in the chode ♪
♪ Only my country ♪
♪ Faith like your heart in mine ♪
♪ If your something is my arms and toes in me ♪
♪ I haven't heard this through before ♪
♪ Ooh, I just thought I'd be ♪
♪ Holding your face for me ♪
♪ With the wind and the fire ♪
♪ And here it's one ♪
♪ It's a time ♪
♪ It's a dream ♪
♪ Each little dream ♪
♪ For take away and my life would be true ♪
♪ Very ♪
♪ And in the truth ♪
♪ You'll be forever ♪
The next of my dreams come true.
[Music]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
Henry accidentally spilled a box of Mary's chocolates in the hall closet.
Later, without realizing it was the same box,
he found one in the dining room buffet
and was about to place it in the hall closet when Homer fell on it.
The scene opens an hour later in to Haven's drugstore.
Oh, Mr. Haven. Mr. Haven.
Yes, there is something I can do for you.
How much is old box of chocolates there?
The two-pound box that sits down in half.
A dollar and a half, Mr. D. Haven. As much as that.
Well, here's a one-pound box for 80 cents.
He always probably has to be the kind home of fell on.
I mean, Mr. Behaven, you couldn't trust me for a dollar and a half, could you?
Well, isn't it? I don't trust you, Henry, but if you'd like me too, I could call your mother and ask her for all right to charge it to her.
Oh, no, don't bother my mother about a thing like this.
Mr. Behaven, you don't have any chocolate at all like those in that box.
For less than a dollar and a half.
No, over.
Hmm.
Well, Mr. Behaven, do you have anything that would be good for removing chocolate creams like those in that box on trousers?
- Oh, tell me you want a spot remover? - Yes, only first.
How much is it? - We have pretty good cleaner here for 25 cents.
- Nothing less than that. - Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, do you have anything that would be good for an unsettled stomach?
Resolving from chocolate foods like those in that box.
- Or you'd like some by-car? - One hundred more chisels.
- One dime. - Yeah, I'm getting anything that would settle me for a nickel.
I could give you a little fizzy water free.
Okay, let's try that first before I throw my money away.
Hey, fellas, where have you been?
She was at Charlie's car.
I'll wait up in your room for you for an hour, Henry.
Did you forget me?
Don't forget, I gave you that baseball.
Charlie, we had to come out here to see about some candy.
Oh, Mr. Behaven, do you have any hair oil that smells nice?
And say fellas, does Mary like candy?
What's that, Charlie?
Would you like to buy Mary about the candy?
Sure.
Sure, Charlie.
And how would you like to have us deliver it, Troy?
Oh, no.
We can't do that.
Look, Mr. Behaven, how much are those boxes over there?
Is it done here?
Charlie, that is in the kind she likes.
You know, listen, hold on. I'm not going to have any part of this.
Hey, don't you want to save your own life?
Charlie, come here.
They'll win. They'll win. They'll win.
Don't listen.
Let go of him, Henry. You had gold in your shop.
Wait a minute, fella.
Wait a minute.
What is that? You want me to argue?
Do you want me to have a come-up?
No, I haven't decided.
- Have you got her? - Yes, dear.
- She just left. - What?
Do you think she might have taken my box of chocolate?
No.
Your Aunt Harry is not in the habit of taking candies.
It doesn't belong to us.
Well, I guess these just three people that might have taken it.
And who are they?
Your Harry or her or Charlie Clark are possibly all three.
Now, Mary, that isn't exactly fair.
You probably intended to put the box of candy in the sideboard
and add some mind and let's put it some other place.
Oh, that's why he's learning his soap upstairs.
And his soap pan?
Yes, Alex, I'd like to wash my hands.
I couldn't ignore the rules that you have all over your home.
Well, nothing there.
It just seems to be chocolate.
Chocolate?
I think it's chocolate.
- Sam, how did you get chocolate on you? - I have no idea.
I have to look at my hand a little while ago and it was all chocolate.
After all, is that important? Where will I find a piece of soap?
- Feel, I don't think I've ever been so mad at you in my life.
- Mad at me? - What about us?
- Sam, you know what you've done. You know very well what you've done.
- What do you think he did? - That's all I wanted to think was told.
- Oh, I can't believe it. - I should have known Mary that your father couldn't be
cut into the box of candy in the house. He never could be.
Let him have one piece and he loses all control and all character.
- Oh, that's Harriet. I thought you'd go. - Oh, don't bother.
I'll just sit back into the hall, talk to your loved ones,
and I'll ask you to last week.
- Oh, did you almost forget it again? - No, I was going to come out on the porch with me.
- Oh, just start and read. - And Harriet, you want me to hold your pocket before you put it out?
- No, thank you. I can put it out. - Oh, it's my good enough for falling on me.
- Oh, there you go. - Chocolate.
- Hey, Harriet, where did you get those? - Oh, where are they coming from?
[Music]
Mother, is here almost ready?
It won't be ready for another ten minutes, Mary at least.
Well, Mother, I don't like the scene, no rush, you, but Joe's in the living room,
and he keeps asking whether I got the box of candy and whether I like it.
Mother, if we can only tell you, maybe he gets my office up there.
Mary, all I can say is I'll get it just as soon as I can.
Now, go back into the living room and visit me.
Yes, Mother.
Oh, Rosie.
Mother, who Henry, is that you?
Yes, Mother.
I am Homer.
Henry, have you seen about the candy anywhere around here?
I've seen it.
Do you please run up there and get washed to dinner right away?
And Homer, you better go home so you won't be late for your dinner.
But Mrs. O, the candy won't be fast.
You're some sort of mother.
Can I go over to Homer to dinner so I won't be here to feed him?
I mean, now Henry, go play him here.
You want to visit, Betty.
Please go up and get washed.
But Mother, Henry, you should have let Charlie get her that far.
Get out of that box.
Let's hold on. I couldn't.
We're a bit of dirty trick.
Then be at the dope.
Who's that?
I don't know. Somebody at the door here.
Hi, Henry. It's Mary here.
Listen, Troy.
Where you going about Box of Canden?
None of your business. Let me in.
But, Troy, let me in.
Mary, are you here?
Listen, Troy. I'm advising you.
I'm begging you.
Don't give Mary that Box of Canden.
I'm not taking any advice from you, Henry.
I gave you a baseball and you don't even want to fix me up with your sister.
Hey, Mary. Mary!
Yes, he's not going to call me.
I'm here.
Here, here.
I see.
It's a box of candy.
Show me, cross.
I should have known all the time you've looked at the fly.
Now, you didn't take it.
What do you mean you didn't take it?
You're already fly from here.
Thank you, Charlie.
Thank you very much.
Now, please go.
Can you hear me?
Not at you.
I could kill you.
Please leave this house.
Where do you live?
Sorry, you hear me go.
I'm going.
I'm only at a minute, Charlie.
There you're faithful.
I feel it's the least I can do for you.
[Music]
(dramatic music)
This is the Armed Forces radio service.
[Music]