[Music]
Henry! Henry Aldrich!
Coming, Mother!
The Aldrich family! A special rebroadcast for you soldiers, sailors, and Marines of the United Nations.
[Music]
Watch a teenage boy in action, and you can probably discover the source of his impulsive vitality.
Whatever he does is immensely important and all engrossing.
Henry Aldrich proves that.
The scene opens at the Aldrich breakfast table.
Thank you, Sam. I think I will.
Mary.
Thank you, Father.
Henry.
Why?
Oh, no, thanks, Father.
Well, Henry, I want you to at least eat your oatmeal.
Mother, I ate all the milk on it.
And you know how much nourishment there is milk, don't you?
Henry, did you get over-tired at the dance last night?
Who I, Mary? Tired?
Henry, if you're old enough to dance, you're old enough to eat oatmeal.
Now, don't let me hear your mother speak about it again.
Even when I don't have any appetite, Father.
Henry, didn't you hear your father or do you either eat or stop dancing?
- You stop dancing? - Mary, I'm eating it.
I want to know whether I have to go clear through the bottom.
It seems to me, Henry, you have the wrong attitude.
There are lots of people in this world who give anything for a dish about me.
Mother, it isn't that I don't appreciate it.
It's girls that I'm sick of.
- Girls, dear? - Boy, never again.
- Why should I want to furl away my life dancing? - What's that?
- Why should I... - Boy, the way I look at it...
- What are you holding your cup up in the air like that for? - I'm fascinated. Go on, Henry.
Well, I just thought things over that salt.
I don't feel I'm getting anywhere the way I'm going.
You know what I mean? Being a darn butterfly?
So, Mother, don't you think I could just forget my oatmeal?
You certainly may not.
By the way, Alice, is anyone phone for me this morning?
No, Sam, not that I know of.
No. Well, if any call does come for me, it'll probably be a Mr. Gilcrest.
Who?
Mr. Gilcrest. And please be sure to call me. I'll probably be up in the attic working.
- How do you mean you're not going to the office today? - I am not.
And that phone call is very important.
- Is that clear, Alice? - Yes, Sam. Of course it's clear.
- And, Mary, do you understand? - Yes, Father.
And, Anne-Ray, Anne-Ray, what are you staring into your oatmeal for?
Who I, Father? I wasn't staring, I was just watching the spoon sing.
Hi, Anne-Ray. She was home. Are you here?
We have to wait that bathroom news for you.
Anne-Ray. I'm coming, Homer.
Anne-Ray.
Anne-Ray. Yes, Father?
When Homer came in, I was asking you whether you understood.
I heard you, Father. She, you can depend on me.
Hey, Henry, who do you think I just saw? Who do you think I just had a talk with?
Who?
Agnes, and do you know what she said?
She said that when Kathleen got home from the dance last night,
she was so upset over the fight you and she had she couldn't sleep all night.
She couldn't, Homer, she couldn't.
And do you know what Agnes said she told her to do?
Why?
She said, Kathleen, or the telephone you want to apologize.
Is that right, Homer?
Kathleen's going to apologize to me?
Sure.
As a matter of fact, hasn't she called you, yes?
No, but she probably will any minute, though.
She's a-- you know, well, I mean, if she wasn't able to sleep last night,
she's probably having a late breakfast.
That's true.
Are you gonna forgive her?
Well, I'll certainly be fair. She was at the least I can do.
Henry, could you and Homer please get out of my way?
Mary, Homer and I happen to be very busy discussing something.
Now please don't hang around and try to listen.
Henry, all I want to do is use the phone.
Use the phone? I'm sorry, but you can't use it right now, Mary.
Why not? I'm using the phone.
You're using it by Henry Aldrich. You're standing ten feet away from it.
And all I want to do is phone Daisy Harper and say hello.
Daisy Harper? She was. You've never gotten Daisy Harper on the poor near life of what you just hung there for a couple of hours at a stretch.
Well, I know my right, Henry Older.
Don't let her buy you, Henry. Don't let her buy you.
Now, Mary, wait a minute.
Oh, no, I won't let go of me.
There, Mary. Now look at what you've done.
- And we had to knock the table over you, dear. - Henry?
Yes, Mother. - What was that?
Why, I'll tell you, Mrs. Older, she was just explaining something to Mary.
Well, see, Dad, you come in here and finish your boat, Beale.
See that, Henry? See that?
Mother, couldn't you save my oatmeal for me so I can have it for lunch?
For lunch?
Sure. Just slice and buy it for me.
Oh boy, there's the phone.
And now, Mary, will you please get out of this hall
while I have my conversation?
- I mean, I won't listen to you. - That is in the point, Mary.
Do you want to make us feel uncomfortable?
Well, all right.
But don't expect me to do this before you all the time.
- Hello? - Hello?
Hello, is this Kathleen's father? I mean...
May I speak with Mr. Aldridge, please?
- Mr. Aldridge? - Yes, this is Mr. Gilchrist.
I'm very anxious to get in touch with him.
Oh, yes, it seems as though I remember him mentioning
your name at breakfast or something.
- I beg your pardon? - Just a minute, I'm calling.
Father!
Mr. Aldrich!
Listen, can we get rid of him fast?
Maybe Kathleen is trying to get you.
Hello?
Hello? Is this Mr. Aldrich?
No, sir, I just happened to remember Mr. Gilchrist.
My father said you should call him at his office.
I think.
- Is that the office? - Sure.
And I remember he said it was very important.
And he must be on his way by now.
- Can we hang up? - The only thing is...
Well, maybe I can get him before my train leaves.
Thank you very much.
That's all I. Goodbye.
[Music]
[Squeaking]
Hello, Mr. Aldrich's office.
Hello, is Mr. Aldrich there?
No, he isn't.
Well, this is Mr. Brown.
Do you know where the Mr. Aldrich has gotten in touch with Mr. Gilcrest yet?
Well, Mr. Brown, Mr. Aldrich was expecting him to go over to his house for a conference, I believe.
This morning?
Yes, you see, Mr. Aldrich isn't coming into the office today.
Oh.
Well, I'll jump in the car and go right over to Mr. Aldrich's house.
I want to get in on that conference if I can.
I'm sure Mr. Aldrich will be very glad to get the two of you together.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Mr. Brown.
Hello, Mr. Aldrich's office.
Hello. May I speak with Mr. Aldrich, please?
Mr. Aldrich isn't in right now. May I take any message?
Well, this is Mr. Gilchrist.
About how long before you expect him in?
Mr. Gilchrist, Mr. Aldrich isn't expecting to see you here.
He's waiting for you up at his house.
Up at his house? I just honed his house.
They said he was on his way down to the office.
Really? He's decided to come down here?
That's what they said.
And I'm supposed to catch a train in 25 minutes.
Well, Mr. Gilchrist, you better hurry up and come right down here then.
You think I'll be able to see him?
Oh, yes. It's a told you he's coming down here. He ought to be here any minute.
Very well.
And then, oh my goodness, I wonder if I can get hold of Mr. Brown.
Oh, and what are you going to do to spend all Saturday here by this phone?
Mrs. Aldrich, that's just exactly what I've been trying to tell him.
Mother, I don't need any fresh air. I slept with my window open all night.
Well, get away from that phone, dear. I want to put in a call.
Now? Now, Justice Cackley?
Mother, couldn't you please wait just a few more minutes?
Oh, you're waiting for a call?
Yes, sure.
Well, let me know just as soon as you're through, because I have to order the groceries.
Yes, Mother, and thank you very much.
Listen, Henry. I know you slept with your window open last night.
But why don't you look at it this way? The sun shining.
Alright Homer, alright, why don't you go out then?
Alone?
What is there I could do alone?
Look, why don't you do this?
Why don't you phone Kathleen and get it over with?
Oh no, Homer, long ago it was her fault and she practically died and apologized to me.
Henry!
Mary, there's no use asking me.
I'm not doing this phone yet.
Henry, I'm not even asking you about the phone.
I just wanted to tell you that Mother has a can of peas out in the kitchen she wants you to open for.
Sure, I know, Mary, I know.
Now run along.
If you think you're gonna get me away from this phone with a can of peas, you're crazy.
Henry, must I ask Mother to beg you in writing to open her canopy?
A merry mail.
I know, Homer.
Mother, still remember the time you pulled the clock out of the vinegar bottle.
Mary, I wasn't going to offer to open your darn can.
I was just going to suggest if it's so important to get it open.
Why don't you bring the can and the can opener in here?
All right, just to show you, I will.
I certainly will.
And she reserves the phone.
There's the phone.
Hello?
Hello, Kathleen.
Henry, you're completely crazy.
That's the front door.
And Homer, can't you please answer it?
Sure, Mary.
Number three.
And never mind off, right?
My sister just asked home an answer.
- I beg your pardon?
- It isn't a phone, goodbye.
- Oh, my, what are you doing over here?
- Oh, hello, Father.
I'm helping Henry wait for a phone call.
- For Mr. Brown.
- Good morning, Henry.
Where's your father?
- My father, are we out the office?
- Down at the office.
- Oh, no.
- Yes, sir.
He particularly mentioned at breakfast
that he was going to the office.
- Well, what did they tell me he was up here for?
Look out, while I use your phone a minute.
- You wanna use this phone, Mr. Brown?
- I do.
- The father, I'm sorry, but it's busy.
- What do you mean it's busy?
I've got to call Mr. Aldrich.
What do you mean you're going to call me?
Hello there Will.
Bam!
I thought you were down at the office.
She was, Father, how'd you get back so soon?
From where I've been up in the attic.
With Mr. Gilchrist.
But who?
With Mr. Gilchrist, Father, did you find him all right?
What do you mean?
Did Mr. Gilchrist find me?
Henry, where is Mr. Gilchrist?
Well, I'm not sure, but I think he said he'd be very glad to wait for you,
Don't you're all?
That's a fine thing.
Here, let me have that phone.
Oh boy.
Father, couldn't you please wait just a little while longer?
Wait, wait.
Henry, do you realize what you've done?
- Do you realize it? - There she is, Henry. There she is.
Homer, let me have that phone.
I'm just handing it to you, Henry, here.
Hello?
Yes?
- Henry, is that my office? - No, it isn't, Father.
It's a sort of a girl.
Well, come with me. Maybe my wife knows something about Gilchrist phoning.
- I'm coming. - Hello?
- How is? - Listen, baby, Barbara,
this is no time to be calling our house.
That's late, hang on.
- Hi! - Hey!
- I'm not in the kitchen, Sam.
- Well, you were around when Gilchrist phoned?
- Yeah, I don't know anything about it.
- Sam, I've got my car outside. We'd better go right down the door.
- That's true.
Sam, there are two things I want you to do for me on the way down.
First, take this list into the grocer and leave it.
Now, Alice?
All you have to do is leave it and run, and they'll fill the order.
And then stop off with this note at the emergency aid.
Alice, why can't you use the phone for all that?
Now, Sam, I can't touch the phone. Henry's waiting for a call from Kathleen,
and his heart is practically broken.
And do you realize my day is practically ruined?
And besides, I don't even go near the grocery store.
All right, then, Mary can go to the grocery.
But you can stop off with this list at the emergency aid.
It's right in the block above your office.
What are we giving them?
some ging of aprons and a hundred pounds of potatoes we have down the
basement and a few other things and i have to carry them no did just take
this list so they'll know what they're going to get
yes mary
i'm glad you still here could you open it can't be for me mary get henry to open
it i'm going down to the office the only thing is though
henry and i have a job for him and father says no one but henry is to do it
but gee wiz mary can't just see i'm trying to use this phone
Hello?
Here's the can opener and here's the can Henry.
Thank you, Marie. Put it right down there.
And if you ask me, Henry, all right, no girl in the world is important enough to tie up a whole family like this.
Hello?
Does Henry answer Henry?
Hello.
Hello, Ms. Aldridge's office.
Oh boy, am I glad to get you. This is Henry Aldridge.
Yes, Henry.
Oh, look. My father says I made a terrible mistake and then I can only talk for a minute.
What did you say?
I've got a call coming. She and then if the line is busy all the time, she might get discouraged.
And my father isn't down there. He's up here.
Mr. Aldridge is up there at the house?
Yes, he turned up in the attic.
Well, I'm awfully glad you thought I'll send Mr. Gilcrest off right away.
That's fine, because my father's pretty mad.
Why?
But Kathleen, I've been expecting you to ask Henry.
I can't help that, Milly.
But we're gonna have such fun on the picnic.
Why don't you go to the phone now and call Henry
and ask him whether he wouldn't like to come along with us?
Oh, no, Milly.
If you'd like to ask him, you go ahead.
But I'm certainly not going to be the one that calls in.
All right.
Hello?
No, but please.
M303.
Kathleen, tell me, couldn't I potentially?
Have you and Henry had a falling house?
That's falling out.
My goodness, Nelly, whatever gave you an idea like that.
I just said I wasn't going to be the one that phones in.
Hello?
Is that you, Henry?
Yes, is that you, Kathleen?
Kathleen?
No.
Did you want to speak to her?
Why not?
No, I mean, but it's--
Who is this?
This is Nellie Miller.
Could you hold the line just a second?
Kathleen, you're a secretary, say you're a no-nilly.
Don't you dare tell me I'm here.
Well, I'm gone now.
Hello?
Nellie, is there somebody there with you?
Well, I... No, not exactly.
And Henry, how would you like to go on a picnic with a few of us?
A picnic? Today?
Yes, we're gonna have a wonderful time.
And all you'd have to furnish would be leather.
Lettuce? Well, actually, I'm certainly...
I'm certainly...
Henry, look at all of my...
Nothing, Nelly. I'm just trying to open a can of peace.
- Yeah, what? - I certainly like to go with you,
but I'm expecting a telephone call.
It's very important, and...
No, Nelly, I don't think I'd better go with you.
- Really? - And, and listen, I...
I don't like the same room, but could you hang up in case...
In case that call comes for me?
All right, Henry, if you want to talk to me that way,
I was just trying to be nice to you.
- See, I didn't mean it that way. - Son of a apologize.
I was only wasting your time. Goodbye.
- But listen! - What do you say, Nelly?
- You asked me to hang up. - Son of a ball, look.
Abola, my goodness, I don't know what's gotten into Henry.
Miss Thompson, do you have him yet?
I'm trying to get him, Mr. Oldrich. The operator is ringing your house right this minute.
Sam, after you get through talking to Henry, let me have a chance at home.
I'll turn him over to you, Will, with pleasure.
Hello? Hello?
Hello, is Henry Oldrich there?
Yes, hello. Is this you, Kathleen?
Who? Isn't this Kathleen speaking?
No, it isn't. But just a moment, there is someone that would like to speak to you.
There is? Oh, boy.
- Henry. - What's that?
Henry, I want to ask you just one simple question. Where is Mr. Gilchrist?
Well, I'm certainly glad you called, Father. He's right in the living room reading the National Geographic.
- What happened to you? - What happened to me? What happened to me?
Wait until you hear what's going to happen to you.
- Henry, what's that noise? - That noise? I'm beating a rug for Mary.
- What? - I've got a hanging on the bastard and I'm being very careful.
You tell Mr. Gilchrist we're coming up there and he's to wait.
Then you're to get away from there and stay away for the rest of the day.
I'm to stay away from Mr. Gilchrist or the carpet.
From the phone, of course, the phone.
But suppose my call comes for me.
Did you hear me? You're not even to touch that telephone until I say you may.
Yes, Father, I understand.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
Sam, you didn't hang up, did you?
Oh, I'm sorry, Wilk.
Oh, that's all right. There wasn't anything more. I could tell Homer anyway.
Just the same, Miss Thompson. Call our house again.
- Right now. - Right now. Let's see whether Henry's still hanging around that phone.
Hello?
- Number three. - Elm, 303.
- Elm, 303. - Hey, you're hatin' code, Will.
I hope you don't mind driving us up to the house again.
Well, it has to be done.
After all, Gilchrist has already stayed over one train
to keep this appointment.
Hello.
Hello, is Henry Odysayet?
Hello, is this Kathleen?
(audience laughing)
Just a moment, please.
Yeah, Mr. Odysh. - Thank you.
Henry, did not tell you not to touch that phone again.
Mr. Odysh, he's not touching,
and I'm touching him for him.
This is Homer and Sam.
Is that Homer?
Let me get my hands on him.
[Music]
We'll be back with the Aldrich family in just a moment.
Right now it's intermission and time for our intermission guest, the one and only Tommy Dorsey.
Okay Tommy.
[Music]
And because we had that silly pride, I'd thought my heart would break the whole night's good.
I knew that you'd be sorry, and I'm sorry too.
I didn't have my favorite dream, the one in which I hold you tight.
I had to call you a...
Just one in you
It was real and everything
Was still our ride, yeah
I had to call you a...
Just one in you
Oh, that couldn't creep away
My friend
♪♪
Oh, like little clipper with my finger.
(audience cheering)
(dramatic music)
(drumming)
(audience cheering)
[cheering]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldridge.
Due to the fact that Henry has been waiting by the Aldridge telephone for several hours,
hoping a call would come through from Kathleen, practically all business and social life in
Centerville has come to a dead stop.
I've seen opens in a nearby grocery store.
Excuse me, but could you wait on me next, please?
Oh, there, Mary Aldrich. What have you...
Why, I'm in an awful hurry.
My mother wanted me to leave this list of groceries.
And will you send them over to our house, please?
Okay.
Well, I'm certainly glad you got a phone.
But if you're even waiting all morning to put a phone call in...
Okay, help yourself there.
All right, goodness.
Now, what's the matter? Is the door stuck? Just give it a yank.
All right. Hello. Hello.
Why, Henry Aldrich, what are you doing here?
Listen, Mary, can I have any privacy at all?
Then we just let me out for a minute. I'll explain things to her.
I don't want anything explained.
Apparently, there isn't a telephone in this town, but a person can use it. You are at all.
You might try behaving in this drug store, Mary. They have a very nice booth there.
Hello?
Number three.
Well, look, may I ask who this is?
This is the operator. What number do you want?
Well, could you do me a favor?
Could you transfer any calls that may come from me at the orages over to the Homer Brown's house?
I'm sorry. We can't possibly do that.
Oh, well, did you happen to know Chate Clark?
Yes?
Well, he's a friend of mine, and his sister works there at the phone company.
So, does that make any difference?
I'm Charlie Clock's sister.
Who you are? You are?
Well, I'm Henry, see?
Then I've got an unusual case here.
My father's giving me out, see?
He's giving me out, and somebody very important is trying to get me.
Is it an emergency call you're expecting?
Boy, I'll say it is.
Well, I'll take it up with a supervisor and explain the circumstance.
And thank you very much. Goodbye.
What'd he say, Henry? What'd she say?
Look out, Homer. We gotta beat over your house before Kathleen's call gets there.
Hi, Henry!
Oh, she was at you, Nelly.
We're getting some things for the picnic here,
and you won't even have to furnish lettuce
if you'd like to change your mind, Henry.
Gee, any other time, Nelly, but--
but right now, I'm in an awful hurry.
Come on, Homer.
Hello, Nelly.
Hello, Homer.
How are you?
Homer, come on.
Goodbye, Nelly.
Goodbye.
Oh, Nelly.
What is it, Kathleen?
Here's a nice, Nancy Cracker.
Who's that that just went out the door?
Henry Aldrin.
Who's that, Henry?
Yes, he was in such a hurry to go away.
He'd hardly speak to him.
Really?
Oh.
Well, you know, Nelly, on second thought I don't think I care anything about going on the picnic.
- Why, Nelly? - No, I simply don't feel like it. What fun?
I mean, Nelly, there's no use pleading with me. I've made up my mind.
Excuse me, but was either of you girls using that phone booth there?
- Uh? - No, sir.
I wondered. I just found a can opener in it.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello there, Mr. Brown.
Boy, have I been running?
Henry, is that you? Where's Homer?
He's coming around.
Boy, he couldn't keep up with me.
But she was. Is that your telephone?
I'm just in time.
I guess that is the phone.
Well, don't bother the answer. I know what it is.
Henry, I'll take that call.
But it's for me. It's for me.
Hello? Hello?
This is Mr. Gilchrist. I want to speak to Mr. Samuel Aldridge.
Mr. Aldridge, he isn't here. You've got the wrong house.
Oh, I beg your pardon. I'm sorry.
That's all right.
Henry, who was that?
Nobody, Mr. Brown. Just Mr. Gilchrist.
He wanted to speak to my father.
See, your father, where is Gilchrist? Where is he?
We've been looking all over for him.
Oh, right. He didn't say it. He just turned off.
And may I ask who gave you permission to come in here and answer our telephone?
The telephone call me. I asked him to.
Oh, you did, did you? And do you see that for a dog?
- Yes, sir. - March.
- You mean you want me to go? - March.
Yes, Mr. Brown.
Gee, Henry, can you run?
Oh, I get out of here.
- Pull me farther. - March!
Ben, will you answer the phone, please?
I'll answer, Alice. Hello?
May I speak to Mr. Brown, please?
Well, I'm sorry, but Mr. Brown isn't here.
You must have the wrong number.
I can't keep getting wrong numbers forever.
Whose residence is this?
This is Mr. Orich's residence.
Well, this is Mr. Gilchrist, Mr. Orich.
Oh, how is it when I call your house?
I get Mr. Brown, and when I call Mr. Brown's house, I get you?
Could you say that again, please?
I'm down at the station, and I just wanted to tell you
that in less than one minute, I'm stepping on board my train.
You're leaving?
Right now, goodbye.
But Mr. Gilchrist, Mr. Gilchrist!
- Sam, that wasn't a call for Henry, was it? - It was not.
Alice, will you please try to tell me what has happened to this telephone system?
Well, I've been wondering about that myself, because Henry is just terribly upset.
Henry is, Henry is.
I think you ought to call the company, dear, and complain to them
that Henry's been sitting here by this phone most all morning, and nothing has happened.
What do you mean nothing has happened?
Now, Sam, this isn't anywhere for you than for Henry.
Just remember the poor boys in the living room completely sunk.
What's the matter with him?
He's so depressed, Sam.
He wouldn't eat his fried-out meal even if I warmed it over for him.
Oh my goodness, there's the phone again.
Mother, do I have the phone ring?
You do, and if you want to answer it, you may.
Well, thank you, Father. Thank you very much.
As soon as you're through answering it, I want to have a talk with you.
Yes, Father.
Nothing?
Hello?
This isn't Kathleen, but listen.
If I were you, I wouldn't come anywhere near my house.
Why not?
The telephone company was just there and they took out our phone.
What did they do that for?
What do you say you told them to?
For me?
Oh my, I give you my word.
I'm coming from the Haven Drug Store.
And you better keep away from my father.
Goodbye.
- But Homer! - Homer!
Henry, where did your mother go?
I don't know, Father.
What do you think just happened?
I know what just happened, Alice.
What is it, Sam? What is it?
Alice, they just delivered some groceries.
And may I ask just what it was you ordered?
Why, a lot of things.
Did you order a hundred pounds of potatoes?
No.
Did you order any lentils?
No, we've got all that down in the basement.
It's what we're giving to the emergency aid.
Well, the store just delivered them to you with a note
pinned on the potatoes, saying they're all out of Gingham aprons.
Sam Aldrich, how could they have done a thing like this?
That's Henry know anything about that.
Henry! Henry!
He probably went upstairs.
I'll answer it.
Hello.
Hello, Mrs. Aldrich. Is that you?
Yes?
Well, this is Kathleen Anderson.
Oh, hello, Kathleen. I guess I know who you want to speak to.
Oh, no, I'm calling you Mrs. Aldrich.
Me, dear.
Yes, my mother just looked over the list of things you promised to donate to the emergency age.
But she wanted me to phone and thank her right away.
Well, it wasn't that nice of her. I hope you'll need potatoes.
Potatoes? You mean you're going to get potatoes, too?
Hard potatoes and laddles on the list?
No, I don't think so. I had your list right here.
Two pounds of butter, one pound of cheese, two pounds of bacon, five lamb chops,
dozen and a half of eggs, two cans of plain apples.
Kathleen, where did you get that list?
My Mr. Olridge left it at the emergency aid on his way to his office.
He took that and s-- Well, isn't that nice?
Yes, it certainly is.
Yes, it is, isn't it?
Kathleen, could you hold the phone just a second while I speak to Mr. Olridge?
So you weren't asking about the potatoes?
Yes, that's exactly what I want to ask him about. Just hold the line.
Sam! Sam! Oldie, where are you?
I think he went upstairs, Mother.
She wins.
Mother, did you know someone left the receiver off the telephone?
Mother?
Whoa, she wears.
Flo?
Hello?
Is that you, Henry?
Listen, Kathleen.
What, Henry?
Well, imagine that.
How long you've been waiting there?
What?
the do's. Boy I've been waiting all I mean oh are you doing anything tonight
no I'm not well how would you how would you like to go on a picnic this morning
it is that's what I mean how about the movie I mean tonight I love to all right
as well I'll see you there goodbye goodbye you didn't hang out that phone did
you going out there wasn't anything more to say mother I finally got my call
[Music]
Hello? Hello?
Now, please.
Operator, this is Mr. Brown. I've been trying to get Elm 303 for two hours. What's the trouble?
Elm 303. What is the name of the party, please?
Aldrich, Mr. Samuel Aldrich.
I'm sorry, but Elm 303 has been disconnected.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[Music]
This is the Armed Forces Radio Service.
(upbeat music)
[Music]
(buzzing)