The Aldrich family based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith and starring Ezra Stone
as Henry with Jackie Kalk as Homer.
Henry! Henry Aldrich!
Coming, mother!
[Music]
Each election year we hear a lot of talk about favorite sons, but Senator Bill USA claims
one who has nothing to do with politics.
Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich's boy Henry.
And because he is just a real American boy, well that makes Henry Aldrich everybody's
favorite son.
Our scene tonight opens in the Aldrich living room where we find Henry and his sister Mary.
Mary, Mary, what is it Henry?
Have you seen my new wrist watch any place your wrist watch? Where'd you leave it?
I didn't leave it anyplace. I just can't find it. Mary you hadn't finished what you were doing in the kitchen
Oh, I'll go right out mother and Henry I want you to go upstairs and get washed
Yes, mother just as soon as I finished looking for something wash especially well there and Harriet's gonna be here for dinner
She is and you know how she is about everything like that
May I ask what you're upsetting all the cushions on the sofa floor? Oh nothing
I just happened to be looking for something.
I certainly hope you wrote your Aunt Harriet and thank her for the lovely wristwatch, she
sent you.
Yes, Mother.
I wrote her the minute I heard she was coming.
Oh, you didn't find anything out of the ordinary when you swept under the sofa, did you?
What would you call out of the ordinary?
Nothing.
Just dust or something.
Mother, what time shall I put the potatoes on?
Oh, Henry, what time is it?
It's exactly about, I should say it's a time of 26 minutes after six.
Oh Father, am I glad to see you.
Put the potatoes on right away Mary.
Henry, I hope you're going to wash before Aunt Harriet gets here.
Yes Father, have you seen anything lying around that's sort of round and shiny?
Such as what?
Well, if you saw it you couldn't help but notice it.
Father, mother wants to know whether you remember to bring that picture Aunt Harriet gave us down from the attic.
Which one?
The Colosseum in ruins.
I'll go up and get it.
Oh, and Henry, Mother says to the dinner,
"Yorta, sit down and Harry, it's right."
On her right?
Where she can see my left wrist?
Henry, always, do you mean to say
you lost that beautiful watch she sent you?
No, Mary, I'm sure I can find it.
Oh, my goodness, if you can't.
You know how to press down,
Harry, it gets over a thing like that.
That isn't the half of her.
She said if I'd take good care of it,
maybe she'd give me a new bicycle.
Henry, haven't you washed yet?
Yes, Mother.
Mary, if anyone asks where I am, tell them I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
I just happened to remember.
I left my watch across the street at Nancy Adams's.
I'll be right back, Mary.
(upbeat music)
Can't you help me look for my watch, Herbert?
Are you sure you left it here?
I must.
I've just been over at Nancy Adams's
and it isn't there any place.
Well, Henry, I don't see how you could
lose a watch on my front lawn.
This is where I remember wearing it last.
Herbert, let me see the watch you have on.
Now listen, Henry, this isn't yours.
It's exactly like mine, Herbert.
It's the same, right.
But is your strap worn as much as this?
No.
Was the second hand gone?
No, but could I borrow that watch just for this evening?
No, Henry.
You don't know how to take care of a watch.
I've never ruined the strap or busted my second hand, have I?
No, but you've lost the whole watch, haven't you?
If my Aunt Harry at finds I've misplaced it, she'll get depressed and refused to give me a bicycle.
Henry, you're the last person in the world, my folks who want me to loan my watch to.
What makes them feel that way about me?
They don't even think you're a very good influence for me.
Alright.
Listen.
Would you let me wear your watch if I give you all my allowance for the week of October 15th?
Why would I have to wipe that wall?
I owe everything until then.
I wouldn't be interested.
You wouldn't be interested. Well, would you consider two weeks allowance beginning October 15?
No.
But I wouldn't be asking you to help me if it didn't mean a lot.
Henry, my folks will raise the dues.
I'm not asking you to give me your watch tomorrow. I'll bring it back as safe as though I'd never taken it.
But supposing my folks ask me what time it is.
All right, give me a call and I'll be glad to tell you what time it is.
Would you give me three weeks allowance?
Three?
Sure.
Come on over by this, please, so my mother doesn't see it.
Herbert, if there's ever anything I can do for you of any nature whatsoever, just name it.
Here, Henry's the watch. Thanks, Herbert.
Boy, if I got a run, it's a good thing we're eating late tonight.
- They'll be careful. - Herbert?
Uh, what is it, mother?
You have the correct time.
- Why, uh... - It's exactly 12 minutes to heaven, Mrs. Thompson.
Herbert, could you come here a minute, please?
Don't you think I got to put the lawnmower away first?
Will you please come here?
Sure. Has something going wrong, Mother?
May I see your watch, please?
My watch?
You didn't buy any chance. Give it to Henry, did you?
To Henry?
It was that you gave him.
I didn't give him anything. I loaned him my watch.
But, Mother, he's going to give me his allowance for the last two weeks in October and the first week in November.
Herbert, you realize how much of Father paid for that watch?
Put the money Henry's paying me as it was doing the investment.
I want you to march over to Henry's house and get that watch this minute.
Right now.
At once.
But mother, I don't think I should.
Have it.
Do you want me to tell your father?
Okay, I'll go.
And if you dare to come home without your watch,
you will go without your allowance for one entire month.
[Music]
Sam, ask Harriet.
But then she won't have another piece of steak.
More steak, Harriet?
No, thank you.
How many nights a week can you people afford steak?
Well, we're really having this for you.
You needn't afford it for me.
Where's Henry?
He ought to be done any minute, Anne Harriet.
I heard him run upstairs a little while ago.
Father never let us be late when we were children.
Henry! Henry, all rich!
Yes, Father!
Do you realize we're practically through with dinner?
I'll be right there!
Sam, as long as you have so much state, give me that piece next to the bone.
All right, sir.
What on earth is that? Henry!
I'm awfully sorry, I'm late. Hello, Aunt Harry.
How do you do?
Henry, didn't you know what time it was?
Oh, oh yes, father. It's ten minutes after seven.
And me, where did you get that watch?
Why, Mary, why?
Oh, nothing. Oh, when you have some bread and Harry.
No, thank you. And Harry, I want to tell you how very much I appreciate the watch.
Why didn't you write me about it?
I did, and Harry. Didn't you get the letter?
I did not. Let me see the watch. Here it is.
Who could that be at the door?
I see who it is.
Don't you want me to, mother?
No, thank you, Mary. I'm already on the way.
So you like to watch?
And Harry and I wouldn't work with it for anything.
Hello there Herbert.
How do you do Mrs. Orridge? Could I speak to Henry a minute?
I'm sorry but Henry's at dinner.
But I have to see him.
We're having guests, Herbert.
Well could I go into the dining room and speak to him?
No, you better go back home and see him tomorrow morning.
Oh no, I'll wait here until he's through.
But Henry will be busy all evening.
But Mrs. Orridge, Herbert, I'm quite sure anything you have to say can wait until morning.
Good idea.
Okay Mrs. Orridge, the only thing...
My goodness Herbert Thompson never comes over to this house except when we're eating.
Oh that's him?
Herbert.
Oh, Herbert, Herbert Thompson?
Yes.
What's the matter with him?
Nothing.
Henry, are you all through?
Yes, Father, I've caught up with you.
Well, I'll clear the table then.
Mary, you helped with dinner.
I'm sure Henry would be glad to clear the table.
Oh, yes, Mother.
Sure.
Should we keep our forks for the pie?
No, dear.
We're going to have clean ones.
Oh, OK.
Henry, don't break anything going through that door.
I won't.
Now, put everything on the big kitchen table.
Yes, Mother.
Here for, buddy.
Here you go.
Hey Henry, she was, who's that?
It's me.
Herbert, where are you?
You're here behind the refrigerator.
Oh, Henry, I've got to have my wife.
You're gonna listen, Herbert, aren't I?
Paying you for the use of it?
But if I don't get it, I'll lose a month's of a while.
Herbert, you can't back out on a bargain.
But you shouldn't have taught me anything.
Listen, Herbert, have sense, can't you see?
I'm... I'm...
Do I or don't I get my watch?
Let me have it just until the end of the meal.
No.
Henry?
Yes, Mother!
When are you coming back to the rest of these dishes?
Right away mother!
Henry, wait!
Get out Herbert, I gotta go back.
Well I'm gonna wait right here Henry until I get that one.
No Herbert.
Henry!
I'm just putting the dishes down carefully mother.
Here I come.
Was there something you wanted?
I'll take the rest of the dishes out.
Oh wait, mother I'll take it off.
I'll take everything in one load.
Henry, look out.
I haven't spold a thing.
Please sit down while I take these things out.
But mother, why not at least let Mary?
She's good at a thing like that.
Mary's done more than her share.
And I think I'll go up and lie down.
What's the matter with you?
I have a fever.
You're not to go to bed until the dishes are done.
I'll be right back to the pie, Harriet.
Henry, must you drink an entire glass of water in one gulp?
No, no, don't you think?
Henry, what are you doing?
I'm dying.
Here, you're looking to slap you on the back.
I'm all right, Anne, Harriet.
Do you think I found in the kitchen?
Listen mother, let me explain.
Explain, I let the burner on under a brand new pan.
You let the burner on under a pan?
I did.
Here Harriet, the piece of pie for you.
I could need a piece that big unless there's some cheese to go with it.
I have the cheese right here.
Where are you going now, mother?
Back to get the rest of the pie.
I don't want any.
But Henry, the rest of us might.
Oh, oh sure, of course.
Henry, you still need a new bicycle?
Well, I could certainly use one.
Mary, it is mother.
How many pieces of pie did you cut?
Pie?
Well, I brought in two, and when I just went back out, there were only two left.
There's one missing?
There is.
Well, I guess Mary only cut four.
But I'm sure I cut five.
Well, don't go back, mother.
I can't eat a thing.
The best pie I ever ate.
[SIREN WAILING]
Well, what could that be?
That whistle?
Yes.
Oh, I imagine it's just one of the fellows outside or something.
Sounded as though it would be right here in this house.
I think it was in the cellar.
From the cellar, Mary?
That's ridiculous.
She was, what is there in the cellar that would whisper?
We have some sold in, Harriet?
On my pie?
Well, some people I get in.
Henry, the doctor says that Harriet must never touch sold.
Well, I'm not kidding.
She certainly doesn't want any.
Isn't that strange?
Santa, is the hot water heater down the basement all right?
Perhaps I'd better go down and see.
You sit still, father, and finish your pie.
I don't care for any more.
I'm halfway out to the kitchen already.
Just turn the path off.
Yes, Father.
Hey, Herbert, you here in the kitchen?
Herbert, you down here in the basement?
Yes, and I want my watch.
Oh my gosh, it's so dark down here.
Where are you?
In the cold, but listen, Herbert, do you want to get me into serious trouble?
You want me to go up until you're in, Harriet?
That's my watch you have, please.
I beg of you.
decent inside of you Herbert please don't go up. Well I'm going up right now.
All right Herbert here's your watch G-Wiz. You better give it to me.
Here take the darn thing. She was the jadropa? You dropped it.
Where is it? Don't you have any light in this part of the cellar. What do you
want with a light in the coal bin for? Are you sure you aren't stepping on it?
How would I know? If I am Henry you'll be responsible. It's a funny thing. I fell
all around on the floor. There isn't any sign up. Let me feel.
Do you have it?
Whoa.
Herbert, here's a broom.
Stand up in the coal while I try to find it by sweeping.
OK.
Henry!
Yes, Father?
What are you doing down there?
I'm sweeping the cellar.
What for?
It's something I should have done weeks ago.
Herbert, Herbert, look.
I found it.
It's OK.
Yes.
Look out, Henry!
Herbert.
Herbert, are you buried?
Tell me to watch Henry.
Quick Herbert, quick, my father's coming, I think.
Let me up the stairs.
You can't go upstairs.
You gotta go in here.
In this little room where my father has his work bench.
Okay.
Don't bother to come down, Father!
What's the trouble down there?
Nothing!
Are you in there, Herbert?
Yeah.
We'll close the door tight.
I can't. There's no latch on the inside.
here I'll close it.
Give me my word.
Hey, I asked why you're sweeping this
fellow while your Aunt Harry is taking dinner with us.
I guess I just didn't stop the thank-bothering.
Who closed the door to my workroom?
But I have.
I certainly hope you didn't snap that lock, son.
Well, it snapped by itself.
Well, that's a nice state of affairs.
I've told everyone in this house I've lost both keys to that lock
and it must not be closed.
You mean it can't be open?
Of course it can't.
Not until I get a locksmith tomorrow afternoon.
[Music]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
Henry having lost the new watches and Harriet gave him,
as borrowed one exactly like it from his friend Herbert.
Herbert, in trying to get the watch back, got locked in Mr. Aldrich's work room.
The scene opens now in the Aldrich kitchen.
Henry!
Yes, Father?
Where are you?
I'm in the kitchen asking Mary if there's anything I can do to help her.
Your aunt Harry has been waiting here in the living room for you to come and play Rummy with her.
Ask father, I'll be right there.
Listen Mary, did you put in that phone call?
Yes, Henry.
Well, what did the locksmiths say?
His wife said she sent him over the minute he got home.
Did you tell her Herbert's been locked in the cellar for more than an hour and a half?
Yes.
Henry!
I'm coming right away, father!
And don't forget him, it was your promise to give me for putting in that call.
No, Mary, you get my allowance for the second and third weeks in November.
- Henry! - Coming, Father!
- Henry! - Is Anne Harry ready to play?
Well, I'm almost ready to go home.
Sit down here and deal the part.
Yes, Anne Harry, I see you give each seven cards.
- Henry, do you know anything about Herbert Thompson?
- Herbert? - Mrs. Thompson just phoned.
Herbert hasn't been home all evening.
Is that right?
The way this younger generation stays out nowadays.
Play your first card.
Oh, let me go.
His mother hasn't seen him for two hours.
Boy, it is time flying a crisis.
In a crisis?
I'll go to the door.
You stay right here and play with me.
Yeah, but that might be for me.
I'll see who it is.
I'm on my way now.
How do you do?
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
Kept me waiting.
Yes, man.
Didn't you phone for locksmith?
Who is it, mother?
Henry, ask your father if he's phone for a locksmith.
Oh, is there one out there?
Yes, sir.
Well, I didn't phone for you, but I do have a job downstairs you might attend to.
Father, who is there?
Henry, play your car.
You got somebody locked up downstairs?
Locked up?
No, sir.
Well, this place I was called to has an emergency of some kind.
Say, I better go back to the shop and shake up with my wife.
I'm sorry, this wasn't the house.
Well, that's okay, lady. All of these were...
Father, has the man gone?
Yes, dear.
Is Mary in the kitchen?
Yes.
I think I'll get in Harry at a glass of water.
I don't want any water.
Oh yes you do Anne Harry.
She was I'd be very glad to get it.
Mary.
What is it Henry?
Mary, Mary listen you gotta phone the locksmith again.
Where's Nick home?
He's come and gone.
They sent him away.
Henry I done all I'm going to.
Mary don't you realize my best friend is down in the basement locked in that room.
Maybe without air.
Henry if you think I'm going to make myself ridiculous by falling out locksmith every 10 minutes you're crazy.
Look, Mary, would you be interested in my allowance for the first week in December?
Well...
That practically cleans me out up to Christmas.
Henry, where's that water?
I'm letting it run in, Harriet!
All right, for you, Mary.
I'm putting the full responsibility for Herbert's condition on your shoulders.
When we get to the door to Father's workroom open and Herbert comes to,
he'll want to know who did this to him.
But, Henry, I haven't even seen him.
Henry!
Yes, see, and Harriet.
Here's your glass of ice cold water.
Now I can sit down and play.
Here you are.
Thank you.
What did you do?
Let the hot water run?
Was it warm?
I'll put it down and let it cool.
How could that have happened?
See, I played that car, didn't I?
I discarded it.
Oh, then it's my turn.
- Is that someone sawing wood?
- Is what someone sawing wood?
- Oh, oh, wow.
- I thought I heard a saw.
- You still haven't discarded.
- Oh, no.
- Oh, oh, wow.
What do you mean?
- What do you mean well, well, well?
You haven't put your car down.
- I thought I heard that sawing again.
- Yes.
And sounded as though I were in the basement.
- Maybe it's the hot water heater.
- I didn't even hear a noise.
You listen, you hear it.
(humming)
Henry, will you please stop singing?
I'd like to hear what that song is.
- Oh, excuse me.
- Very unharried is my card.
- And Harriet, did you know I've been taking
music lessons?
I'll play a tune for you.
- Not now.
- Look, here's what I learned so far.
(piano music)
- Henry.
- Yes, mother.
- I want you to go back to that card table,
and if I hear one word out of you for the next five minutes,
I'm gonna have to ask you to go up to bed.
- Yes, mother.
Now then let's listen.
Well, you wait.
I hope that that be.
Probably that locksmith again.
Is it?
I don't know, dear, and I won't know until I open this door.
Hello, Mrs. Orr, a chibbit.
Mother, is that Harvard?
Henry, come back here.
Henry, I want to talk to you.
Henry's playing Rummy with his aunt, Herbert.
And if you don't mind, I'll go into the living room.
Who's coming in here?
I am. I always wanted to play Rummy and now I'm going to.
Harriet, what's the score?
I'm two thousand ahead. It was I'm three thousand and going.
Herbert, how would you like another glass of ginger ale?
Sure.
Young man, do you realize this is the fourth bottle you've had?
It is. You drink anymore. You're going to go right up in the air.
- Herbert! - Yes, Mary.
Your mother wants to speak to you on the phone.
Okay.
You mean to say that young man is actually going to leave this room?
Well, I had a nice nap.
Father, you've been asleep for two hours.
Oh, I'm glad to see Herbert's gone.
What makes you think he's gone?
- Where is he? - He's phoning for his pajamas.
But, Mother, it's just a question of time.
As soon as he's in, Harry, it goes like got it.
He's got what?
There are several things I'd like to know.
One is that locksmith coming back the second time.
Yes, that some man was locked up here.
Well, I'll certainly be interested in reading what was in the morning papers.
Henry, I'm quitting.
You are?
Oh, uh, this only?
I'm not going yet.
Just not going to play anymore.
Yes, Anne, Harry.
Henry, I want to see your watch.
It's exactly eight minutes after eleven.
Let me look at it.
Oh, there's just one little thing I'd like to explain.
Give it to me?
Yes, ma'am.
How would you like to have me take this down to the jewelers and have your monogram put on it?
Who's monogram, Henry?
Who's do you think?
You mean my initials naturally?
Oh, I don't think he'd like that.
How do you know he wouldn't?
Oh, no, Aunt Harriet, she was.
Suppose, and Henry wanted to change his name sometime.
- To what, for instance? - Early thing.
Yeah.
Only girls use their monograms.
Henry, you let me take this and sometime during the next week or so, I'll have it in braid.
I'll put in my pocketbook.
Wouldn't you fight to have me carry your things out to the car for you?
What things?
Well, your pocketbook or anything?
No, thank you.
Henry, supposing you helped your aunt Harry go with her coat?
Well, I hold her pocketbook.
Put my pocketbook.
I'll put it right down here.
Thank you.
Anne, Harriet, don't you want to leave it there and go upstairs and see my new wallpaper?
You mean to say you got new wallpaper, but not asking me what to get?
Well, you told me to get it.
Well, I'll go up and see it, but I know I won't like it.
Oh, but I think you will.
Hand me my pocketbook.
Do you want to carry it all the way upstairs?
Give it to me.
Henry, don't you think it'd be nice if we helped
your aunt Harry up the stairs?
Yes, Herbert.
Let's do that.
Not so fast, boys.
So fast, but Henry?
Yes, Aunt Harry.
It isn't necessary to push me.
Alice.
Yes, darling.
Would you please tell me what's gotten into those two boys?
Trying to be nice to Harry it.
It isn't like them to be that nice.
Herbert's fond of us, and he fits.
[SINGING]
Well, Herbert.
Yes, Mr. Walrich?
Did you like the wallpaper?
Oh, very much.
Well, Henry, I guess I'll be going.
About what time is that, Herbert, my friend?
Well, my friend, it is exactly 21 minutes after 11.
Thank you very much.
Alice, what do you think I've lost?
What?
Well, sir.
So long, Henry.
You wait, young man.
I want to say good night to you.
What did you do?
I locked my car out in front of the keys inside it.
What?
Sam go out and get them.
And how would I do that?
Oh, here they are in my pocket.
The only thing is--
Now what?
Henry's watch is gone.
You mean it isn't there, Anne Harry?
Henry, I gotta go home.
Yeah, so long, Herbert.
Now who's dead at the door?
Hello?
No, Mr. Oldie.
Go ahead and then see Adams.
What are you doing here?
If Henry here, I just found his watch.
What?
His watch?
Where did you find it?
He left it over at my house this morning.
Well, how would you account for a thing like that?
Henry also let this letter you forgot to mail.
A letter?
Oh, yeah, here, Aunt Harry, it's for you.
Thanking you for my watch.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Listen again next week, same time, same station, for another sparkling half hour with your favorite youngster, his family and his pals.
The Aldrich family starring Ezra Stone is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
[Music]