[Music]
And now for the all-great family.
The actions of a teenage boy are above the closing of the thunderstorm.
They never see as long as he has an ounce of energy to draw.
And with Henry Olvitch, there are usually a few extra ounces in reserve.
It is Saturday morning and the scene opens on Homer Brown's front for end.
Oh my, look at it this way, it's January.
Stand back, Harry, you're crying.
And what better month is there to go fishing in than January?
Can we, can't you see, I'm busy watching the store and window?
What's the thing about home, are you cut a hole in the ice tree?
And you sit there and my nights lost the air.
Oh, it's not too frosty.
Just healthy.
Harry, why should I go sitting around in the air
when I can watch the store and window from my father?
Homer, do you feel well?
Yeah, well you step aside.
Boy, after all my father's done for me, it's only a second due.
But when we're big of a side sister, let's see him flex your tongue.
They've been growing ever since summer.
There's no use after me, Henry.
When my father wants me to do something, boy, I certainly wouldn't let him down.
What?
Come on, you sure you feel well?
Well, I think he's right in the living room there.
Oh, yes, sure.
Listen, look at every word we say.
Thank you, see, you got the window open.
I don't see him, I'm there.
My mother finally put a foot down on these windows.
What?
I'm walking outside, and my father's walking inside.
Only Kayleigh will listen.
Oh, Murr, what are you whispering about?
Oh, Father, can we just--
Oh, you were whispering?
[LAUGHTER]
How are you giving us your bra?
Henry, would you mind not confusing, Homer?
He could only think of one thing at a time.
Right now, he's supposed to be on the window.
- Well, Father, can you hear me?
We can't sound his way home.
- I was?
- Goodbye, Henry.
If you were that father, Homer.
- Listen, Homer, suppose I go in
and have a word with your father.
- What about?
- You know, when the field was better,
then you're licked before you start.
And he's putting your finger in the window, son.
- Well, it's worth a try.
I knew what.
Watch it step in.
He's pretty rigid.
They'll call me if anything here happens.
Oh, Mr. Brown, are you watching the window?
Of course I am.
And now do you think she is?
I just want to get the perspective from back here before I saw it.
Oh, hand me that darn sponge.
Mr. Brown, Mr. Brown, you're quite a fisherman aren't you?
What then?
Oh, I mean, fishing is good and spring sure, but no you agree there's no month like January.
For fishing?
Sure.
Don't you agree that that's when the fish are biggus?
Yeah?
Well, they've had some solar to put on waste.
[LAUGHTER]
Yes.
And I will look down at that way.
Sure.
I'll bet if you went down to Fletcher's pond
and chopped a hole in the ice, you could catch some whopper.
Yes.
I bet you.
What is that?
You mean you agree with me, Mr. Brown?
That a person should take advantage of a thing like that?
I certainly do.
Oh, boy.
Thanks.
Come here.
What is that?
I fixed it over your father and grieze that this is a perfect day for fiction.
He does.
Boy, father, you mean they don't have to watch the outside of the windows?
Of course you do.
Rock, why?
And the inside too.
Listen, Haley, I thought you said.
And get busy right away.
I have to speak to your mother.
Just think, Father, in January.
Henry, I don't want to speak to you again about your seat.
Why don't you run along and let me finish?
My seat, Father.
Are you afraid they'll get frosted, then?
I'm afraid they'll get chopped off.
Oh, sure. I'll stand back.
Thank you.
Why, look at that ice slide.
And if you could find time to demo,
let's talk more regularly.
The other way you're supposed to.
The ice wouldn't form like this.
I realize that, Father.
And I'll certainly see to it that I do it,
as you're there.
Good.
And the sitting of my father had all about it.
How about what?
Going fishing.
I'm sorry, anybody.
I can't find the time today.
Couldn't you cap the ice the mother's time?
Not very well.
Well, we're calling it Henry.
I can't get out of it.
Your mother is keeping an eye on me.
She is?
Don't look now, but she's right there in the living room,
when--
Oh.
Hello, mother.
Henry, I hope you aren't growing up your father.
Now, whether I'm helping him.
You are.
So are now.
I'm stopping out of it.
There.
You want to go to the phone.
Oh, thank you.
Get in there.
See, father.
What are you doing with it?
You can shop with it.
Oh, here he comes down at the bone.
Oh, is it well, Bob?
Yes, I don't know.
I told you a busy, but he said this is very important.
Hello.
Hello, Sam.
So why are the day you tied up saying?
Well, I'm doing a little cleaning up outside.
Oh, then he's telling you to get out of him.
Why, as a matter of fact, what's on your mind?
Sam, what do you say we go fish?
A dead?
Well, there's no better months to go fishing with you than anywhere.
But, well...
You know you're stuck in the hole in the ice, it's been around in the ice, off the air...
What made you think of that, Will?
I heard somebody talking about it. Come on, Sam, what do you think?
Well, it's a temptation, I'll admit. The only thing is, I have this work I should do.
Oh, do it tomorrow.
When you see Alice want a
Met me. I don't have to do it
Did it work?
Well, I'll meet you there in 15 minutes
Mary, who pays the bills around here?
What's up?
That is, I think I'll go out and get some some bars.
I'm at all anyway.
Hi, Mary.
Is that you, Homer?
Oh, come here, let's go. Let's go.
Where?
See which way you're through.
This way.
This is a fine time for you to decide that.
Just when I had to chop up the darn sidewalk for my father.
Where's your father hiding?
He didn't hide in any place. He would call the way on a very important conference.
He was. And besides, I thought you had to stay home and wash windows.
I don't know.
I saw him in awesome place. So I saw him in the sun even less.
Don't hit a wall anyway.
Oh, you really can't go.
Well, but you know how long it's taken me to chop this little bit of ice.
So long.
Well, it's going to take me a whole day to finish it.
If you thought I'd shoveled his walk once in a while, you wouldn't have all of his eyes.
Oh, good words. What are you eating? A piece of ice, it just flew in.
(audience laughing)
Listen, Homer.
Listen, if you think you can stand around all day eating ice when I'm breaking my darn back,
what are you getting at, Henry?
The least you could do is help me.
But why should we both break our back?
[Laughter]
Oh, what?
Maybe we can still go fishing.
Have you thought of hot water?
Hot water? Sure.
You have a home, haven't you?
What?
Sure, it's fine.
You didn't emphasize the no-turn.
Oh, gee, what are we standing on and on for?
[Music]
(cheering)
- Hey, deal that phrase, Will.
- Yes, sir.
- It really keeps you on your toes, doesn't it?
- Since then, how are you, toes?
- Oh, they're fine, Sam.
It's gone to my keep wiggling them.
- Family to saw again, let's see if I can get this whole
a little bigger.
You know, you couldn't catch a middle
through a whole the size of that.
- The trouble is getting you started, Will.
- Once I get the saw down in there, we'll be fine.
- Say, I got an idea.
You got a pen knife on you?
Yeah, certainly.
Here.
Now if I can just get a little more ice off, I think we can get the floor in there.
Good idea.
Yeah, that's getting it, Sam.
You mind if I run around the bit by you doing that?
You're not cold, I is.
Of course not.
Just a little sip.
I mean, I will do.
Alright, clap your arms, Sam.
Hey, what's that, it's real?
I'm paying the dollars.
Say, Sam, yes sir.
Sam, did you attack any sentimental value to that ten night?
Well, you're getting off the truth.
Well, now don't worry, I'll get it back out.
I have homework come out in the summer and dive for it.
That's my thing.
Now wait a minute, hand me my line. What for?
Well, it's got a good big hook on it. I think I can stick around and hook to penknife.
I doubt it, but here.
But here look you go on clapping Sam. I'll drop this in and then give it a try
Feel anything now
Let's just forget it
Hey, will get off the ice
I gotta finish look at that shadow under the eye
Why do I do hand it?
Don't just stand there, throw the whole figure!
I can't, but I will have to cut the line.
Don't do something, Sam! Don't do something!
Homework, homework, stop shivering and seeing still.
Listen here, I'm taking easy.
You're rubbing the back off me.
You're circulating again, darling.
Can't you talk it to you?
That one feels like sandpaper.
When I go to the women's closet and get some more towels.
Is there a link to a loan in your room?
Look at the sheet on.
Well, anyway, I'll find you some clothes.
And all I can say is, the next time you hold the sidewalk,
I hope you have a little more control.
Anyways, Homer, it was your own fault.
Mine's fault, mine's fault.
You were.
Then you come right out and say, "Turn the hose over here, Henry!"
You are here. I didn't say, "Turn the hose on me!"
And then you jump right in one way.
[laughter]
The whole boy knows how I feel about what his car is now.
It's a nice waterfall, James.
Well, you know what I was just thinking for?
See, if it's no fun-tapping life on your own sidewalk,
think I'm a stupor, it's one of the atoms, what your car is.
Sure.
See you stand around and wake you back and sing some things come along and play your nice water.
All of these cools and your mix brings you to the line.
Sure.
And right here at home we've got a fireplace and lots of wood.
So long.
Then we can sit in front of the fire with a comic book and a skyscraper sandwich.
Sure.
Some of them somewhere.
I'm going to be with...
I'm going to get a family.
I'm going to have to...
I'm going to get a tattoo here.
Extensive?
I thought I saw a milli-line.
What do you want?
Mother wants to see who's out on the living room.
He does? What's more?
I don't know. But you better come out down.
I can't even give me a...
Mother!
No, no, no, no. I don't think I've ever been so curious in my life.
Hey, mother.
Let's go out the window here.
Look at the condition of our truck walk.
Why, good, this is a solid piece of art!
The person just missed a bell right on his mailbag.
[audience laughter]
If your father's policy is safe,
then you have all that ice cleaned off today.
Brother, this is after a gift of power.
I'll give you my word.
Wait, wait, please, for good hold on.
We're going out? You are, dear.
I want you to go straight out to take this pond
and, Mother, I've changed my mind.
What about that?
I don't want to go to breakfast time anymore.
Well, I want you to, and you're the ten-year-old father
to come home immediately.
Father, the twickers are?
Yes, dear.
Mrs. Brown and I are positive.
That's where they went.
He's having his cocks on, sir?
My conference.
Oh, he is.
He's standing there.
He's out there with Mr. Brown.
This is.
He is.
We're all these dogs.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Anybody home?
Hey.
Hey! Anybody home?
What is the fire, Mr. S?
Oh, I'm sorry to be so noisy, but this isn't an emergency.
- If you're not an act. - I sure.
You want to come in? No, I can't.
I have to get back down to flesh and pine.
What's the trouble?
My friend and I went down there fishing,
see, and all of a sudden there was this big
that was splashing around.
- Under that? - My friend is hanging on
for dear life, and the hole isn't taking off
the porting out.
He's all a thing.
And man, is he struggling.
If we don't get him out fast, we're gonna lose him.
Now look, you find an act around the side on the ground.
Oh, fine. Thanks a lot.
You get right down there and don't worry.
Father, it'll be part of my stupid surprise.
Get you down to the pond right away.
Where are my boosters back?
Quick, you better get me a rope.
Come down here, fallin' through the ice.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
And now getting back to the trouble,
look Henry Alden.
Henry, and trying to talk Homer into going fishing
with the eye that preceded only in selling both their father's on the idea
so far the men are having difficulty landing their face and the boys have been sent out
to find the scene opens at such a spot.
Hurry up with.
I'm treating the Jack.
Now listen, ma'am, I got up to that farmhouse and back as quick as I could.
Well, at least you've been moving.
Here, you hold the pick right and that needs to come.
Let's do space.
Oh boy, it's good to sit down.
I get to sit down the way, Will.
My feet are all right.
Let's hurry and get that fish out and get home.
Well, it's a lady of some kind.
Have we seen her?
Oh, ma'am.
Look, Sam, it's a lady of some kind.
Have we seen her?
Oh, ma'am.
What's going on?
My dad.
I'm not coming up at the Lord's end of the car.
We've been looking all over and we haven't been able to find anything.
Well, say, we've been here for over an hour.
We haven't seen anybody around here.
I'm seven. I have the toxins in these glands.
Look, I'm sure it's expected.
A car in the sense that I knew.
Why, I thought it was more.
You don't think it's going through up its purchase tree?
Sure, I feel you here.
You must be up there.
I think we did it. Get up there. Right away.
I'll go and get my house.
We have time. Come on, Will. On your feet.
What's Sam? What about our sick?
We can't worry about that now.
I've aligned this tree over here and we'll come back for it later.
Father! Father!
Oh, my God, Ed!
Oh, are you sure this is what you're talking to?
You're sure you are.
Nothing looks familiar anymore since it started this now.
It's a mystery.
You don't find our father here.
That's fine, Ed.
It's a little going home.
Oh, my baby, there are lots.
Oh, Homer.
Homer, where are you?
I'm from here.
Oh, here I'll help you out.
Help.
Hey, wait.
You know what I think?
I think there are lots.
How could we be if this is what your time is?
The human, if it's just over a thing.
What?
And I'm the thing to do, I'm like this.
Time.
Summer.
Summer, this isn't any basis, a piece of strength.
Now listen, I'm not that mean.
But look, Homer.
Look, it's trying to achieve.
It is an assembling.
Seriously, it's a white one, so I follow it along.
Except it is re-ggling.
She lives here right.
What do I think, Summer, is snowing.
What is it?
You go down to a hole in the ice.
Bring me to a hole.
What?
There's a structure in the end of it.
It's great to see it.
Well, all these do on.
Pull it out.
The hole is in the middle.
And if he was hooked up here, I'd let it snow.
Why?
And then, I'd say, it's a miracle.
You're that a hole.
Well, I could dream.
Bring me to the good top.
I'm going to see the hole.
Get back to the house before we wake up.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(music)
Well, if you turn around and walk backwards, we'll get there a lot faster.
You walk, you're always, Sam, and I walk fast.
I think that's where it's at. It's not flowing in what's past.
Yes, and I walk into all the trees I'm going to walk into.
You're still bumping into trees, walking backwards.
I can stand it better that way.
Anyway, here's like a spot.
Boy, I'd like to get my hand from a guy who started us on this wild goose day.
Well, we'd be pretty well had to go.
Well, suppose somebody really had fallen through the ice.
We had to go, sure.
I wouldn't have minded going up there and taking a quick look around.
Now, I'm just right around here.
That woman insisting that we hunt for three solid hours.
I said, I don't think I'll ever go out.
Do you remember what thing we tried out to find you?
Oh look at that. Look at that. No all over the place. Oh well. Even if we do find the tree.
How are we gonna find the king? Well if we can only keep our sense of humor we'll be all right.
Ah what? Same time ready so bet. As a matter of fact the square.
There's our tree. I just need to remember that broken branch.
No. Oh the ice can't be forgotten yet. Oh we'll never find it in this snow Sam.
A tiny little hole like that. We'll find it all right.
Look!
Turn!
We'll come out!
How does that fire feel to us?
If you'd like to mark this, John, I'd like to give you a word.
If it's good to keep that blanket over your shoulders now, my friend.
Oh, I will. We'll be lucky if we don't bulk catch pneumonia.
I think it's going over flexors time.
- It's fighting. - And John, if you could have only seen those poor men
hollering with me up there versus please.
Now who that is?
Well, who's that answer?
I guess I better.
I'm sorry, not technical.
- Yes, some click, Mr. - Oh, you again.
Hurry, bring those blankets in the hospital.
I'm just out for the ice.
Oh, yeah?
Well, talk to the police.
What?
If you think I'm going to pull the next toy
up in your place.
Oh, you son!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
That's-- look at him.
Mother, isn't he?
You remind me of his in-it, that's
what he gets inside everything.
He gets away from his dog.
He's sedating his officer.
He's coming out by yourself?
Well, we didn't actually talk to him.
We were walking along in the middle of nowhere.
And all of a sudden, there he was.
High to a tree.
- Come on, mother! - Ah, mother!
- Come on, mother! - Come on, mother!
- Oh, boy, come on, I've got a juicy log.
- You have to sit around like that, do you hear?
- 'Cause we haven't, man.
- It's a small log.
- Why don't you take the key? - Edward!
- Ben, is that you? - Oh, well, that's right.
- I just think that's the deal, but, Sam, what happened to our front wall?
- Yeah, what happened to you? - Let me tell you something.
A few minutes ago, we started up the front wall.
And I mentioned the wheel, "Ah, happy, I want to get home."
When all of a sudden, there we proved well flat on our back.
Who turned our front wall into a skating rink?
- Sam, that's what walking your own fall.
And then I asked who was told you wearing?
That my own other thing just a little drunk.
I was talking more.
All right.
I got him.
The car.
Let's go.
All right.
Forget it.
Let's forget everything.
Let's just lie down here.
Move over, Sam.
So I'm thinking we're going to get you some blankets.
Father.
Every coming here.
Good.
They're running you.
They're there.
You're into one of their chesies.
Every.
When could you get that there?
We found this, Father.
You're a addict, but you're a
But that's what you've got. Sorry, that you and the floor.
Henry, was that safe by any chance?
Side to a tree. What? What do you know about that?
In that case, I'm a guinea pig. You want to have a good look at it, Bob?
It happens. It's that safe. It belongs to Mr. Brown and Denise.
So, now you're still on me. Oh, yes, oh, man.
I'm sorry, boys, but we caught it and we tied the line to the tree.
But father, even if he did, we landed.
Henry's come day.
I'll tell you what we went through today
because of that thing.
I'll hand it over to you.
But he wins.
Henry's.
Yes, father.
Well, let's see it,
let's have a good look at it.
It's near a beauty.
Oh, boy.
He was late.
10 pounds.
8 pounds.
[LAUGHTER]
It's all right, too, man.
Come on, father.
Boy.
Oh, no.
Oh, why don't you go along with Henry
and stop asking questions?
Well, do you think we should know them?
Who? Oh, man.
[ Laughter ]
I'm so proud of you.
All right, all right.
Oh, here. Hold it, please.
We'll have your right back.
Hey, sure. And, Sam, we ought to take a picture of it, you know.
Hello?
Oh, and that's a problem.
Yes?
I understand you're a commoner, Steve.
You don't care. My friend and I are a designer.
It is our best.
Well, what we will do today, I'd like to see anyone else claim that best.
I understand you're a commoner.
Our best is the beauty of 10 pounds, man.
Let me tell you how we call it.
You can tell me all about it in my office at 10 o'clock in the morning.
- Who is this? - The game was.
You're not allowed to catch fast and genuinely.
No way!
Will everyone have another piece of space?
I will, please.
I paid enough for it.
I might as well enjoy it.
I don't mind a bit you're taking the fix away from me, Todd.
Oh, that's fun. I got something much better.
Who and I was feeding the fix to you and who are you?
What a game for a miracle.
Oh, thanks. Guess what we found inside it, Mother?
What, dear?
It's something I've always wanted, a pen knife.
What's done?
[Music]
(loud static)
(static)