[Music]
Henry! Henry Aldrich!
Coming, Mother!
The Aldrich family! A special rebroadcast for you soldiers, sailors, and Marines of the United Nations.
[Music]
It does grown up, no end of good to go back now and then to a time when the world was younger.
And the first thing they'll need on that return trip will always be a typical teenage boy like Henry Olbridge.
The scene opens on the Aldrich Front lawn.
Homer, did you look around and back for?
Yes, sure. I looked every place.
And there isn't a sign that would be yours or mine.
Oh boy, oh boy.
Let's lookin' back again. But Henry, I remember distinctly.
We left them both lights there by that tree.
Sure, that's why they can't be very far away, Homer.
After all, we just went down the corner store for ten minutes.
Henry, look, isn't that Mary coming down the street?
Yeah, sure. But don't say anything to her about her losing them, Homer.
You only go running around telling all my parents.
You don't have to worry, Henry.
Boy, if my father finds out I've lost mine.
- Henry!
- Yes, Mary?
- His father's to you?
- Me?
- What, are you looking for me?
- Yes, Henry.
Is I was starting over to Kathleen a little while ago?
He and Homer's father were looking all over for you.
- They were, Mary.
- Henry, what are you looking at the front porch for?
- Nothing, Mary. Nothing.
You just stay long inside.
I wanna make sure of something.
- We wouldn't remember if we put them there.
Mary, say both our fathers were looking for us.
Sure she did.
Oh, boy.
I never felt so sick in my life.
Hey, I hope you haven't forgotten.
You promised to wake up the lawn this morning.
No, Mother, I haven't forgotten.
Only first, have you seen my--
Have you seen my life?
I've seen what?
Nothing.
Just forget the whole thing.
There was anything to get up stuff about.
I don't think.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
- Are you coming Sam?
- Fine, this bicycle of Henry's run
just as smooth as the top.
- Homer doesn't so bad either.
Glad you suggested we take them.
- Let's turn down this road here Will.
We can leave our bike at the edge of the woods
and walk through to the lake.
- All right Sam.
- Yeah, this is gonna be exactly what we need.
Getting away and going fishing like this Will.
I just hope the boys weren't planning to use
their bicycle today.
won't use them. They won't even miss them. I've told Homer over and over again. He doesn't
appreciate the things I give him.
Eh? Well, Henry will certainly find that note I left for him.
Where did you leave the note? I tied it to the garden rake. He was going to clean up the
backyard first thing this morning so he'll be sure and see it.
Hey, Sam! Look! No hands!
Yeah? That's nothing, Will. Watch me put my feet up on the handlebars!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SIREN WAILING]
Oh, boy, Henry, what are we going to do?
Now stop and think once more, Homer.
Where do you remember seeing our bicycles?
The last time you saw--
I told you, Henry, they were leaning against that tree.
Oh, boy.
And you know what?
My father said he was going to do to me if I ever
lost my bicycle.
Well, I know what my father said he do.
He turned me away to boarding school.
He would?
When you phone the police, what did they say?
They said that it's an hourly port,
but we shouldn't plan.
Ever sing them again.
You know what I think we ought to do, Henry?
Go up and down the street to this town
and keep our eyes open.
Boy, anybody that would play a dirty trick
like stealing a couple of guys' bicycles.
That's what I think.
And boy, will we lay into them.
- Henry!
- Yes, Mary?
- I think it's any of my business.
I think I ought to tell you something.
Mother is just terribly upset.
- Oh, you mean she knows Mary?
Yes, Henry. Of course she knows.
told her. Oh my nobody had to. All she had to do was look out in the backyard. You mean
they're out there. What's out there? Oh my don't you realize that you're hanging
around here like this is just keeping Henry from raking up the backyard. Oh oh gee whiz
Mary why didn't you tell me it was a backyard she saw when she looked out the window. Oh
hey Homer look come on. Where are you going? You haven't been anywhere near that race all
morning. Mary I can't stop the fool around with that right now. Henry what are we running
Don't you see that guy on the bicycle down there on the next ride in mine?
You know it's mine, can't you see it's what?
I can tell from here it's mine.
Little hurry up, let's call Zinnar in him.
Hey you! You are that bicycle!
Stop!
He was hitting me, it's Charlie Clark.
Hey Charlie!
We'll go here to take my bicycle.
You know what we want to do to him, Henry?
Ow, say, "Hey Charlie!"
(cheering)
- Hello?
- Hello.
Mrs. Aldrich?
Mrs. Clark?
- Who?
- Mrs. Clark.
Charlie Clark, father.
- Oh yes, good morning.
- Mrs. Aldrich, I think you should know
that Henry deliberately pulled Charlie off his bicycle.
Kyle Charlie was finding his own business
and tried to take his bicycle away from him.
- I beg your pardon, Mrs. Clark.
- Can't you hear me?
I can't hear you, but you're talking so fast I can't entirely understand you.
Your son Mrs. Orridge jumped to the wrong conclusion.
He jumped at an entirely wrong conclusion.
And it killed my boy Charlie of stealing his bicycle.
Henry, dear.
Henry and Homer, they both jumped on him.
Well, my goodness Mrs. Clark, I don't see how they could possibly have done that.
Henry and Homer are upstairs right this minute.
They're there at your house.
They're upstairs washing.
They've been working around the house all morning.
But that's utterly impossible.
Charlie came in here less than two minutes ago and he fans are torn.
Oh, Mrs. Clark, I don't see what that proves.
Mrs. Aldrich.
Homer, is that you?
Yes, Mrs. Aldrich.
You know where I can find the iodine for Henry.
Homer, I knew all the time you were here at the house.
What's that?
Dear, I want you to come here to the phone and talk to Mrs. Clark.
Listen, Mrs. Aldrich, I--
Homer, all I want you to do is speak to her and sure you're here.
Now, yes, dear.
Please take the receiver.
Yes, ma'am.
Hello, Mrs. Clark.
Goodbye.
Here, Mrs. Aldrich.
Thank you, Homer.
No, what was it you came downstairs to get?
Oh, why nothing, Mrs. Orridge.
I don't think Henry would want to bother you.
We can locate it ourselves.
All right.
Hello, Mrs. Orridge.
Are you still there?
Hello, Mrs. Clark.
I said, ma'am.
Well, who was that?
I just spoke to.
That was Homer Brown.
And it might introduce you to know that Henry is right up there
with him.
And in the future, it seems to me that Charlie should
be a little more careful himself about jumping at conclusions.
But Mrs. Orridge, as Charlie said,
that Henry said that Charlie could get bicycles.
That's just what I mean, Mrs. Clark.
You can see for yourself how ridiculous it sounds.
- Can me? - Yes, Mother.
Mrs. Clark is on the phone and I want to ask you something.
I don't think I can talk for an hour, Mother.
Dear, all I want to know is,
didn't I see your bicycle out there on the lawn
under the tree this morning?
- Why?
- Yes.
- And did Charlie Clark take it at any time?
- No.
No, he didn't take it.
Charlie has a long bicycle.
- Mrs. Clark?
- Hello? - Hello.
- Mrs. Clark, if you tell Charlie
to please go back and look very promptly
he'll see that he has his own bicycle and not Henry
yes of course he has
then i don't see what the bus is all about
and this is part of the story but i have a pie in the oven
[Music]
I'll need help you carry a line and tackle Will
no thanks Sam
I can carry it alright
Because if you're having any trouble, I'd be glad to at least carry that fish.
No, thanks.
About how much farther you think it is out to where we left our bicycle?
Oh, not too far, Will.
Ah, did you ever feel better in your life, Sam?
No, sir.
Been a good day, good fishing, and good everything.
Here's the road, Sam.
Huh?
Already?
Now then.
Under which bush?
What's that?
Well, what are you stopping here for?
This is where we left our bicycle.
Well, what are they?
That's what I want to know.
I put Homer's right here and you left Henry's left.
Well, that's strange.
Are you sure this is a play?
Of course it is, Sam.
Somebody stole them.
No, they didn't.
We're just a little mixed up.
All we have to do is look around and do is find them.
But Ed, I think you ought to have a talk with Charlie.
I'm perfectly willing to have a talk with him, Will.
But why don't you just let the whole thing drop?
Ed, Charlie Clark is your boy.
just as much as he is lying and I've never, never been so embarrassed as when I
told Mrs. Olga. What did you say to her? Well, at first I told her I'd into it and
even when he said Henry was right there at the house and had even seen Charlie, I
practically insinuated she was lying to me. Yeah? Well, whatever made Charlie cook up
a story like that. I don't know, dear, but I suppose he was afraid to come home
with his hands torn and Henry was the first person to have him. The origins are
really nice people and I think Charlie ought to be punished. All right, I'll tell
He's telling me to go to bed for the rest of the day.
The only thing is, he promised to take some girl to the movies this afternoon.
All right, all right. I'll let him go over and tell her he can't take her.
But we're going to teach Charlie to be a gentleman.
Give us the last thing we do.
Hello? Hello?
Hello? Hello, is this all, Rich?
This is police headquarters. I'm calling about that bicycle. It's missing.
- My goodness, the bicycle. - Yes, ma'am.
Now here's the way things stand, lady.
- But just a minute. We don't have any bicycle missing. - You know what?
I'm sorry that the whole thing isn't a third mistake.
A mistake? Oh, no. I've got a report here under the name of Aldrich.
Two bicycles stolen.
But that guess goes to kill how long it is.
In the first place, Henry doesn't own two bicycles. He's never owned more than one.
Yeah? Well, how would you account for a mistake like that?
I had no idea. Only I do hope that sooner or later we can get this whole thing straightened out.
We'll take care of it, lady. Don't worry.
Good night.
Hey, Captain. Can I have a talk with you?
You can. Only first.
Didn't we get a report a little while ago that a state trooper picked up a couple of bicycles out on the edge of the woods near the big lake, is we?
I didn't know. Sure we did.
I thought they answered the description of two bicycles lost by all of us.
What's happening? It's the all reach bicycles that I wanted to talk to you about.
I think I just picked one of them up.
Where is it?
In the next room.
Um, come in here, sonny.
What is it you want?
I'm a captain here.
What it is you say your name is.
It's Charlie Clark, but this isn't Henry older.
She's bicycle. It's my own.
What were you doing with it?
Nothing. I was going over to tell my girl I can't take her to the movies
because I'm not a gentleman.
[laughter]
Okay, then take your bicycle and go tell her.
Now then, what are we going to do with those other two bicycles?
[cheering]
(dramatic music)
- Do you see anything of them, Will?
- No, Sam.
If you asked me, those bicycles have been stolen,
and we're lost.
- No, we're not that south right over there.
- No, it isn't.
South is this way.
- Which way?
- Where I'm pointing with this fish.
- Will, I still don't understand
why you didn't wrap that fish,
while we still had some paper.
- I hated to cover it up, Sam.
It was such a nice color.
- How about the boy's bicycle, Will?
Suppose we don't find them.
I mean, what are we going to tell Henry and Homer?
That's what I've been wondering, Sam.
If we don't find those bicycles, I'm not going home.
Even if we find our way out of here.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Don't you think that's a good idea, Homer?
I mean, going down here to this bicycle shop
and asking whether anybody tried to sell them
two bicycles today?
I agree with you.
Only don't you realize when somebody tries to sell a bicycle a stolen, they usually...
Hey, Henry, lookin' back of it.
Those come.
It's our father's. It's our father's.
What are we gonna tell him, Henry, if they ask us where our bikes are?
Do they see us? I don't think so.
They stop.
And they're looking in the store window.
Oh, boy.
What's fuckin' the value here?
Look out, Henry. Let me in first.
Well, D, would you don't have to show me against a brick wall.
Come on, stop pushing.
Well, right.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
It's all right, Sam. The boy's gone.
Do you think they saw it?
No.
You know, well, we've walked 15 miles if we've walked a foot.
Do you know why I think no one would give it the right, Sam, because of this fish I'm carrying?
I told you you should have left it back there, but no. You were too anxious to have everybody see it.
I didn't know I was going to have to carry it all day, though.
Wait a second. Wait a second.
What do you see?
Isn't it the bicycle shop we're going right by here?
- What do you think we step in and see whether they don't have to use one for sale?
- That's an idea.
And while you're doing that, I'll be down to the office and phone my brother-in-law
and see whether he'd be willing to sell his daughter's bicycle.
- You think you might?
- Well, you can't tell.
The girl's bicycle.
But if Homer says anything, I'll just ask him whether he doesn't know there's a war on.
- And here, Sam. - What is it?
- Take this fish.
- Oh, no, Wille. Oh, no, no. You caught it. You keep it.
- Now, Sam, I have to go way up to the office here.
- Wille, I don't want it.
- You give it to Henry. He's going to be feeling pretty bad.
- I know, but...
I know, but well.
Is there something I can do, boy?
Mr. Alders?
Hello there, Mr. Sparrow.
I'm in thought of a jam, and I wondered whether you could help me out.
Oh, you want something to wrap that fish in?
Oh, well, not exactly.
What I want is...
You haven't used bicycles.
I wish I did have.
None?
I'm really in a... I took Henry's bicycle fishing, and...
Now, wait a minute.
What did you see?
You see that boy riding by outside there?
Isn't that Charlie Clark?
I think so.
Well, he may have a bicycle exactly like Henry,
but I'm pretty sure I could swear--
I'll be right back, Mr. Sparrow.
Charlie Clark!
When you want, Mr. Algory.
Would you mind getting off that bicycle for a minute?
This isn't Henry's bicycle.
No?
How'd you know I was going to ask you that?
Now listen, Mr. Algory, you let go of me.
Then get off.
Get off that bicycle.
Now listen, Mr. Algory!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(audience cheering)
We'll be back with the Alders family in just a moment.
Right now it's intermission,
and time for our intermission guests,
the one and only Tommy Dorsey.
Okay, Tommy.
(upbeat music)
(jazz music)
(lively music)
♪ For one, two, three ♪
(drumming)
(lively music)
[Music]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(audience applauding)
(audience cheering)
(upbeat music)
(lively music)
(dramatic music)
(jazz music)
(lively music)
(dramatic music)
(upbeat music)
(jazz music)
(dramatic music)
(audience applauding)
(audience cheering)
[Music]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Olgred.
Henry and Homer, not knowing that their fathers
have borrowed their bicycles to go on a fishing trip,
think that they have been stolen and have reported it to the police.
Their fathers, on the other hand, not knowing that the police
have found the bicycles out by the lake,
are afraid to tell the boys that they apparently have been stolen.
The scene opens in the older living room.
Sam! Sam!
Yes, Oliver?
You want it on the telephone right away?
Yes, who is it?
It's Mr. Clark, dear. He's very much upset about something.
Mr. Clark? You tell Mr. Clark I don't care to speak to it.
Oh dear, I can't tell him anything like that. He's angry enough as it is.
Well, tell him I'm busy right now. I don't have to talk to him if I don't want to.
Sam, are you handling some kind of a lawsuit for him?
A lawsuit? You talking about a lawsuit?
That's what it sounded like. When he gets excited, he talks even faster than Mrs. Clark.
Well, if he's going to take that attitude, I'm not going to talk to him at all.
Where's the iodine?
iodine?
What is it you want iodine for?
Nothing.
Just forget it.
Well, my goodness.
Hello, Mr. Clark.
Hello.
Mr. Clark, I'm terribly sorry, but Mr. Aldrich wondered whether he couldn't phone you a little
later.
He apparently just caught himself as something.
Yes, I know all about it.
What's that?
When is he going to call me?
No, Mr. Clark, I don't know what it is you want to discuss with Mr. Aldrich, but I'm sure
you'll hear from him later.
Very well, then.
Goodbye, Mr. Clark, and thank you so much for calling.
Goodbye.
Well, my gracious.
Mother, the yes Henry!
Mother, is anyone foreign ass raised or me or Homer in the last hour?
No, dear. We have your two boys in.
Why, just... just over the town and around.
You've been over to town?
Yes. And look, Mother. When father comes home this evening, could you tell him I'll be having dinner at Homer?
And my house Henry? I'm not even gonna be there.
Your father's already home.
Oh, yes? Now?
He knows certainly is. And you might as well know, dear, I'm very much disappointed in your attitude
about cleaning up the backyard.
I don't believe you've even touched that rake all day.
But, Mom, I thought--
She was where you going?
I'm going to see you at the front door.
Oh, I'm so bored.
Let's go up to my room.
OK, let's go right on up to the attic.
Alice!
Yes, Sam.
Someone at the front door and walk to see you.
Who is it?
Mr. Clark?
No, dear.
The man from the bicycle shop.
What's that?
The bicycle shop?
Yes, dear.
And he says he has something you'll be very glad to get.
He has?
He's had a load off my mind.
Alice is what I've been meaning to tell you.
but somehow I couldn't.
Sam, I think you better go to the front door.
Yes, Alice, but here's what happened.
I borrowed Henry's bicycle and lost it.
You what?
But Alice, don't you understand?
The fellas found it, and they didn't think the worry about it.
Well, where did he find it?
I don't know.
That's what I'm going on at Naskybs.
Hello, there, Mr. Sparrow.
I'm gently glad to see you.
Well, here you are, Mr. Olrich.
And you thought you'd lost it.
At that?
What is it?
It's your face.
I put a newspaper around her.
[LAUGHTER]
I make her pardon.
You left it right in my window.
As the darndest time find not where the smell came from.
Well, thank you. Thank you very much.
That's okay. Hope you enjoy it.
Yes.
Sam, is it in good condition?
Well, apparently it smells a little.
Can I re-find it?
Now, you tell me exactly how the whole thing happened.
Well, there's going to be a lot about it
that you find hard to believe, Alice, but first, here, take this.
Sam, what is it?
A fish. Riot for Henry's dinner.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello.
Hello, Sam.
How are you speaking?
Oh, hello, Mr. Allrich.
This is police headquarters.
Yes?
I am calling about that bicycle, Mr. Allrich.
About the bicycle?
Is Mr. Clark report that?
Oh, Mr. Clark.
Is Mr. Clark down there with you?
Oh, no, sir.
Why, here's what I want to tell you.
Before you tell me anything, let me tell you something.
The whole thing with just the case of mistaken identity.
But Mr. Allrich--
I am a lawyer.
a new tell that part of the he wants to sue to come on and serve the paper that
isn't one thing he can prove what's that but Mr. Orange and Mr. Orange
hello say if these are by second who's early you know what I've decided to do
homework why I'm gonna tell my father the whole thing and get it off my chest
listen to me if you tell your father he'll tell my father and I don't want to
I'm going to get it off my chest until I get this week's allowance.
Just the flame I'm going to tell him.
Hey!
Oh, well, look, Henry, I'm going outside.
Henry, have you seen your father anyplace?
No, mother.
As a matter of fact, I was just going to look for him.
You were?
Uh-uh.
You said I'm right here, and Henry wants you for something too.
Well, mother, I did want to see him, but I sort of came for him and I'll see him a little later.
Uh-uh.
Yes, Sam.
Right here, dear.
I've been taking things over, and it seems to me that sooner you tell Henry what happened the better.
Alice, can't you tell him for me?
Frankly, I'm gonna feel like two cents saying Henry,
I'm sorry, but I lost your bicycle.
- Say I'm on a shame debut.
- Alice, I'm not afraid to tell the boy.
I just don't want to upset him just before dinner.
Why not sit down and have a good meal?
And then tomorrow morning, right after breakfast,
or maybe when I get home from church tomorrow noon,
I'll come right out and tell him.
- Sam, did you ask Henry that you could borrow his bicycle?
- You mean I should have?
- Father!
- Alice, is that Henry calling me?
- Father?
- Yes, Henry, your father's right here.
Oh, my ears.
Well, she was...
Hello, Father.
Hello, Henry.
Did you...
Did you have a nice, baby offer?
Well, pretty good.
That is, I...
Well, that's the offer, exactly.
No, that's quite true.
Henry, I'm gonna have to go out and get Dennis started,
and I'm sure your father has something he wants to say to you.
But Alice...
Well, as a matter of fact, Father,
I've been thinking things over and...
I'd like to make a confession.
You were?
As a matter of fact, Henry, there's something I feel I should say to you.
But first, Father, could you please just let me finish?
Henry, I know exactly what you're going to tell me.
You do?
If you were busy with other things today and didn't have time to touch the backyard, it's quite alright with me.
Did he?
How much was I going to pay you an hour for that?
Well, 15 cents, you usually pay me.
15? Only 15? You want to make me pay you 20.
Just to clean up a backyard when I didn't?
There's two dollars. I'll run along and forget it.
But, Father, that isn't what I was going to talk to you about.
It isn't.
No, sir.
This morning, Father, what were you going to tell me?
Who I?
Oh, yes.
Yes, Father.
Well, Henry, this morning, that is what I mean to say as--
Father, do I smell fish?
Fish?
Yes, you certainly do.
One of these days you and I are going fishing together.
Yes, Father.
But how about this morning?
How about it?
Oh, I'm very busy.
I'm very busy.
Oh my God, my father's going to give me a lecture.
Henry of Homer wants you the thing to do is go and see what it's about.
Now?
Yes, of course.
Henry, I'm coming!
Homer G. Webb!
Dad, what did Henry say when you told him?
Well, tell you, Alan.
Homer, what is it?
Come on, Alan.
Can we just look like I'm the friend of ours?
Homer G. Webb, weren't you got a bicycle?
The police just drove up with him.
And boy, were they sure about something.
They were sure.
All these would throw them on the grass there and then they drove away.
Edward!
Listen, we're quick.
- Hey, come around the back, what's for?
- He was my father's got something on his mind.
Then I don't want him to lecture me
about leaving my bicycle on the front lawn all day.
- Okay, Henry, I'll take him around.
- Henry!
- Yes, father?
I'm out here on the porch.
- I've just been talking with your mother, Henry.
And she thinks, what I mean is I think
I better get the whole thing off my chest.
- Yes.
- Son, your bicycle is pretty important, isn't it?
I guess if you lost it, you would know what to do,
would you?
If I ever lost my bicycle, yeah, I'd just never forget myself.
Well, if you couldn't have your bicycle anymore, what would you like in place of it?
Oh, yeah, I'd never be willing to sell it.
I wouldn't even let Alrigroj for a million dollars.
But suppose it isn't in the garage.
But it is, Father.
Oh, you think it is?
Well, that brings us around to what I wanted to talk about.
Henry...
What, Homer?
I just took my bicycle out of the garage and I'm going home.
Your bicycle?
So long, Mr. All-
Wait a minute, wait, you get that.
There are any bicycles out of the garage?
Yes, there are, Mr. All-
I didn't mean to have to earn mine was there a minute ago.
Father, you didn't think for one minute, I'd be so careless that-
No, just a minute.
What wasn't you were going to say, Father?
Uh, not a thing, not a thing.
You know, you used a note I found around and back for you.
For me, I happen to see it tied to the Ray Campbell.
Oh, she went.
Oh, well, here, give me that.
But Father, this notes for me.
You have enough to worry about without this note.
Hey, Sam.
Oh, gee, what here comes my father.
Sam, I got one of them.
Well, bro, where'd you get that bicycle?
It's Henry.
I took it away from Charlie Claus.
[LAUGHTER]
Oh, I'm sorry.
Has anyone ever had the iodine?
And now wait a minute.
Oh, ma, where did you get that bicycle?
This?
Don't you remember, father?
You gave it to me two years ago.
[LAUGHTER]
Sam, you wanted on the telephone.
Mr. Clark wants to talk to you again.
[LAUGHTER]
[audience applauding]
- Callie, I want you to stop sitting there feeling sorry for yourself and eat your dinner.
- All of it, Father? - All of it.
- But Father, I don't like this. - Callie, the Aldrichs were kind enough to send that fish over just for you.
Now set up an eight!
(audience applauding)
(audience cheering)
(breathing heavily)
(buzzing)