[Music]
If you weren't too far from the days when you were in high school,
you probably remember that a teenage boy is about as unpredictable as the wind.
And so because Henry Aldrich is an average boy,
the kind you'll find anywhere in your town,
well, there's just no telling.
It's morning and the scene opens in the Aldrich Mythi room.
Now, don't worry, Ed, I've taken care of everything.
I know the country courts wouldn't have a better chairman of the arrangement committee.
Thank you, Anne.
But I can't help worrying.
Last year, only 11 people turned up for our Fourth of July celebration.
And six of them were waiters.
That's right.
Well, this Fourth of July will be different.
I have a rose surprise.
A surprise?
A special fireworks display.
George Washington crossing the Delaware on Hothback.
It's famous.
Didn't Washington cross in a rowboat?
That's the surprise.
And that is no.
I have a...
You see, if we want a big crowd, we have...
- We have to call the killer to hear him, sir.
- No, but he isn't.
Now, my idea is...
- He isn't home.
- I mean, he isn't here.
The thing here is not to scribble about pennies.
- Oh, I agree with you, sir.
We send a little money on publicity.
We'll be able to...
How many do you find this conversation particularly interesting?
- Oh, no, no, no.
I mean...
- Oh, but if you want, Henry, he's in the kitchen.
- Thank you.
- The kitchen is the room with the refrigerator.
Good to you. All the time. Now if you don't mind. Oh sure. I'm going I would say it. And all of the
things. I'm going to. What are you doing here. What does it look like. Like a clean. That's what I'm
going to. For a home or guy can help his mother out without the force to do it. Can you're doing this
of your own free-roading humor.
And Homer, since I'm going to be busy.
Oh, don't mind me, madam.
I'll just sit here and watch.
Don't be just a wise guy, Homer.
Personally, there's nothing I like to see there
in a well-kept kitchen.
Listen, if you came over to scarf at me--
I don't see how you keep your kitchen so wide and clean.
Homer and your woodwork.
It's just spotless.
Homer, it may interest you to know
that the reason I'm helping my mother is on account of the park.
I find the scouring powder that's wonderful.
What powder?
The one we're having here tonight.
Tonight?
Here?
Don't want me to help you clean the stove here in old pal?
I don't know, my mother's pretty fussy about her stove.
Come on, here, I'm going to help. I'm a 12 stove cleaner.
Well, please hand me.
You've talked me into her.
Here, take the rag.
Just rest a little.
He pays him.
You're a pal.
All the way in back, Homer.
You'll have to get a little dirty.
Oh, that's all right.
I don't mind.
Oh, what kind of party are you having, Jim?
They're well parties, of course we're going to the country for the summer.
Have you invited many people?
Well, it's just going to be a small affair.
Well, exclusive time.
Now, get all the burners, Homer.
Oh, sure, he's sure.
Are all invitations out?
Oh, most of all.
Oh, but there are still some people you haven't asked.
Just one.
Here's some clean calls, Henry.
There I ask you to clean the soul.
It's been done, mother, by what you might call remote control.
- Well, I'm doing it, Mr. Holders.
- Why, goodness, Holders, I didn't see you under the stoke.
- I'm getting all the corn in.
- Thank you, dear.
- Tell me, I don't think it's very nice making Homer do your work.
- The mother was his own idea.
- That's no excuse.
- It really did go up Mary back in the hall, Rob.
He was mother do you want to have to this girl's work?
Well you could clean up the garage. That's man's work.
Well what I'm adding mine was more boys work.
Then there's the base of the guest mother. I'll help Mary.
I'm going right now.
Uh is there anything you want me to do Mrs. Hauler?
No thank you Hauler.
My goodness you got yourself all dirty from the stove.
How am I getting dirty?
After all it's not as though I was doing anything tonight.
You know, that's no.
Or if I was at another suit I could wear.
Oh, that's nice.
It's the suit I always wear to parties.
[LAUGHTER]
I'd like you to see it sometime.
Oh, I'd like to do it.
When?
[LAUGHTER]
Sorry.
It's fine, not tonight.
It's free having little parties here.
Mm-hmm.
I'm trying to love you.
Good.
Really expect you then.
Of course, I don't want to be in the way.
Not at all, my--
Maybe I'll be one to many for an exclusive party.
I'm trying to feel your tight welcome.
The last thing in the world I want to do is force myself.
Oh, but don't you want to come?
Am I giving you a question I didn't?
I don't see what mother says, Henry.
You are asked or you'll see, you'll see.
Children, not so nice.
Mother, when we say that, I have to say one to the party tonight.
Do I, mother?
Now, do I--
You're darn right, you do, Mary.
Mother's making me say it.
And tell me you stay out of this.
Mother, I'm supposed to go to the movies tonight.
It's coming.
If Mary goes so to why.
It's in.
What kind of a party is this?
Now Mary, you and Henry will both stay home.
After all, it's the last time you'll see Aunt Harriet all summer.
Is that the party?
This Aunt Harriet?
Yes, dear.
Oh, boy.
But Mother, I've been here at home and everything goes down.
And I see all of them as in that.
That's enough.
This time they thought it was your father's idea,
and I don't think he'd like the way you're both behaving.
Yes, Mother.
But Mother, it's a doubt.
Don't call him moving.
I don't care where I practice those.
You're saying no.
Mother!
Now come along, Mary.
Help me with the bedroom, please.
Mother, where are those?
I'm so tired.
Boy, if I'm known as a family party, I wouldn't have let your mother invite.
You mean your invite?
Yeah, and you can get some invite.
That's all I'm inviting.
See, you were a farmer.
What kind of attitude is that?
Listen, if I were an ovation, even in that way, I happened to have relatives of my own.
Mother, I'm not an opportunity to finish vacuuming the hall.
Boy, Mary, it's girls.
Oh, Mary, it's Gerald's work.
Mother said if you said that, you tell me the garage,
you should be--
I know, Mary, I know.
I suppose you know how to operate a vacuum cleaner.
Don't worry, Mary.
If there's one thing I know, it's had a maneuver of Hoover.
You take my work for it, eh?
This will be the biggest port of July celebration
the country club has ever had.
Father, no, I just heard you.
You already have, Mary.
What is it?
Mother would like you to move the living room
furniture when you have time so we can get out the rug.
I tell you mother I'm busy.
That's all I say.
I'm going anyway.
Well, goodness, Father.
I just gave you mother's message.
That's all.
Well, family, the ticket committee does a good job.
Everything will be fine.
And we'll just have to make it our individual business
to get as many people to come as we can.
Are you right, Sam?
Now, I won't keep you from the furniture.
I'll see you later.
And I'll ask you, bye.
Bye.
Mr. and I can show, Karen, you can do it by yourself.
Oh, hold on.
Yes, sir.
Do answer the question for me.
If this is the one about how you get down from an elephant's
back I've heard it no I'm a this is I do you get down from another side you know
you get it from the dark
think of it I've heard it home would you say that a six piece orchestra is large
enough for dancing I'm sure you're gonna have an orchestra of course we are
nothing but the best. I thought that is mr.
Polders said it was going to be a small thing.
I was just being modest.
Matter of fact, it's going to be one of the biggest affairs
center there has ever seen.
Even any sort of was going to be a small quiet gathering.
I think Henry is due for a surprise.
Oh, I get it.
And by the way, over, I want to see as many people
show up as possible.
I'd appreciate it if you would spread the word to anyone who doesn't know.
I sure will.
You can depend on me, Mr. Orley.
Good, oh my good.
Oh boy.
We're not even wanting to bring the ladder up there.
All right, don't forget all this.
Spread the water.
You bad, Mr. Orley.
Spread the word about what?
I can tell you, he needs to see good.
You and my father have a secret, sure.
And don't ask me what it is.
I'm on a bound not to tell.
Wild horse, you couldn't drag it from me.
OK, almost.
That's the way you feel.
I'm trying to explore all the whole things you knew.
Knew what?
If your father was going to...
I almost told you.
Okay, Homer, don't tell me. I don't want to know.
All right, here, look here and sit.
But remember, you forced it out of me.
What?
This party tonight.
You're in, Harry?
Yeah.
It's just a blind.
It is?
Sure.
It's really a surprise party for you.
For me?
Are you sure?
Sure.
Your father just told me, face to face.
And she will.
And it's gonna be a real big affair.
An orchestra and everything.
An orchestra?
Sure, and I'm supposed to invite anyone I can think of.
Boy, how's that?
I wonder why my father's getting a party for me.
It must be some reason.
Is it some special occasion?
None that I can think of.
I don't graduate till next year.
Maybe.
[audience laughter]
It isn't my birthday.
- Since I say... - What's it?
I bet it's because I passed in chemistry.
You think that might be it?
Sure, I got a fixie too.
That's the only thing that's happened lately that's worth celebrating.
Hey, me!
Oh, my gong, but my mother's suspect, I suspect anything.
Henry, will you help your father with a ladder?
I sure will, mother.
I don't know why the curtains have to be changed today.
Well, the house will look nice, thanks.
All right.
Come on, Henry, give me a hand with a ladder.
Do you mind if I get a glass of 8-2-0 first?
I beg your pardon.
That's chemistry for water.
It's also an excuse for not working. Come along, you know.
Yes.
Sometimes I think it'd be easy just to do everything myself.
Oh, Mrs. Alden. Yes?
I know all about it.
Oh, about what's here?
About the party tonight.
Oh, you're not the prize party.
What's the prize party?
Sure, you know.
No, I don't.
And I don't think you should have told me.
Oh, Mrs. Long, if you study,
you tell me I don't want to hear about it.
But you learn to find out.
When I do, it'll be time enough.
But wouldn't you like to know?
I mean, tell me.
Not another word.
Yes, ma'am.
Would you mind having Henry and Mr. Albright, tell me?
He is, my little.
I'll be glad.
Thank you, dear.
I'll ask my good friend to give me L2O2O.
Hello, is this the beauty stop?
This is Mrs. Albright.
Can I come in at two o'clock?
I couldn't wait that late.
There's a special reason.
My husband was giving a surprise party for me tonight.
Yes, I found out by accident.
You're a pager?
Oh, it's the anniversary of the day he proposed.
I knew it was the '20' age.
Oh, it was the '27.
Was it you?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(music)
Mother, is anything wrong?
Well, Mary, I have a cotton heart.
I don't know, you've been walking around with a funny look.
Come Mary, that's silly.
So most of those you know something?
I don't know something.
Another thing.
Hi, Mother.
Really, Mary, I don't know something like that.
Did you know anything? I didn't know.
I told you I don't know a thing.
I'll get it, Mother.
Thank you, dear.
Hello?
Hello, Mary.
This is Elaine.
Oh, hello, Elaine.
I just saw Homer Brown.
You do you?
Yes, you invited me to the party tonight.
Homer invited you?
That was by the authority of your father.
It's all right, isn't it?
Oh.
Oh, of course Elaine.
It's just that I didn't know about it.
Well, I wanted to know what to wear.
I thought that since your father was hiring, you know,
It was highly an orchestra and everything it might be formal.
Oh no, Elena. It's just a small family party.
But Norman said it was a surprise party.
It's nothing like that, Elena. It's just a...
a surprise party.
Mary, don't tell me you didn't know.
Why, I didn't.
Oh, you wouldn't get it yet, I am.
But, I mean, it never occurred to me that the party might be for you.
It is.
Isn't it?
Oh, I'm good. There's no wonder my mother was actually so mysterious.
Please, please don't let on a told you.
Oh, don't worry, I won't.
Mary, what's the reason for the party?
Oh, I can't see them, huh?
Yes, that's what it is.
My birthday.
Yes?
Happy birthday.
No.
No, it's your time.
But we'll be in the cut-scene then,
so they'll have to have it now.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, now you came to it?
- Well, no, it's my party, isn't it?
- But when it's a surprise party, I knew it.
It is an ethical invite people yourself.
- Homer, what have ethics got to do with gliders?
- Boy, and you should don't know girls.
Ethics is everything to them.
- It is?
- Okay, Homer, you call gliders.
(upbeat music)
Hello, Willy. Can you come to a surprise party for Henry tonight?
You're going to do a club practice?
We'll bring them along.
[CHEERING]
Madeline, like to drop over to my house tonight.
Oh, the lights may be out, but come in anyway.
[CHEERING]
Oh, yeah.
Yes, tonight, a wrong night.
You have to be a babysitter.
Look, why don't you bring the baby along?
[CHEERING]
Hello Lucy, this is Henry Aldrich.
Aldrich?
Yes, you may not remember me, but I used to sit behind you in third grade.
Yes!
Mary, I didn't expect to see you here, and I was happy to surprise you.
Oh, I don't know why we should be surprised.
I suppose it's the most normal thing in the world for a woman to go to a beauty college.
I don't know why I came to do to just as relevant tomorrow.
That's the way I see your mother.
Well, especially since I'm not going to have much done.
I think I've got a manicure and lazy a hair set.
Goodness, they say, "Yeah, do this today."
And I don't even have an appointment.
Neither do I.
I wonder if you lady could come back tomorrow with terribly rough.
Tomorrow?
But unless... I mean, I'd like to have it done today.
You told me over the phone you'd be able to squeeze me in.
I'm sorry, I don't know what happened, but everyone seems to be going to a party tonight.
- How am I sure, oldie? - Yes, Omar, what is it?
- Well, I've been spreading the word, like you said. - Good, Omar. I knew I could defend on you.
- George Bigel, a way to question. - What question, Omar?
He wants to know what flavor ice cream you're having.
All flavors and sandwiches and cold drinks.
Boy, I did not let it get around there. Everybody will want to come.
Well, that's just what I want, Homer.
You do?
Get as many people as you can.
All right, Mr. Olga, if you say so.
Goodbye.
Bye.
What do you say, Homer? What do you say?
Homer, don't you hear me?
Boy, you hear me? You're a father. I'm so excited to invite more people.
He does?
God, who would drink the chemistry was so important to my father.
(music)
That's right Ed, 38.
I just got a report from one of my agents.
And it's just the beginning.
We'll have more people at the country club this fourth of July than ever before.
All right, this is why I called Ed.
We'd better order more food.
You better double the order to the caterer.
Oh, no wait a minute.
The way things are going, you better triple it.
(music)
My goodness, my grandma, how much longer are you going to have to go?
I'll just about restain to my patients, Mary.
Are you going to leave, Mother?
I'll wait just one more hour.
Oh.
Oh, yes.
How much longer will it be?
Oh, I'm very sorry you had to wait.
Can you take a glance?
Which one of you want to be sample and set,
facial, manicure, fingerweight, and feather cut?
Yay!
Oh, well, I can only take one of you.
Which one will it be?
Namir.
Namir!
(upbeat music)
- Can I add him to you?
What you're worrying about,
your father said to invite as many people as I could.
- I know Homer, but 54 people.
How do you wanna cook them?
- How about the basement?
- I'm allowed for that.
They're just as in room and up in this house
for that many people.
- Well, I only did what your father told me.
- I know Homer, I know.
Look, here comes my mother.
- Why don't you ask?
- Okay, but you better be.
You're not supposed to know when it comes out.
All right, Homer, I'll be in my room.
Oh, my, wasn't Henry just here?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh, Mrs. Org, this is sure when I--
Oh, thank you, dear.
--just come from the beauty palace.
Mrs. Org, can I ask you something?
Who, Homer?
It's, um, about the surprise party tonight.
You think, Homer, I'd rather not hear about it.
And Mrs. Org, if you don't know what I'm gonna say.
And I don't want to know, dear.
But Homer, please.
Yes, Mrs. Org.
Mother, look at my hair.
It's just awful.
It looks very nice, Mary.
And besides, dear I did, you're yours.
I know, Mother.
Now I wish I had taken a sample one thing to wait
instead of the face.
Now I'll have to with your hair.
Dear, come upstairs.
All right, Mother.
I hope you can do something with it.
Mary.
Yeah, Mother.
What is it?
Can I ask you something?
That isn't Homer.
Well, you know the surprise party, Tenerys.
I do not.
What?
I don't know what's it happy about.
Listen, Mary, there's a party to me.
Oh, I'd rather not discuss it.
And I must say I'm surprised at you.
Oh, Mary.
Oh, Mary, I'm sorry.
Excuse me. Mother's waiting for me.
Mother, do you think I had a wash, my mamper?
Well, Omar, what's the latest figure?
It's, uh... 54.
But don't forget, you told me it's plenty.
Plenty.
Why?
Omar, I never realized before how talented you were when it seemed to spread it.
[laughter]
Or even a football.
Oh, there's plenty of room at the country club.
The country club.
The country club?
What's the matter?
Nothing, I had no idea you were going that way.
Well, isn't this cozy? Our own little family at our own table.
Yes, Sam. Yes, Father.
Well, what are we waiting for? Let's eat.
Since you think we better wait, dear?
It's still our own father.
And we might have, well, you know, company.
Oh, that's right. That's about all about it.
Oh, who?
There is that, Harriet.
And didn't you call her?
I thought you were.
My goodness.
It's too late now.
Alex, have you served dinner?
Oh, no, Father, not you.
Can we wait, Father?
Wait, what's all?
Sam, please. What's going on?
What's everybody all dressed up for?
Is this special there or something?
Now, Sam, please don't be kidding me.
Father, I hate this boy, I suppose, but I know.
You do.
And I suppose you know too, Henry.
Tell you the truth, Father, and I do.
I just want to say I consider myself well rewarded
for all the work I did in chemistry.
Fine.
Now, everybody knows but me.
What if it is just an ordinary day that's when he hates his deal
and I don't think I'll go right.
You do father and that's not playing game.
Just on you too.
It is.
This is a surprise party.
Father we know that.
You're also clever about it but my birthday isn't until next week.
But father.
And you're always saying how good you are today.
A surprise party for me.
Oh we before my birthday.
Well, better early than never, Sam.
I got to say, I'm really touched.
Thanks, you all.
Happy birthday, Father.
[LAUGHTER]
Thank you, Mary.
Dear Father, I hope you don't mind a present
with slightly second hand.
What?
I thought I'd give you the present I got to Uncle George
for Christmas, the BB gun.
So I can fire three times.
Thank you, Henry.
Feel free to use it anytime.
Father, you remember that book of Robert Brown in the past?
I got lost, please. Yes.
You said he was your favorite part.
He said he is.
When you take it as a birthday gift, I'll have a credit.
Yeah.
Thank you, Mary.
Borrow it whenever you like.
Sam, you know that package it came today
from the guest of Brothers Department store in Arlington?
Yes.
Please take it as a birthday present.
All right, what will I do with the ladies umbrella?
Stand where you take it and don't ask any questions.
All right.
Now, what about the birthday cake?
All I have is an apple pie.
Good.
I don't like cake anyway.
And why should I have to eat something?
I don't like a week before my birthday.
I'll get the pie.
Don't bother about it.
I'll get the vote.
Hello.
Mr. Allrich, where is everybody?
What's that, Omar?
I'm here at the country club with 96 people.
What?
Not including the police club.
In a baby.
A what?
[applause]
Boy, Homer, it's my whole family mad at you.
Oh, now wait a minute, Henry.
You and your surprise party, boy.
Listen, Henry, you heard your own father tell me.
Right on this whole home.
Well, my father was talking about
was the big Fourth of July party at the country club,
next week.
- This is Ezra Stone.
Now that I've stepped out of character,
I'd just like to say a word to all you folks in our audience
who've been friends and neighbors of the Aldridge family,
all these years.
Folks, we want you to know how much we'll really miss
our wonderful sponsor, the General Foods Corporation,
and our foster fathers, Howard Chapin and Ray Smith,
who have kept us in the world so well fed all these years.
But I guess most of all, we'll miss you.
We hope you'll miss us too, just a little bit.
Usually at the close of each show,
I've always bid you goodnight to the entire Aldridge family,
but tonight I think we should eat, speak for ourselves.
In the booth, NBC's finest.
Alice Young, Paul Knight, Bill Brinkmeyer,
and of course, our own Jack Miller and his fine orchestra.
Goodnight to Rita Bauer, Mary Aldridge.
- Goodnight everybody.
- And Catherine Ross, Alice Aldridge.
- House Jameson, Samuel Longbend.
- Good night, everybody.
- Of course, Jackie Kelk, Homer.
- And for me, as with Stone,
may you always be healthy, prosperous,
and appreciative of the folks who live next to you.
Good night, and good bye.
(audience applauding)
(dramatic music)
(buzzing)