[Music]
And now the Jell-O family presents...
Henry... Henry O'Rish!
Coming, Mother!
[Applause]
Yes, it's the Aldrich family based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith
and starring Ezra Stone as Henry with Jackie Kelka's horror.
And yes, it's the Jell-O family with its three famous desserts.
Jell-O in those six delicious flavors,
Jell-O puddings with that old-fashioned homemade flavor,
and Jell-O tapioca puddings,
a miracle of goodness, a marvel of speed.
♪ Everyone's a Jell-O good fellow ♪
♪ A very good Jell-O good fellow ♪
So rich, so tempting, and mellow!
J-E-L-L-O!
And now for the Aldridge family.
All the happenings in a typical day of a teenage boy can never be diagram.
There aren't enough zigzag lines for that.
You simply start a day with a boy like Henry Aldrich,
cross your fingers, and hope for the best.
The scene opens in the school cafeteria.
It is noon, partner.
Why don't you like Charlie Clark, Henry?
Well, I like him, Nancy. I like him.
But she was... I thought we were going to have lunch alone.
Well, I didn't invite him.
He just happened to ask who I was eating with, and I said, "Just Henry,
And my goodness, I couldn't be rude and tell me wasn't welcome.
I know, but...
Gee, was he ruins my appetite.
Henry, you've already had three sandwiches.
Sure, but I'm forcing myself.
Here you are, Nancy. Here's your milk.
Oh, thank you, Charlie.
Say, Hank, would you mind moving your chair a little?
What for?
Well, so I can slip mine in next to Nancy's.
Now listen, Charlie Clark.
But I just wanted her to take a bite of this sandwich.
It's made from a can of Patty de Foygras, my Uncle Harris, Senes.
Patty what?
Foy gras, Foy gras, G-Wiz.
French chopped liver, Henry.
Oh, Foy gras!
Boy, Charlie, do you speak a broken French?
Is that your Uncle Horace Clark who's in Congress?
Sure, and the mayor of a French village gave him six cans of this stuff
as a token of how his whole country felt toward my uncle.
Jean Nancy, did you ever hear a story like that near a life story?
Listen, Henry, have you ever heard of Lewis and Clark?
Who?
Lewis and Clark who practically discovered the rest of America.
Listen Charlie, you trying to make us believe that that Clark was your relative to?
Figure it out for yourself Henry.
Figure it out for yourself.
Hey Henry!
Oh gee whiz it's Willie.
Henry you have to get me out of a spot.
Willie, can't you see I'm having lunch with Nancy?
But all you have to do is tell Mr. Bradley I'm the wrong one to speak in assembly.
Willie, you're speaking in a family?
Nancy, I'm just as shocked as you are.
How did it happen?
I volunteered.
What? What?
How did I know they only paid outside speakers?
You expected to get paid?
Sure, and if you ask me, they've got no right to discriminate just because I'm a minor.
So Henry, wouldn't you be willing to point out to Mr. Bradley that every time I open my mouth, I make a fool of myself?
What makes you think he doesn't know already?
Well, I can't possibly talk to Mr. Bradley now.
But Henry, if you really have to help, well, I don't mind finishing up with Charlie.
What?
Sure, run along.
Oh no, how rude do you think I am?
But Henry, I can't memorize!
I'm sorry, Willie.
Say isn't Cynthia Harris related to Mr. Bradley?
I think so!
Hey, Cynthia!
Willie, I thought you hated the way she popped her gum.
I do, but right now I'm desperate.
Hi, Cynthia!
My goodness, poor Willie!
Speaking of memorizing, did I ever tell you about my uncle who had a photographic memory?
Listen, Charlie, who are you kidding?
Kidding?
Henry, did you ever hear of Socrates?
I suppose he was a Clark too.
No, but my uncle memorized his complete works at one sitting.
Ha! Gee Nancy, did you hear that?
Can we, if Charlie said he did, the least we can do is believe it.
That's okay, Nancy. He's just jealous.
Jealous? Listen, Charlie, it might interest you to know that there were just as many famous
aldridges in history as there were Clark.
Oh, yeah?
If not, famous-er.
Name one.
One?
Well, that's okay. That's okay.
They're there.
You want a bet?
Bet?
Afraid?
How much, Charlie?
How much?
$50.
$50?
You want to make it a million?
OK.
OK, why?
A million.
It's a deal, Che.
Che.
You're a witness, Nancy.
And I'll match my Uncle Horace against any old rich you
can dig up.
You're Uncle Horace.
My Uncle Horace.
Did you know he delivered one of the longest
filibusters on record?
My goodness, he did.
Well, all I can say is it certainly runs in the family.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, this was Henry.
Why, he went out right after dinner, Sam.
Yes.
He said there was something in the library he wanted to look up before they closed.
He went to the library?
Yes, dear.
Henry?
Yes.
My son.
Yes, Sam.
And incidentally, did I tell you I got a letter from your cousin Alan's boy Lionel?
Really?
Fine, and doing very well in his job.
And he asked for some pictures of us.
- Father!
- My goodness, Henry's back from the library fair.
- Probably getting used to it in small doses.
(audience laughing)
- And here, Henry.
- Boy, father, boy, you'd think they'd certainly
have a book that's more complete.
- Who, dear?
- The library mother.
Of famous people, the book they had
didn't mention a single Aldridge.
- Dear, we Aldridge has lived very quietly.
- Excuse me, Sam, I'm gonna drop a line to live.
Henry, what's this about famous orchards?
Well, he was.
Charlie Clark's been bragging about his darn family.
And father, I have to find a famous orchard,
or I'll lose my bet.
Henry, what have I told you about betting?
He was.
I couldn't admit in front of Nancy
that our entire family was nondescript, could I?
Henry, our family's hardly that.
Did you tell Charlie about your uncle John?
He did something?
Your uncle John won the milking championship
of the entire state.
He did.
Hands down.
But, gee, Father, Charlie's Uncle Horace is in Congress.
Weren't there any altages who were more outstanding?
- Why, of course, there were many.
- There were, oh boy, who, Father.
- Well, there was, there was,
- Yeah.
- Henry, it isn't important who your ancestors were,
it's who you are.
- Well, that's just it.
Who are we?
(audience laughs)
- Well, gee, there was,
there wasn't one of us worth talking about.
Let me tell you something, Henry. I don't know Nancy.
For all I know, she may be a very nice girl.
But if she's only interested in you because of your ancestors,
then I've looked at her again.
I have, Father.
Legafarden.
And she's one of the prettiest girls in the whole school.
And Father, would you mind moving your feet
so I could get at the encyclopedia?
Hey, Henry!
Boy, this is a fine time for Willie to show up.
Henry, if he's back selling second-hand Christmas cards,
I'm not interested.
You know what, Henry?
You know what, Cynthia Harris hasn't got a bit of influence
with Mr. Bradley.
- Willie, what's that on your tie?
- Bubble gum, Mr. Rawlidge.
I just stood too close to Cynthia when she popped.
(audience laughing)
So now I'm stuck with a charge of the light brigade.
- The charge of a light brigade?
- That's what I have to recite and assembly.
Here, Henry, hold the book while I see
how much of the first stands I've memorized.
- Willie, I can't, I'm going through Abba-to-Azo.
- What?
Abba-to-Azo, Abba-to-Azo, in the encyclopedia.
- Willie, don't you think you'd be happy
or if you memorized at home?
- I was doing that,
But my father decided the acoustics were better over here.
You don't say it.
Mr. Roberts, would you hold the book?
Oh, Willie, I'd be willing to pay it for it, Mr. Alberts.
I don't need money that badly.
I don't just take a second here.
The charge of the light brigade by Alfred Ward Tennyson.
Carefully, carefully, carefully onward.
How's that so far, Mr. Alberts?
It's perfect.
It is?
What comes next?
Boy, the Valley of--
Oh, boy, Father, I found one.
Cyrus, Aldridge, 1810 to 1875.
A well-known general in the Civil War.
In the Civil War?
Well.
Oh, boy, excuse me.
Where are you going, Henry?
To phone somebody.
Oh, in the Valley of-- what did you
say was the role of this?
Dead.
Number three.
Elm, 424.
Hey, Willie, could you bring that encyclopedia in here,
please?
But I'm tied up with your father.
I can spare you.
Hello?
Hello Nancy, this is Henry.
- Who? I can hardly hear you.
- Henry, Henry, who ordered?
- Oh, Henry, hold on a second while I see
what I can do about all the noise.
- Henry, here's your encyclopedia, thanks.
Well, what else does it say about Cyrus Aldrich?
- Cyrus Aldrich, 1810 to 1875, a well-known general
in the Civil War who gained notoriety
at the Battle of Crookers Creek
when he fell off his horse and missed the ferry.
- What?
(audience laughing)
From then on, he was laughingly referred to as the general who missed the boat.
[Laughter]
Henry, you really want to tell Nancy about that?
Hello.
Why?
Hello, Nancy.
I'd better go back.
I left your father right in the middle of the valley of death.
I couldn't hear you.
Charlie was playing the piano so loud.
Charlie was playing?
Yes.
A lovely song.
His aunt wrote.
Why did you want to tell me, Henry?
Right.
Well, Gee was, Nancy.
When you come right down to it, it's not a person's...
Well, it's not who a person's ancestors were.
It's who he is.
- What?
- Well, that is, I mean, well,
if you can take a person for a person,
we certainly ought to look at each other again.
- Well, my goodness, Henry Orridge,
I didn't make any bets about who the Orridge is.
Where are you there?
- Sure.
- And I'm certainly sorry you consider me that show.
- But, but Nancy.
- But Nancy.
She was.
- Henry dear, may I have that snapshot of you
on your dresser?
- My snapshot?
My mother, that's the one with my dog, Smoothing.
There, Smoothing ran away three years ago.
Sure, but suppose he comes back.
Well, how he feel he finds out I gave away my only picture of him.
Suppose I ask Lionel to send it back.
Send it back?
Is this Lionel reliable?
Henry, he's your own father's cousin's boy.
Mother, I've somehow lost confidence in our whole family.
Well, I think you can trust a man who works for the Royal Canadian Mounted.
The Royal Canadian Mounted?
Yes, for you.
Those guys and the red coats always bring back their man even if they die first.
And there's one in our family?
Yes.
Oh boy, will I get my hands on Charlie Clark?
What for?
What for mother? What for? Gee whiz, he owes me a million dollars.
[Music]
Agnes, wait!
Hi, Nancy, going in England.
Agnes, did you hear?
Did you hear?
Henry's cousin, Lion, Noah's coming to town.
Hey, yes.
The Aldrich has got a telegram that his vacation says
"We can be stopping by for a visit."
Oh, boy.
When's it coming?
Today!
Henry's meeting his train right after school.
Oh, boy.
I imagine having a guy in center bill who practically captured nearly six criminals dead or alive all by himself
He did I heard it from at least three different kids in school. Oh my goodness. Oh boy
I can't wait to see it hard. He's bringing it with him. They never go anywhere without their horses. Really?
They practically sleep together
I wonder how my big sister always will feel about that. She's even baking your cake with red and blue icing
What for?
To go with Lionel's uniform when he comes to dinner at our house tomorrow night.
He's coming to dinner.
My sister Eloise has been dying to meet him.
She hasn't had a date with a man in uniform since the war.
Invite me, Nancy.
Invite me.
Oh, I'd love to, Agnes.
But frankly, if I invited all the kids who wanted to meet Lionel, I'd have to hire a
banquet hall.
Hey, Agnes.
I have to go into class, Agnes.
Nancy, are you sure you couldn't squeeze me in providing I bring my own phone?
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- Agnes, would you hold this book for me?
- What for?
- Well, don't you realize the assemblies
that they have to tomorrow?
And I haven't memorized a single line except half-a-lee,
half-a-lee?
- Well, you know what they say, kid.
Half-a-lee, better than none.
(groans)
- Oh, boy.
- Agnes, this is no time for jokes.
- Look, Willie, you're a friend of Henry.
Can you fix it for me to meet his cousin?
- Agnes, I've got problems in my own.
- Oh boy, if that tobe Smith down there,
maybe he'll speak to Henry.
Hey, Toby, wait for me!
Oh boy, yes Mr. Bradley.
Were you calling someone?
What?
Yes sir, Toby Smith.
I see, and where is he?
At home?
You mean I was raising my voice.
Raising it is hardly an adequate description.
Please remember, this is the school.
Yes sir, I'll try not to lose my head in the future.
No, who you do?
And I'll run along.
Yes sir, it's been nice talking with you Mr. Brad.
The pleasure is all mine.
Mr. Brad, could I have a word with you?
Certainly, Willie, what about?
Well, I'm reciting an assembly, Friday.
See, you are?
Yes, sir.
Reciting?
Well, that's fine, Willie.
I'm sure it'll be an assembly we'll remember for a long time.
That's just it, Mr. Bradley.
I'd like to be excused.
Excused?
Well, isn't that what I don't want to,
but gee, was I have a head that nothing seems to stick into?
Yeah.
So couldn't we get someone else to take my place?
Who?
Why--
Why?
You know, other student is prepared and we don't have the money for outside speakers.
Oh boy!
I beg your pardon?
Oh boy, why didn't I think of him before?
Mr. Bradley, I've got just the person to take my place.
Henry, dear, please stand back from the track.
Yes, mother.
Father, are you sure this is Lionel's train?
I believe it is.
Be on the lookout for a man in a red jacket.
Sam, there's a red jacket.
Where? Where?
Down at the end of the platform.
Alice, that's a porter.
Oh.
Oh, man.
Who's calling?
My little fat man, the Derby.
Is he waving at us?
You can't be. I never saw him before in my life.
You're Mr. and Mrs. Oldridge, aren't you?
Why, yes.
I recognize you from your pictures.
Hello.
Cousin Sam? Cousin Alice?
I...
I'm Lionel.
You?
You...
Are?
Yes.
I guess this is Henry. I didn't recognize you without your dog.
Well, it's very nice to have you with us, Lionel.
Yes, yes. When did you leave them out?
Oh, I haven't left them. No.
Whatever gave you the idea I had.
But where's your uniform?
Henry.
I'm sorry, Henry, but I don't have one.
They only come up to size 38 and...
Well, I'm a 44.
Oh, boy.
Besides, nobody in our office wears one.
- Office.
- You working in office?
- Well, well, shall we be getting home, Sam?
I imagine Lionel would like to wash up.
- Yes, thanks I would, cousin Alice.
- Are the cars parked over this way, Lionel?
- Henry, aren't you coming?
- Mother, I have to phone Nancy Adams first.
- What for?
- Can I call off that dinner date?
- Henry Aldry.
- Mother, if Lionel's seen in public,
I'll be the laughingstock of the whole school.
- Henry, Henry, I must say you're not behaving at all well.
Henry, I got wonderful news for you.
- Well, out of my way, I have to make a phone call.
- But guess who I taught Mr. Bradley
in the letting take my place in the assembly tomorrow?
- Well, I don't have time to--
- But it's Lionel!
- I don't care who?
- Lionel!
Mr. Bradley said it was the best idea I've--
- Henry?
Henry, why are you staring at me like that?
Henry?
Mrs. Allridge, come back!
I think Henry's had him attack!
(dramatic music)
[Music]
And now while Henry is speechless, it's time for a few words from Meredith Wilson and his talking people.
Are we the intermission, Meredith?
The intermission? Well, yes, you might say so. We are the intermission and the high lariest adventures of the Aldrich family
family brought to you by the jello family
in the theaters during the mission of all you do you have the island
yet here
programs
yeah that's right
we like to do a little young too about the jello family of dessert i don't
blame you
you never tasted anything better
there's tell
the world's most famous shimmering dessert yes
and there's yellow pudding
like that means
move
That's right.
And it's jello tapioca pudding.
Full of personality and dimples and three wonderful flavors.
Yellow vanilla tapioca, jello chocolate, tapioca, yellow orange, coke, golden, that's it.
They taste all downright delicious.
You'll hurry to order Murray just to learn to dance with tapioca polka.
Yellow chocolate tapioca, yellow chocolate tapioca, yellow orange.
That means orange, coconut jello, the melodepioca,
jello chocolate, the pepioca, jello orange.
That means orange, coconut.
And now the jello family returns you to the Aldrich family.
[Music]
Yes, getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldridge.
Henry's second cousin Lionel of the Royal Canadian Mounted
has turned out to be a severe disappointment.
And to make matters worse,
Willie has volunteered Lionel's service as a speaker at Central High School.
It is the day of assembly. The scene opens outside the school's main office.
Willie, you'll just have to go into Mr. Bradley's office here and volunteer to recite your poem again.
But Henry told you, "Lionel steps on that stage, well, I'll be the laughing stock of the entire school."
Henry, things aren't that bad.
But you should see him, Willie. He's short, he's fat, and he doesn't have a uniform.
And he can't stay on a horse any better than General Cyrus Aldridge could.
Well sure.
And to top everything, do you know what he had for breakfast this morning?
What?
Cream pups?
No kidding.
Three of them.
Well, Henry, things aren't completely hopeless.
Maybe the assembly will be canceled.
Cancel?
Sure.
Remember the one that got called off last month?
What about it?
Wasn't it because the bell somehow didn't ring?
Well, well...
- Well, earlier, you suggest-- - Well, naturally not,
but you happen to be in the janitor's room,
and somehow your elbow happened to hit the switch
that worked the bells,
and they didn't happen to ring for assembly when--
- Will he for the last time,
will you recite the charge of the light brigade?
- You wanna definite answer?
- Yes, no.
(audience laughing)
- Once I get past the valley at death, where am I?
- Okay, okay.
If that's your attitude, I'll volunteer myself
in place of Lionel.
You to do what?
Play my cello.
Harry, you can.
Why not?
You're terrible.
Willie, I played it once before an assembly,
and nothing happened.
Step aside.
Oh, then.
Well, good luck, Ken, old time.
Oh, it's you, Henry.
Come here.
Yes, sir.
Henry, I've never seen Mr. Dutenbody so excited
about any assembly before.
Well, about that.
Are we your cousin, D, in his uniform?
No, sir.
He's a 44.
What?
He doesn't have one.
- But it really doesn't matter.
How would he like me to introduce him?
- Well, Mr. Bradley, about that, he's gonna be nervous.
He is a member of my own family, you might say.
- Yeah.
- Well, how would you feel if I...
Mr. Bradley, wouldn't you care to sit down
before I suggest this?
- Henry, it isn't necessary to explain.
- It isn't?
- No, if you think your cousin Lionel would feel more
comfortable if you were to introduce him.
- Introduce him.
Naturally I would mind.
Why?
Just be up on the stage before assembly begins
and we'll make the necessary arrangements.
But you see, I...
You know, Henry, for a moment I was afraid
you were going to suggest that I allow you
to play your cello again.
(upbeat music)
[APPLAUSE]
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
That was our own orchestra playing William Tell,
a number which Miss Wheeler tells me they've
been working on for some time.
I'm sure we all found their performance quite spirited,
especially in the brass section.
[LAUGHTER]
Now, in connection with the assembly bell ringing 15 minutes earlier today,
I regret to say it was no accident.
I just learned that two boys were seen running from the janitor's room immediately after it happened.
And when we discover who they are, I can assure you they will be severely punished.
Oh, I see our principal speaker hasn't arrived yet, so I'm sure we'll all enjoy hearing
months again from the orchestra Miss Wheeler.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Boy, Willie, boy, you and your idea.
Me?
Was it my fault that the bells went on instead of off
when you pulled the lever down?
Why, Willie.
Step out here in the hall.
Henry!
Oh boy, it's Nancy.
I've been looking all over for you, Henry.
Do you know who's sitting in the background?
- We wish I was.
- My sister, Ella, we just couldn't wait
to see what Lionel looks like.
- Oh boy.
- And you know what, she bought an honor
of this coming to dinner tomorrow?
A pair of shoes with sex and cheer.
- Nancy, do you think she ought to get her hopes up that high?
(audience laughing)
- Oh boy.
- Who's that?
- I'm sorry I'm late.
I was all over town looking for some things
I need for my talk.
(upbeat music)
Henry, have you heard from him yet?
Why, yes, Mr. Bradley.
I've heard from him.
Mr. Bradley, this is my cousin Lionel.
(audience laughs)
What?
Of the Royal Canadian Mountain.
Oh my goodness.
How do you do, sir?
Well, welcome to Central High.
Henry, suppose you go out and introduce Henry.
Well, whether you're suppose he disappeared too.
(upbeat music)
- Patrick, is that you?
- Yes, Father, it's I or I.
- Well, how did the assembly go?
- How did it go?
It went, Father.
(audience laughs)
As a matter of fact, I didn't even stay.
- Oh.
- And Father, Father, can I ask a big favor of you?
- Favorite?
I do. I want you to keep in mind that I intend to go to work and pay part of my tuition.
What tuition?
To Abbott City High.
Abbott City? What's wrong with Central High?
It's the kids, Father. I don't know.
Well, then, Gee, was it isn't who you are? It's who your ancestors were.
So you want to change?
Yes, I think it'd be better all the way around.
And, Ray. And don't you think you ought to be a little ashamed of yourself?
I followed.
You are feeling sorry for yourself because Lionel isn't something you pretended that
he was.
But tell me the truth Henry, have you ever met a nicer person than Lionel?
Why, no.
Of course you haven't.
He's just pleasant, well-mannered, and charming a person if you'd ever want to meet.
You should have every reason to be proud of him instead of feeling that you were betrayed.
Gee, Father.
Gee, I didn't look at it that way.
I didn't think you did.
Oh, please answer the phone, Henry.
And you know what about Abbott City High?
What?
I'm sorry I mentioned it.
Hello?
Hello Henry, this is Nancy.
Oh.
Before you start Nancy, let me tell you one thing.
If you're expecting an apology, you're wasting your time.
An apology for what?
You're right.
Boy, I've never met a more pleasant, a more...
She was who cares if he can't stay on a horse anyway.
Henry, I agree with you.
What?
I think Lionel is divine and so is my sister Eloise.
Whoa, Gee whiz.
She's even going down to buy a pair of flat heels.
That's how divine she thinks he is.
[LAUGHTER]
And you should have heard the hand the kids gave Lionel.
They gave him a hand?
Yes.
And Mr. Bradley said it was the most interesting assembly
talk he ever heard.
Nancy, what did Lionel talk about?
His work with the Rock and Hadeon Mountains
in the scientific crime detection bureau.
What?
Yes.
He showed us how he always gets his man without even
leaving his desk.
Will I be John?
And Charlie Clark certainly lost that bet.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Excuse me, Nancy. Will he just walked in?
All right. Don't forget dinner tomorrow night.
Yeah, I won't.
We're having saddle of lamb and Lionel's honor.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Nancy.
Will he? I'm in here.
Boy, Henry, boy. Darn that Lionel anyhow.
Oh, you haven't heard. Lionel was a big success in assembly.
I know he was I know he was I was there you were sure and he was such a big success
You know what he offered to do what come back tomorrow and give a practical demonstration
He's gonna track down a criminal by scientific method. No kidding boy. I sure like to see that
That's what you think you know who he's tracking now. No, the two guys who rang the assembly back
You certainly have one fine family
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hi, Willie, all kid.
Hi, Henry.
Hi, Agnes.
Hi.
Henry, guess what?
Your cousin line will come over to my house
Sunday night.
Bye.
For Agnes, what about our date for the B's you?
And next to well western, where the hero
chases the robbers over an entire mountain?
Set tires to most stuff.
From now on I'd like to see him copy easy way, like cousin Lionel does a sitting in a chair.
Bye!
Well ladies, you'll always catch him the easy way when you serve your family jello for dessert.
Yes, jello and any one of those six delicious flavors.
Strawberry, raspberry, cherry, orange, lemon or lime.
Every jello flavor is rich with that famous locked in goodness.
Flavor sealed right in by a special process, so it can't get out till your first delectable spoonful.
And that's why Jell-O is America's favorite gelatin dessert.
Look for those big red letters on the box.
They spell Jell-O and Jell-O spells a treat.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Here's hoping you'll be in your living room
and ours next week at this same time.
Good night, Homer, and good night, folks.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
The old rich family starring Ezra Stone
with Jackie Kelka's Homer is written by Norman Tokar
and Ed Joris with music by Jack Miller.
Mr. and Mrs. Aldrich are house Jameson and Catherine Roth.
And this is Dan Seymour in New York saying,
"The Aldrich family is brought to you by the Jello family."
♪♪♪
♪♪ Everyone's a Jello good fellow ♪♪
♪♪ A very good Jello good fellow ♪♪
So Rick's so tempting and now oh
J-E-L-O
Oh!
(applause)
Listen again next Thursday, same time, same station, to another sparkling half hour with the Oldridge family.
This is NBC, the National Broadcasting Company.
[MUSIC]