[Music]
Henry! Henry Aldrich!
Coming, mother!
The Aldrich family. A special rebroadcast for you soldiers, sailors and Marines of the United Nations.
[Music]
American boys always grow up. They can't stop themselves.
But no matter how important or how old they become,
they always like to grow down to boyhood again
and recapture their youth in the adventures of Henry Olridge.
The scene opens in the Olridge kitchen on a Saturday morning.
-Bye, Mother. So long. -Henry Olridge, where are you going?
No place, Mother. No place. Just skating.
Skating, dear. You're leaving without doing what I asked you to do.
-Who, I, Mother? -Henry, I told you I wanted you to take a package over to old Mrs. Proctor's before you did one thing today.
On the first day of skating, and the whole gang's going to be down on the lake, Mother?
I'm sorry, Henry, but you got to take this fruitcake over to Mrs. Proctor.
Even when Homer's waiting for me out on the front porch with a skates and everything.
Here's the cake, dear. It's in a tin and keep this side up.
She, weren't you listening, Mother?
Yes, dear. Now, please start.
Well, where are you going, Henry? Skating?
Skating, Father?
Wonderful day for it.
Now, Sam, I've just gotten through explaining to Henry it's going to be exactly as nice later on.
Father, you... Oh, you aren't finding a chance going to drive over by Mrs. Plochner's today, are you?
Oh, I know, sir. I have a very busy day scheduled.
Sam, you haven't forgotten you're going to that reception with me this afternoon, have you?
You know what reception Alice.
Sam I don't believe you ever hear one thing I say.
I've mentioned it at every meal for the last week.
To me?
Oh Henry.
Yes Homer I'm coming.
Henry you're tipping the fruit cake just as I knew you would.
Not very much Mother.
I just wanted to have it at the right angle as I went off the door.
Alice what reception are you talking about?
At the women's club at four o'clock.
At the women's club?
Yes dear and please go answer the telephone.
At four o'clock I can't possibly make it.
But Sam.
Hello?
Hello Sam this is Will Brown.
Oh yes, good morning Will.
Say Sam, is everything all fixed?
You mean for...
This afternoon?
That's right, Sam.
Well I'll tell you Will, I'm in sort of a jam here, I'm afraid.
Yeah, what's the trouble?
Could you call me again in just a few minutes and when Alice answers the phone,
you tell her how important our engagement is.
Why, Sam?
Well frankly, I forgot there was a reception at the Women's Club.
And she's going to make you go?
Not if you handle it right Will.
Oh, I see what you mean.
Yeah, I'll tell her it's a case of life and death that we get together for a conference.
That's right, Will, that'll do it.
Look Henry, look, the lake's just like glass.
Oh boy.
Well, be Henry, wait a second, where are you going?
I told you ten times, Homer, I've got to deliver this fruitcake.
But she was, I thought you were going out on the lake with me.
Oh no Homer, I walked a block out of my way so we could see how the ice looked.
And now I've got a gorbite Mrs. Proctor.
Henry, we're right here, aren't we?
Why don't we put on our skates and go down the lake once before the crowd gets here?
And now Homer, don't tempt me.
When I tell my mother, I'll...
I'll...
Although I'll admit I might step out here just one step to see how smooth it is.
She or Henry?
And why don't you put your skates on?
And no Homer, I'm just going to walk out of ways.
In the first place Mrs. Proctor is waiting for this fruitcake.
Gee, it isn't bad out here, is it?
No, Henry, and boy, watch me slide.
Look out Homer, stand back.
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna take just one long running slide
and then beat it over to Mrs. Prok.
Wait a second, I'll slide with you.
Homer, I can't wait. Here I go.
Wheee!
Hey, hey Homer!
Oh boy, Henry, look out!
Hey Henry!
What?
(dramatic music)
- Dallas!
Dallas, where are you?
- Come on, off the kitchen, Sam.
- The telephone's ringing.
- Yeah, you'll have to answer it.
- I can't, I've got to go downstairs
and look at the furnace.
- Sam, how do you know it isn't someone
who wants to speak to you?
Hello?
- Hello, is this M303?
- Yes?
- Oh, hello there, Alison.
How are you just fine is this wheel brown? Yes. Well, this is a pleasant surprise just a minute
Will and I'll call say I know Alice wait you don't have to call him you don't want to speak with him
I just want you to give him a message all right. I tell him something pretty important has come up and no matter
What he plans to do I've got to see him this afternoon really and what time well
For oh, but we hope he hasn't planned to do anything at four. There are some figures
I have to go over with him and and well, it's that important by naturally
that was my any chance. Well, problem. Yes, Sammy. Still on here. Don't you want to
speak to him? Oh, what? Oh, what's your calling for? He says you can't go to that
reception. No, he did take the phone. I've got to go back to the kitchen. Hello,
Will. Hello, Sam. I fixed it for you. You don't say well, Will, that's too bad.
Now listen, Sam. It's your turn to phone me. What do you mean? Call me back and do
the same thing with my wife. It's that reception, Sam. She hooked me.
All right, Will. You can depend on me. I'll give that by immediate attention.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Will. And thanks for calling. Alice.
Yes, Sam.
Alice, I'm certainly sorry about Will insisting I be with him this afternoon.
Just what kind of figure is it that you have to go over?
Why, they're rather intricate figures, Alice. In fact, they're...
Well, I've got to be going to the office.
Dear, you won't forget to stop off and leave those things at the tailor's, will you?
I won't. I've already got them out in the car.
Eh, is somebody in our back door there?
Hello Mrs. Aldrich.
Why, hello there, Homer.
I thought you were with Henry.
Who me?
Well, tell ya, I was with him and...
and then he asked me...
I decided to come over here for something.
Dear Henry, hasn't gone skating, has he?
Skating?
No.
No, Henry didn't even put his skates on.
Could I just step up to Henry's room for a second...
and sort of look around for something that I'd like to see whether I can find.
You want to go up to his room?
It's okay, boy. I want to call somebody at the back door here.
Oh, Charlie!
What did she say, Homer? Did you talk her into it?
Charlie! Say hello to Mrs. Aldrich. She's right here behind the door.
Oh, hello Mrs. Aldrich.
Good morning, Charlie. What did you want?
Why, well, I just... Well, you see, here's what happened.
I'm not mine, Charlie. Mrs. Aldrich is very busy baking, and we don't want to bother her.
Okay. Now don't make a mess up there boys.
Oh no.
Alice, exactly what is it I'm supposed to tell the tailor.
The same, everything in mind is to be dry clean.
Yes.
And Henry's soup and his two pairs of trousers are to be sponged and pressed.
Fine.
And tell him Henry would like at least his soup back by Monday because he hasn't a thing up in his closet except what he's wearing.
Very well.
Are you leaving now?
No, not just yet. I've got to put in one more phone call.
Mrs. Allbridge.
Yes, Homer.
Mrs. Allbridge, does Henry...
Does Henry still have the same room he's always had?
Why, yes, Homer, of course.
Is that right?
Why do you have?
No reason.
The closet.
The whole thing seemed a little empty.
Well, what is it you're looking for, dear?
Nothing, Mrs. Aldrich.
Oh, Charlie.
Homer, was Henry gonna meet you here?
Well, no, not exactly.
We were gonna come here and...
and then...
he'll probably be at the lake when I get back.
Hey, Homer, what's keeping you?
Listen, Charlie, did you find anything?
I found a sweater.
What could a sweater do?
What Henry needs is a pair of trousers.
Well, where are his trousers?
That's what I don't understand and listen Charlie you gotta let me take your pants over to him
Oh no Homer, but Charlie don't you realize Henry's over at the lake and only spent to keep him warm as a fire?
Come on now. Let me have no no Homer. Oh no. I'll take your pants
But Charlie don't you realize your pants are brown. They're the same color as Henry's all he's gotta do is put them on and nobody
11. No, we fell in well
But why don't you go over to your house and get in your brown pants because my mother's looking for me
And if I go anywhere near my house, I'm sunk.
Well, you can't have mine.
What, Charlie? You look tired.
You can get into Henry's bed and read a good book.
Oh, no.
Now listen, Charlie.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Agnes!
Hey, Agnes!
Oh, Henry!
Hi!
Why do you know you were down here at the light, Henry?
Come on out here and skate with me.
Wait, I tell you Agnes, I can't write this minute.
Why not? What are you doing behind that bush?
Why nothing? Have you seen Homer?
No, is he down here tonight?
Well, he was. Then he left to go on sort of an errand.
She was, have you seen Charlie Clark?
No.
Boy.
Oh my goodness, look at the hole in the eye.
What?
That's how I'm fishing here?
Fishing. Fishing.
Say, Henry, have you got a fire there?
Listen, Agnes, just stay away from here. Just stay away.
Why? Because, well, this is my fight.
Oh my goodness.
Oh, listen, do you see that house down at the end of the lake?
Yeah.
Well, could you run down there and ask to borrow a blanket?
Why can't you go?
Well, that's why I'm behind this board.
What?
An Agnes, while you're down there, ask if you could get anything I could fish with.
What's that?
Tell him I want to hook a fruitcake.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(
(Music)
Thanks a lot, Charlie.
And remember this, don't worry.
Now listen, Homer, how long are you gonna leave me here?
I'll be back with Henry before you know it.
Just stay in bed and enjoy that book.
Okay.
And don't call anybody.
And listen, Charlie, do you want me to pull down the shade in case you want to take a nap?
No, I don't.
Just stay away from that shade and bring my pants back.
Okay.
Oh, Mom!
Yes, Mrs. Aldrich.
Are you still up at Henry's room?
Wait, I was Mrs. Aldrich, but I'm not now.
I'm coming downstairs.
Should I pick you out of the kitchen, please?
Now...
I'll be there just as soon as I...
All I have to do is put something down here in the living room a second.
Very well, but please, Harry.
Yes, ma'am, I'm coming.
Here I am, Mrs. Aldrich.
Here, I'm terribly sorry, but I'm gonna have to ask you to run down to the store for me.
Now, Mrs. Aldrich, yes, dear.
The only thing is, I...
All you have to do is run in and ask for a can of baking powder and run right back here.
Yes, Mrs. Aldrich.
Only first I think I'll step in the living room in a minute.
Now, dear, please, I need the baking powder at once.
Right away, yes. Here, I'll open the back door for you.
Okay, Mrs. Aldrich, and I'll be right back.
Thank you, dear.
Homer, you don't have to run that fast.
- Aldrich. - Yes, Sam.
Are these brown trousers that Henry's supposed to go to the tailors, too?
- Where did you find those? - On a chair in the living room.
My goodness, I thought Henry was wearing his brown trousers.
Well, as long as you have them, you might as well tell the tailor to dry clean them.
They've been needing it for a long time.
[Music]
Hey, Henry, are you fishing?
Henry, are you?
Get away, I would stand back from this hole.
What's your fishing for, Henry?
Henry, can't you answer me?
Listen, now, would you want to fall through this ice?
You're too young to be around here.
I am not. I want to see what you're fishing for.
Oh, gee, we'll see that, Elwood.
If you hadn't been bowing, I would have had it.
Oh.
Now, just keep quiet.
You would have had Watt Henry.
What you got a blanket around you for?
There you go, Elwood. That's twice my darn fruitcake's gotten away from me.
You're done Watt Henry?
Listen, Elwood. Go on over the other side of the latency where the home of Brown's coming.
I can see from here, isn't it?
Henry, you gotta fly, you gotta fly!
I know, what do you think I'm blind?
Want me to help you Henry?
Listen, will you step back?
Oh boy, Henry, let me give you a hand!
Look out, Elwood!
Now listen, Elwood, there goes the fruit cake!
Gee whiz!
Hello?
Hello, Wilf and speaking?
Hello, Wil, this is Sam.
Oh, hello, Sam, where are you?
I'm at my office, Will, and I just phoned your house, see?
Yes? Did you fix everything?
Well, that's why I'm calling you. Your wife, Walt.
She bought?
She says it's Saturday afternoon, and you need to get away from your work, and she's taking you to that reception.
But, Sam, I've been calling on--
I know how you feel, Will. I don't blame you a bit.
Sam, you couldn't arrange to serve me a summons, could you?
A summons?
No, the courthouse is closed.
But I could send you a wire.
Say, that's an idea, and make it strong.
I know what I can say.
Good. And Sam, when you send it, don't send it here to my office. Send it to my home.
Then Elizabeth will be sure to open it.
I understand and don't worry well.
I won't. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Hello.
Hello. Can I speak with Mr. Sam who will Aldrich-
Mrs. Mr. Aldrich?
Oh.
Who is this speaking?
Why? This is Homer.
Oh?
Homer, don't turn them to Homer. I had breakfast at your house this morning.
Oh yes. Homer.
Mr. Aldrich, Mrs. Aldrich happened to mention that you took some clothes to the tailor when you left the house a little while ago.
Yes, what about them?
Well, why not pay there?
What's that?
I've just been over to the tailor, isn't he? Doesn't he know anything about?
Of course he doesn't. If Mrs. Aldrich is worried about them, tell her they're in my car and I'm going to take them in a few minutes.
Oh, well do you know where your car is?
You mean it's been stolen?
It has. With Charlie. With Charlie's?
Homer, I can see my car from my window here. It's parked right there on Main Street.
It is on Main Street.
Yes, of course. Right in front of the barbershop.
Oh, then I guess it is in stone.
Goodbye.
Oh, Gee whiz.
Now, wait a second, Terry Young fella.
Oh, boy. Are you speaking to me?
Is this your car?
Oh, yes, sir. No, sir. I'm just looking through it.
That's what I thought. What's your name?
My name?
You think I haven't been watching you? You even tried to get into the trunk?
Yes, sir. I'm looking for something.
Yeah?
Look, a friend of mine dropped a fruitcake, see?
I mean, first I borrowed another guy's pants, see?
And this is his car?
Yes, sir. No, sir. It's Mr. Olwich's car.
Good for Olwich's?
Yes, sir. It was his wife who baked the fruitcake.
Oh, so it's a fruitcake you're looking for?
Yes, sir.
No, sir.
He's taking it to the cleaners, see?
Now, wait a minute. What's your name?
Don't you understand? Charlie's pants.
They're holding everything up.
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Olridge.
Henry, while supposedly delivering a fruitcake for his mother,
has fallen through the ice on the lake.
Now, while he's waiting for someone to bring him a pair of dry trousers,
the scene opens with Homer returning to Charlie,
whose trousers he had borrowed.
Charlie?
Hey, Charlie, wake up.
Now listen, Homer, where are my pants?
That's so loud, Charlie. Do you want Mrs. Olridge to hear you?
Mrs. Olridge isn't here.
I heard her go out.
Who is here?
Nobody's here.
I've been alone here all day.
What do you mean all day? It's hardly three o'clock.
Well, I haven't had any lunch.
And I want my pants.
Oh, that's what I came over to tell you about, Charlie.
Where are they?
They're being cleaned.
They think.
They're what?
Well, the cleaning promised me definitely it had been back on Monday.
I've got to stay here until then without anything to eat.
Oh no!
Charlie, take your hands off me.
No, I won't. I'm going to get out of here.
How?
I'm going to take your pants.
Now watch out!
Quick, Charlie.
Hey, Charlie, get off me.
No I won't! Don't let go of my ears!
Let go of my pants!
Well hold your foot up!
You make me!
Now listen Charlie, stop dragging me across the floor!
Let go!
Let go of yourself!
Oh boy!
Now look what you've done! You tore my pants right in two!
Why didn't you let go of them?
Well this is a swell thing to do, a guy! Look at me!
Can't we solve them back together?
Sure, sure! How are we gonna sew them together?
I've got one leg on and you've got the other in your hands!
Sam, I certainly want to thank you for fixing everything up with Elizabeth.
No trouble at all, Will.
Well, she got that telegraph.
Now, wait a minute, Sam.
I've struggled.
Let's go this way instead.
Let's hurry too.
Only you see, Will.
I think that was your wipe up the street.
Alice?
You must be on the way to that reception.
Nothing to worry about, Sam, she didn't see us.
Hello there, Mr. O.
What's that?
It's Agnes Lawton.
Hello.
Oh yes, hello there.
Where are you going?
It's not your ride.
I'm going home to get something for...
for...
boy, am I in a hurry?
[Music]
Boy.
Boy of all...
Listen Homer, get off that bed.
It's my turn to lie down for a while.
What's wrong with that chair you're sitting on?
It's hard, but I'm tired.
Well, I'll tell you one thing.
The next time I do something to try to help you out, Charlie,
don't think you know more than anybody else that ever lived.
Hey, is anybody in there?
She whiz, who's that?
So much, fellas, is it all right to come in?
Oh, hello, Elwood.
Where'd you come from?
Listen, Henry wants to know where you are.
Does Henry want to see me?
Sure, Homer.
What's your line now, Cory?
You're sick?
I'm getting up.
Say.
Come here a minute, Elwood.
Come here a minute.
What for? I just want to see something.
Listen Homer, you've got to need pants on.
Well they're better than nothing.
What do you mean by that home?
And nothing else with nothing. Just come here to Homer.
What for?
Elwood, I'm not gonna hit you.
Come here. Come here.
Henry!
I'll be there in just a second, Agnes.
Do they fit you, Henry?
Well, they cover me.
But don't come near this bush again.
I'm not coming near it.
They fit me.
But just how big is your father?
Well, he has to be centered on the air football team.
He did?
Yes, but he's put on a little waist since then.
There.
Now I guess I have them on all right.
My goodness!
What's the matter?
You're just a sight!
Boy!
Hey, Henry!
She was-- who's that?
Here they are, Henry.
Here they are.
Listen, Homer, where have you been?
I've been trying to get to these pants, and boy.
Here, put them on.
Homer, I've got a pair of pants on.
You have? Are those pants?
Sure, they're Agnes's fathers.
Agnes's who?
My father.
Oh, well, Henry, don't you want Elwood's?
Elwood? How'd you get Elwood?
I just borrowed them.
And then went over to Charlie's and got a pair for myself.
And here are yours.
Homer, I certainly hope you don't think I want to wear neat pants, do you?
Well, why shouldn't you?
I would, I'm right out in public, all the way over to Charlie's house.
Henry, isn't that your father over there?
Where, Agnes? Where's my father?
Right out there on the lake. Look at him, scaring.
Oh boy, stand in front of me.
She was, is that my father, with him?
Yes, sure.
They certainly are doing some fancy figure skating.
Homer, won't you please stand in front of me?
No!
Agnes, what's the matter?
No, Mr. Overt, you just fell in.
He did?
My father fell in.
Oh boy, him, you old boy.
Look out.
Homer, where you going?
Where do you think to your father I'm
going to take a Melwood's pants?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
- Can you see through the window, Will?
- Yes, I'm looking.
- It's all right to go in, is the coast clear?
- Come on, Sam, your wife isn't in the front of the house
anyway.
- Are you sure?
- Alice, Alice Aldrich!
- Will, don't do that!
It's alright. If you don't look so bad in those pants, Sam, they just look like a skating costume.
Just the same, well, I don't want her to see me. Look, I'm going upstairs to take a hot bath.
Okay, and as a matter of fact, I think I'll be pulling out.
Sam!
Will, is that Alice?
Goodbye, Sam!
Yes, Alice?
Was that you that just came in the front door?
Well, yes. Yes, that was I.
Well, come on out here to the kitchen a minute.
Well, I can't right now, Alice.
Sam, I want you to come out here and help me with something.
I'm coming with something.
Very well. I'm coming.
Did you see Harry?
Yes, Alice. I'm right here on the other side of the door.
Why don't you come all the way in?
Well, I would, Alice. Only I was afraid I'd bother you.
Sam, I'm peeling these onions and I can't see a thing.
Step over to the range. Will you please and see whether I turn that back burner off?
Now, Alice?
Yes, dear, of course now. Did you get all your figuring done?
Why, we went over a few figures.
And then something else came up. But that is, yes, you might say we got them done.
Goodness, but these onions make my eyes water.
You mean you can't see anything Alice? Not anything at all?
No dear, where are you?
I'm sort of around here behind you.
Well, I suppose I'll have to keep on peeling these or I'll never get them done.
And incidentally Henry is upstairs.
He's upstairs?
Yes, he came in just a few minutes ago and he's taking a hot bath.
Well, that's fine.
And after dinner Sam, I want you to have a talk with him.
Yeah?
He started off this morning to deliver a fruitcake
and he distinctly disobeyed me and went skating and fell in the lake.
Er... yeah?
Sam, you don't seem a bit concerned.
Oh, I am too concerned, Alice.
I was just going to say "falling" in the lake.
I also wish you'd have a talk with Henry about Homer.
About Homer?
Yes, Sam.
Elwood Hazard's mother phoned a little while ago and said that Homer had knocked Elwood down today.
Stolen his trousers from him and locked him up in some room someplace.
What did he do that for?
I don't know.
And now Mrs. Hazard is going out all around town trying to find the poor boy's pants.
Elwood Hazard?
Sam and he's only a little fellow in knee pants.
Hmm.
Well, that's how I think I'll be going upstairs and get dressed.
Don't be like Virginia Sam.
You will stick to Henry, won't you?
Yes, Alice.
And if this is hazard bones again about Elwood's pants, tell her not to worry.
I'll try to get to the bottom of them.
[Music]
Henry, did you take part of this morning's paper?
- Why, Mother? - Yes, dear. There was a picture in it of some man who fell into the lake yesterday.
And it was the funniest thing it looked exactly like your father.
- It's our ride! - Yes, dear, and I wanted to show it to him.
You know where it is?
Well, to tell the truth, Mother, Father and I were lighting a fire in the living room a little while ago and I guess we must have burned it!
This rebroadcast of the Aldrich family is a presentation of the Armed Forces radio service.
(upbeat music)