[MUSIC PLAYING]
Henry, Henry Oldridge.
Combing mother.
[APPLAUSE]
Yes, it's the August family written by Clifford Goldsmith.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
There's an old saying that claims you're only young once.
But as a matter of fact, you can be young more than once, and the best way of doing that is
to share the misadventures of a typical boy like Henry Aldrich.
He'll take you right back to your own teenage days.
The scene is the living room of Nancy Adams, one of Henry's favorite classmates, and the
Time is evening.
Nancy, tell me honestly.
What is it you like about Bill Turner?
I don't know, Henry.
I just like him, don't you?
Well, sure he's all right.
If you like athletes.
What's the matter with athletes?
Nothing.
Except you're so athletic.
I mean, well, to hear Bill Turner talk,
you think he was Joe DiMaggio, the Notre Dame football
team in gorgeous George.
All rolled into one.
That's so loud, Henry.
He might hear you.
Who do you hear me?
He's out in the front hall.
I like them only.
Frankly, is there any way of getting rid of them?
- You're eating your dog like him?
- Well, sure, I'm crazy about him only.
- Hey, Nancy.
She whiz.
- Nancy, did I ever tell you about the time
I dove off the top of the boat house?
- Oh, Bill, I didn't even know anybody could climb up that high.
- Oh, it's easy.
And you know that flagpole down at the end of the lake?
- Yes.
- I dove off that once, too.
- Nancy, how's your mother?
- Oh, she's better, Henry.
She just strained her back a little.
- Boy, was that some luck I had in the game Saturday.
You remember when those three guys tackled me
and I carried them right across the gold for a touchdown?
Oh, that was just wonderful, Bill.
I don't see how you stood up.
Nancy, what kind of a television set is this?
I don't know.
Hey, Henry, could you or Bill open this window
a little, please?
Sure, why not?
Oh, wait a minute, Henry.
I'll open it.
Well, that's all right, Bill.
I've got it practically--
practically.
Is it stuck, Henry?
No, it isn't stuck.
I just--
[GRUNTING]
Could you stand back, please, Bill?
How am I in the way?
I want to get some leverage.
- Here, Henry, let me show you how to open it.
- Now look, Alpil, all I have to do is...
(clears throat)
Nancy, would you mind if I pushed this sofa away?
- No, Henry.
- Well, don't get off, I'll push you along.
- Along.
(audience laughs)
- Well, maybe if you just got up for a second, Nancy.
Never mind this sofa, I'll just...
She was who opened that window.
- I did.
(audience laughs)
You know, I thought I had it started,
I just should have kept at it.
Anything else you want done, Nancy?
Well, there's some ginger ale out in the kitchen
if one of you wants to--
But you as I'll get it for you, Nancy, you stay where you are, Bill.
You're sure you don't need any help lifting the bottles?
You'll find everything out there on a tray, Henry.
All you have to do is put some ice in the glasses.
I'll be right back.
Nancy, isn't there any way of getting rid of him?
This evening?
Sure.
Bill, Henry Aldrich is one of the nicest--
Nancy, I'm not saying he isn't.
Only, frankly--
Frankly, what?
Well, three's a crowd.
And frankly, I have crowds cheering for me every time
I go out on the field.
I want to be alone.
Excuse me, Nancy.
But is there any special way of getting your ice trays loose?
Well, my mother never has any trouble, Henry.
All she does is pull and they come right out.
That's funny.
I'll take another crack at it.
Nice guy.
I'd like to see him come out for football practice
some afternoon.
Bill, what did I tell you about sympathy and understanding?
Oh, I understand, Henry.
That's why I have no sympathy for her.
I don't forget about him.
What about that dance Friday night?
What about it?
Well, what time should I--
[LAUGHTER]
What time should I--
You know, he's going to wreck your refrigerator.
What time should I call for you?
Oh, about that.
[THUNDER]
[LAUGHTER]
Just an answer.
Yes, mother?
- All those boys playing football down there.
- No, Mother Henry's getting some ice.
- I'll pick everything up, Nancy.
- Does your father have a hammer I could use
with this screwdriver or a small crowbar
would be even better?
- Henry, what's that all over your suit?
- It's, well you see, I was aiming for the ice cubes,
but was your mother planning to have
tomato juice for dinner?
(audience laughing)
- Why?
- There's a freshly opened can in the ice box.
- Oh my goodness.
- Of course if they're going out for dinner,
it'll keep the tomorrow's lunch.
- I'm out of the way, Henry, I'll get the ice out.
- Now wait a second, Bill, you'll need something
to loosen it with.
- What's the matter with my hands?
- Some guy sure loved a brag.
- Why a bill turner?
- Whoa!
Hey, who could put her on the floor?
- I'm here!
- Just took it out so I could get better leverage.
- Nancy, will one tray of ice be enough?
- She did, I loosen it that much?
- Nancy, I don't think you'll feel the same way about
you know who, once you get a look at your mother's kitchen.
- I think I better be going.
Oh, Henry, do you have to?
Well, I've got a lot of homework to do,
and I think I better.
Don't you?
Well, if you have to.
I, I, I had a very swell evening, though.
Oh, I'm awfully glad, Henry.
Well, so long.
You really have to go.
I think I better.
Oh, but would your mind closing that door
that coach told me to keep out of draft?
Oh, oh, sure.
I didn't realize I was keeping the door open.
What time should I call for you Friday evening?
Friday evening?
Sure for the dance.
Henry, I didn't promise to go with you, did I?
Why sure, why sure?
You didn't?
I don't see how I could have.
I'm going with Bill.
Oh.
With Bill?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry, Henry.
I guess you must have misunderstood it.
Hey, what about that door?
I'll walk you after the porch.
No, no, you go back and have your ginger ale.
I can find my way, all right.
Boy, I hope you understand, Henry.
Oh, sure.
You and Bill just go ahead and enjoy yourselves.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[Music]
Sam, could you pass the toast please?
Hey, you are, dear.
Why didn't Henry go to the dance?
Well, dear, that's what I don't know.
Do you remember the other evening when he came home from Nancy Adams soaking wet?
When?
Last week, dear, a couple of nights before the dance.
He walked into the house covered with tomato juice.
And Sam, Henry hasn't been himself since then.
Did you have a talk with him?
Yes, and all he'd say was he felt dancing was a waste of time.
Mother!
And Mary come in here and eat your breakfast.
Mother, what's this letter all about?
What letter?
Why is the silliest thing I've ever seen?
It must be for Father.
May I see it, please?
Who's it from, Sam?
From the Lionel Strong Ford Institute of Physical Development Incorporated.
Dear Mr. Olrich, are you a man or a mouse?
I knew all the time it wasn't for me.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
No man can make his mark in the world.
No man can inspire the love of a good woman unless he is willing to develop his inner potential
strength in our 26-week course.
Sam, what in the world is that?
I don't know, Alice, but I'm fascinated.
We can give you a money-back guarantee if your chest expansion does not increase by
at least two inches during the first six lesson.
How many inches, darling?
You quiet Mary, that's just the first six lessons.
We also offer a shorter course for the busy executive, interested in only partial development.
Remember, decide now, yours Julie.
Father, what's that?
P.S. replied by return mail and received free, one genuine simulated nylon tape measure, especially desired, for checking your chest development.
Dear, when did you write for that?
May I see the envelope please?
- Father, it's addressed to Mr. Harold Olrich.
Who's he?
- I have no idea whether he's a man or a mouse.
- Well, he put the letter back in the envelope, please.
It's probably for Henry.
- Mother, why would he want to develop?
- I don't know, dear.
And besides, it's none of our business.
Please put it back in the envelope.
- Well, I think I'll walk to the office this morning.
- What time you haven't walked to the office in six years?
- Well, of course I have.
I walked a couple of times just this last summer.
It made me feel great.
I'll get you top coat for you, Father.
My coat?
The coat?
Why would I want a coat?
Well, I can at least get your hair.
Goodbye, Alice.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, son.
Mother, do you have any idea where my blue and white tie is?
You're a blue and white tie?
No, dear.
And sit down on each of your brackets.
But, Mother, I've got to find it.
There'll be plenty of time to find it after you've eaten.
Turn around.
What's the matter?
I think you want to have those shoulders on that coat taken in a little.
Taken in, Mother?
You just want to throw your money away?
They'll be filled out in 26--
I mean, before you know it.
Henry, dear, please sit down.
I want to ask you something.
What about?
What in the world is the trouble?
The trouble?
Gee, I don't know of any trouble.
But you want yourself, dear.
And when anyone speaks to you, you're way up in the air.
When I'm up in the air, mother, I may be a little upset
because I can't find my blue and white tie.
But otherwise, I feel fine.
Then why not eat your breakfast?
I'm going to eat it.
How's Nancy Adams these days?
Nancy Adams?
Mother.
Oh, I asked this.
How is she?
You see this book here, Mother?
You see this book?
Yes.
Well, that gives you an idea of what little interest
I have in Nancy Adams.
What about the book?
I borrowed it from her two weeks ago.
Well--
I'm returning.
Well, that's fine.
I'm returning it.
That's all.
That's as far as I go.
She asked me whether I'd like to keep it and finish it.
I'll tell her I'm not even slightly interested.
Well, that's fine.
Do you not drink your milk?
You know what else?
What?
That's all right.
Never mind.
But if her folks can't afford a better ice box
The one they have, she was, do you like Bill Turner?
Bill Turner, I hardly know him.
She is, he got a lot to learn.
He just goes around, you know what he thinks.
Henry, what's your ambition in life?
My ambition, Mary, what do you mean?
That's all.
I just wondered whether you wanted to be a man or a mouse.
Mary, I haven't any time for small talk.
Have you seen my blue and white tie?
No, but I'd love to see your chest expansion.
Not Mary.
That's what I say, Mother.
But, Mother, all I was going to ask him
was if he was going to take the short course of the 26-week course.
Mary, will you please give Henry that letter?
A letter?
I don't think it's for you, though, Henry.
Mary, give me that letter.
Are you, Mr. Harold, Aldrich?
Mary, you come back with that.
Do you realize that United States may help?
Mary?
Mother, it says right on the envelope.
Maybe open for inspection.
Mary, if you don't give me that--
[LAUGHTER]
Oh, we won't break anything.
I'm just helping Henry develop.
Now, listen, Mary, you're only going to make me late for school.
- Do you wanna take it with you and show it to Nancy Adams?
- Mary, if you breathe one word about this to her out,
Mary, Mary, come back down here with that.
(upbeat music)
- What are you writing, Henry?
- Henry, what are you doing?
- Homer, is there a class in this room next period?
- Sure.
Henry, what are all those questions you're filling out?
Nothing Homer, nothing important.
It's just some information I've got to send away.
Could you measure my chest just once more please?
It's pretty hard with this ruler.
Well,
(audience laughing)
well, just go around me real slow.
It's exactly two and a quarter.
Two and a quarter?
Two and a quarter rulers.
That's 27 inches.
27 inches for my chest.
Don't you think I better take off a half inch
for where I went around the corner?
(audience laughing)
The only thing is Homer, my thigh was 27, too.
You mean my thigh is as big as my chest?
It is.
Boy, Homer, I don't want to mislead anyone.
Listen, Henry, what is it you're sending for?
Nothing, Homer.
Gee, what is, why would I...
Do you know whether Nancy Adams has a class
in her next period?
Sure.
I thought you were ignoring her.
Oh, yeah, that's why I'm waiting to return this book.
When I hand it to her, it's going to end everything.
Let me see that letter, just for a second.
Will you, Henry?
Homer, don't you see what's printed right at the top of it?
Strictly confidential.
What is that question at the bottom mean?
What question?
Do you have flat feet?
(audience laughing)
Now listen, Homer, that just shows
how your imagination works.
Well, what did it say then?
Keep quiet, Homer.
Ms. Watson just came into the room.
Ms. Watson?
Well, boys, you certainly look busy.
We are, Ms. Watson.
You working on your biology?
Well, you know, what do we are?
Now isn't that fine?
You know we're going to start working on mice next week.
We are?
On mice?
Yes, we're going to compare their development
without a man.
What's that?
Come on, Henry.
That's the end of the period.
There's a class coming in.
Hello, Henry.
What are you doing in here?
Well, well, and, Nancy, I've been waiting--
I've been filling out--
I've been--
Henry, you're getting ink all over yourself.
I am.
Here's a blotter.
Well Nancy, I just wanted to tell you how much I enjoyed this book.
Oh, I'm awfully glad you were turned at Henry, because Bill Turner is anxious to get it.
He is?
Are you sure you're through with it?
Oh yeah.
After all, even if I weren't through with it, naturally a Bill wants the book.
Where have you been for the last week?
Just around.
Just around every place.
Hey Henry, come on!
You go ahead Homer.
I may be held up here a second.
Quietly.
Oh you better go Henry.
I just wanted to tell you though how much I enjoyed your book.
Henry Aldrich.
Don't you have a class this period?
Yes, Ms. Watson. I'm on my way right this minute.
Goodbye, Henry.
Goodbye.
Boy, is Nancy a good-looking girl, Henry.
Do you think she's so good-looking? I think she's terrific.
Well, the way I think of her, she's good-looking, but I wouldn't ever want to...
Henry, let me have a look at that letter, will you?
What letter?
About your flat feet.
Now Homer, listen.
Homer, who is that letter?
I haven't got it.
I put it in this Latin book.
I put it right here in the Appleton of Absolutes section.
Well, don't look at me.
I didn't even touch your letter.
Do you suppose I put it in Nancy's book?
You did.
Well, why would she be interested in your flat feet?
Oh, I didn't know I put them there.
I mean, the letter there.
I was just talking to her, and I may have just stuck it in there.
Well, Homer, I've got to get that letter.
Why?
I think I want a thing like that to be read publicly by Nancy.
Well, you certainly can't get it now, Henry.
Maybe they haven't started class yet.
Well, I'm not going in with you.
I don't want the whole class to look at me, you quiet, Homer.
going back in and get that letter.
Will you all get your pencils, please?
I bet your part in Henry Always is there
something we can do for you?
Why, if Miss Watson, I'm starting to interrupt your lesson
like this, but I just returned Nancy to a book.
[LAUGHTER]
I mean, the Nancy's desk has something in it
I'd like to want.
I mean, me.
Well, is it anything you can't do without for the rest
of the period?
Well, yes.
Am I just have to have it?
Well, if it won't take more than a second,
you may go to a desk and get it.
Thank you, Ms. Watson.
In the meantime, when all of you be copying,
what's written on the board here?
[LAUGHTER]
It's like, by the way.
Nancy.
Henry, what on earth is it you want?
I'd like to borrow that book again.
But Henry, it didn't have to come all the way back
into class and embarrass me.
But I just happened to remember.
I haven't finished it.
I thought you said you had finished it.
All the giants, like I don't know all.
Henry, will you hurry, please?
Yes, Ms. Watson.
You're Henry.
Thanks very much.
Henry, may I ask what book that is?
This book I just got from Nancy?
Yes.
Well, it's just a book.
What is the title?
Rita's Revenge.
[LAUGHTER]
And that is the book you were in so much of a hurry to get.
Well, I'll tell you, it isn't a story I'm so anxious to get.
Yeah, I have a book, please.
The whole book?
The whole book.
Wouldn't I take just one look?
Please don't open it.
No?
- May I have it please?
- Yes, Ms. Watson.
- And I should like to see Nancy Adams
immediately after class.
- But Ms. Watson, will you please leave this classroom?
- Yes, Ms. Watson.
I'll go.
(audience laughing)
(upbeat music)
- Welcome back to the Aldridge family in just a moment.
Sundays on this station are really full of top radio shows,
but I'd like to tell you about just one of them,
"Theta Guild on the Air."
For seven seasons, "The Theta Guild"
has been bringing you the brightest stars
of Broadway and Hollywood and some of the world's
greatest plays.
Tonight, the comedy attraction is Ring Lardner's
baseball story, "Elmer the Great."
Your stars are Eddie Bracken and Wanda Hendricks.
Now, the play concerns Elma Kane, a pitcher
with the best right arm and the three-eye league,
but a brain which has failed to vibrate
with a clear thought since birth.
Now Elmer refuses to leave Gentry Villalenoy
for the big league because he's in love with Nelly Poole,
owner of the grocery where he drives the delivery wagon.
But Nelly guesses his secret and fires Elmer.
Well, from then on, it's all ring-lard and a fun.
So check your newspaper for broadcast times
and tune to NBC tonight for "Theta Guild on the Air."
You'll enjoy Elmer the Great.
(upbeat music)
[Music]
And now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich.
Henry has decided that he needs a course in physical development.
And after filling out the rather intimate questions on the application blank,
he discovers that he has left the blank in a book belonging to Nancy Adams.
The scene opens in Henry's school at the close of a period.
Listen, Henry, this will make two classes I've missed just because of you.
All you have to do is just walk up to Miss Watson's desk there,
pick up Nancy's book, and walk out with it.
It's as easy as pie.
Are you sure Miss Watson isn't in there?
No one's in there. There isn't a soul in there now.
You like pie? Why don't you go in and get it?
Well, she was Homer. I was going to stand here in the door,
and people watch for you.
Well, if anyone does come along, Henry, give me a signal.
Clear your throat.
Sure, I'll sort of cough.
Okay, I'll go.
That's it.
That's it. Just walk right up as though you own the place.
Which book is it? The one your hand is on.
This isn't it. Sure it is. Isn't that book blue?
Sure, but it's the advanced essence of poetry.
It must be there Homer.
Come here and show it to me.
Alright, wait a second. I'll close the door part way.
If it was here, it would be here.
Homer, I'm almost positive Miss Watson didn't take it with her.
Alright, show it to me.
It's a book with a blue cover.
A blue cover?
Oh, this must be it.
Yes, Ms. Watson.
Henry, someone's out in the hall.
Well, I'm glad to hear that.
Quick, Homer, Doc, have you got it?
Where are we done?
Get down here beside our desk.
Did they come in, Henry?
No, they just closed the door.
Well, come on.
Let's get out of here.
And that's so fast, Homer.
It won't tell you they've gone down the hall.
But, Henry, I've got to get to my next class.
Quiet.
Open the door easy.
I'm going to.
You must be stuck.
Let me try it.
Henry, this is all your fault.
Now don't get panicky Homer, we'll get it open.
Oh, it's locked.
You are crazy. Why wouldn't anybody lock a door and draw a daylight?
All we have to do is throw ourselves against it.
Okay. One, two, three.
Don't you stand there Homer? Help me up.
I guess they locked it all right.
You mean we're locked in and I can't get to solid geometry?
Well at least they didn't see us Homer.
But Henry I'm weak in geometry as it is.
Well all we have to do is climb out that window.
But what good are we going to do? We're way up in the third floor.
Homer stop arguing. Give me that book and let's go.
[
If you're quite sure you won't let this book interfere with your studies anymore, you may have it.
Yes, Miss Watson.
I'm sorry you let Henry Aldrich have it.
After all, he has much more important things to attend to than Rita's revenge.
Yes, Miss Watson. He's a very nice boy, Nancy.
At least he has his good points.
But I do wish you'd become more interested in someone who takes things just a bit more seriously than Henry does.
Yes, Miss Watson.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Be careful, Homer.
Do you want to knock me off this fire escape?
Well, gee whiz, Henry, we have to get out of here somehow.
Don't you realize this fire escape
goes right past all the second floor classrooms?
It never goes below the second floor?
We'll keep quiet, Henry.
Suppose somebody should see us out here.
Let's close the window.
They're quiet now, Henry.
They're being quiet.
That's it.
Make all the noise you can.
All we have to do now is go up the fire escape to the roof.
And then I suppose we just jump off.
It's bound to leave to something, Homer.
Come on.
Have you got Nancy's book?
Sure.
Here, take it.
Here's my letter in it.
I don't know.
Hey, Homer.
What?
This is Nancy's book.
She was-- this is Miss Watson's report book.
There's a report book.
What made you think my letter'd be inside this?
You said blue so I grabbed blue.
[LAUGHTER]
But you should have looked, Homer.
Boy, if we get caught with this, we can even be expelled.
Just for having a report book?
Sure.
Well, you can be the one that takes it back, Henry.
All we have to do is open the window.
And be sure no one's in there, Henry.
No one's in there.
She was.
Lift, Henry.
I am lifting, Homer.
Move back so I can get some leverage.
What's the matter, Henry?
Are you weak?
Well, gee, as maybe I do need--
wouldn't you think I could at least open a window
when it's an emergency?
Boy, you're really in a fix.
You've got Ms. Watson's reports, and Nancy's
got your measurements.
Sure.
And probably by this time, Nancy's read the whole thing.
Come on, Homer, we've got to get off this virus game.
Boys, boys, what are you doing up there?
Who is it, Henry?
What are you doing up there?
It's Mr. Bradley.
He's down in the courtyard.
Boys!
- Why, we just kind of opened a window, Mr. Bradley.
- Don't you know the rules about going out
on the fire escape?
- Are there any special rules, Mr. Bradley?
- What are your names?
- Henry, Aldrich.
- Oh.
- Homer, Brown.
- Henry and Homer.
- All tricks and brown?
- Yes, sir.
(audience laughing)
- Of an adult and fire estate,
then report to my office at once.
- Yes, sir.
How would you like to have us get there, Mr. Bradley?
Any way you can.
The only trouble is, Mr. Bradley.
What's that?
Nothing. We'll get down.
And how long have you been a student in this school, young man?
About three years, Mr. Bradley.
And this other young man?
About three and a half, Mr. Bradley.
But that was on account of the mumps right on top of the measles.
I see.
And you both know those fire escapes were placed there for emergency use only?
Well, the fact is, Mr. Bradley...
It wasn't enough that you were out on a fire escape.
You climbed in a window and broke right into the middle of Professor Vanderhoof's French class.
Well, you see, Mr. Bradley was the only way we could get off the fire escape.
Professor Vanderhoof's window was open...
Homer, must you lean on my desk?
No, sir, excuse me.
I thought you were through with us.
I don't know whatever gave you that impression.
Excuse me, but can I interrupt you, Mr. Bradley?
You're Bill Turner, aren't you?
Yes, I'm the one that carried three men over our goal
Saturday.
And what were you sent in here for?
Well, I suppose I shouldn't have been reading this book
during study hour, Mr. Bradley.
What's the title?
Readers revenge.
I see.
- Hey, Henry. - Yes, Mr. Bradley.
What do you think of a boy who would spend his time
reading a book like that?
Well, I guess it's pretty bad, Mr. Bradley.
That's what I say.
I see.
Do you know what I think all three of you boys need?
No, sir.
Suppose you wait here, all of you,
while I step out and get your records.
Yes, sir.
Bill, what did you get that book?
From Nancy, and what business is it of yours?
Listen, Bill, could I borrow it a second?
Nancy's book, all I wanna do is take it for just one second.
I just want to...
Can't you even let me look at it?
Keep your hands off.
Let me have that.
People, wait, do you hear me?
Hey, Henry, look at what fell out of it.
There's your letter right in the floor.
Gee whiz.
Phil, turn to you, take your foot off that.
You make me.
Do you hear me?
Take your foot off that letter.
Henry, somebody's coming.
I don't care.
Mr. Bradley, Ms. Watson asked me, Henry.
Hello, Nancy.
Close the door.
Let go of my leg, Aldrich.
You look like you're like, do you hear me?
Let's go.
Boy, stop.
(audience laughing)
Lift his leg, Henry.
- I need more leverage.
- Hey, Bill, cut it out.
You're twisting my hand.
- Yeah?
- No, turn it, you stop that.
- Tharn you, Bill.
( (audience laughing)
- There.
- Henry, Gee, Henry, you knocked him out.
- Oh boy.
- You lifted him right off the floor.
- Hey, what happened?
- He's all right, Henry.
Pick him up before Mr. Bradley comes in.
- Come on, Homer.
Let's lift him out of the couch.
- Ugh.
Listen, Alders, why did you hit me with?
I just used my bare hands.
Didn't I, Nancy?
Now then, young man,
Turner, did anyone invite you to lie down in that pouch?
(audience laughing)
Oh, Mr. Bradley.
I'll help him out, Mr. Bradley.
Don't you think he can get up himself?
Well, I'm up.
Well, young lady.
Miss Watson asked me to bring her keys down here.
I'll take them in one moment.
Turner, here's what I want you to do.
I want you to spend a part of each lunch hour for the next 10 days picking up the papers
and the corridors of this building.
On all three floors.
And as for how did Miss Watson's report book get here on my desk?
On your desk, Mr. Bradley.
Nancy, would you see that she gets it back?
Yes, sir.
Now then, Aldrich and Brown.
Yes, Mr. Bradley?
Yes, Mr. Bradley.
I'm sending you to the gym instructor.
He needs a couple of huskies like you two to help him move the steel lockers.
Move them?
Yeah, tell me.
Aren't there quite a few, Mr. Bradley?
There are 350. It will take every afternoon for the next two weeks.
Gee whiz! That's alright Homer. You heard what Mr. Bradley said.
They need a couple of huskies like you and me.
Aldrich, what's that you're tearing up?
Nothing. It's just sort of a letter I've decided I won't need anymore.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
A radar network to detect the approach of planes
can do the entire job of protecting our country
from a devastating surprise air attack.
That's up to us as individual citizens.
Right now, the Air Defense Command
needs 300,000 more volunteers for its ground observer core.
Both men and women from teenage up
can contribute a few hours of their time each week
and perform a valuable service to our country.
Right-of-phone your nearest civil defense center,
a right to ground observer corps Air Force Washington 25, DC.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Well, gee.
Henry Aldrich, look at that window.
That's what I mean, Nancy.
No matter what I touch these days, it crumbles right in my hands.
[LAUGHTER]
The Aldridge Family is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
Henry is played by Bobby Ellis and Homer by Johnny Fiedler.
Mr. and Mrs. Aldridge are house Jamison and Catherine Roth.
Your announcer is Dick Dudley.
Listen again next week, same time, same station, for another sparkling half hour with the Aldridge Family.
Good night, everybody.
This is NBC, the National Broadcasting Company.
(bell dings)
[ Silence ]