The Aldrich family based on characters originated by Clifford Goldsmith and
starring Ezra Stonner's Henry with Jackie Kalk as Homer.
Henry! Henry Aldrich!
Come in, other!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[cheering]
[Music]
And now for the Aldrich family. Memories of youth are precious things to be challenged and recalled all your life.
And there's no better way to keep those memories fresh than knowing a real teenage of everything boy like Henry Aldrich
Or Henry's every escapade seems a mirror held up to your own you
The scene opens in the Aldrich front hall
Homer are you sure sure I was walking by the emporium and I saw them right in the window with my own two eyes
That's what I mean. You've been complaining. You don't see too well lately. That's only in Latin
Oh.
Hey, man, is that the phone?
No, Father, just Homer.
Oh, I thought perhaps it was that long distance call I'm waiting for.
Henry, can you think of a way we can raise $6.95 a piece?
Just $6.95 for genuine pilots?
Oh, sure.
They're surplus from the Air Force.
Boy, would I like those.
I'll say they're even for a line.
The only thing is, it's $6.95.
They'll go like hot cake, Homer.
- Hey, my father will never advance me that much voluntarily.
- Henry!
- Yes, Mary.
- Well, maybe you have any white elephants you'd like to get rid of.
- Do I have one?
- Hey, elephant.
Do you, Henry?
- I don't think so.
- Do you have any--your hot, Homer?
- White elephant?
- Yes, I'd be glad to stop buying collection.
- Well, I haven't noticed any lately.
- Can we--is Mary feeling all these days?
- Hey, Mama, I've got an idea.
- What about?
- How we can get the pilot's food?
- How?
Oh you calling Henry?
Number three.
Al, two, three, two.
No, two, three, two.
Hey, that's my house.
Homer, all you have to do is talk your parents into it, and mine will be a pushover.
When Henry, every time I ask my father for money, he makes me count out ten dollars in pennies.
That poor.
It's supposed to teach me the value of money.
Homer, the least you can do is try here, take it.
But, Henry.
Hello?
Yes.
Is this Mrs. Brown?
Who is this?
Homer.
Homer, who?
Homer, you're Sam.
Wow.
Yes, dear.
Mother, how's your headache?
Fine.
It cleared up just a little while after you left.
Oh, that's good.
Mother, how do you feel about boots?
You mean the polyn?
No, the crane with fur lining from the Air Force.
Fear the Air Force would never take you. You are after way.
He was, I don't want to join the Air Force. All I want is $6.95.
So do I. I'd like a new hat. But I'm not going to cut out $10 in this heading together.
But mother...
Oh, my head aches back. Goodbye, dear.
I don't think he makes me suffer.
I love it.
Hello.
Boy, you don't know how to handle mothers at all, Homer.
Well, let's see you do better.
Dear, you're not disturbing your father, are you?
Disturb him?
How could we do that?
Well, I want you to be very careful today.
He's working on a very important case.
Has he been kicked out of his office?
No, Homer, it's being painted.
And I'd appreciate it if you'd steer clear of his study.
Mother...
Mother, how would you like to go through this winter and not have to worry about my
catching cold.
Catching cold.
Nice going, him.
Let me see your forehead, Henry.
Oh, no, Mother.
You don't understand.
I don't have a cold now.
It's this winter I'm worrying you about.
So, could I have 695?
What's for?
Boots.
Politics boots.
Sort of like a luscious.
Dear, you'd have to ask your father for that much money.
You mean if it's alright with him, it's alright with you?
I suppose so, but do it quickly.
He's in his study.
Can we explain it's really our patriotic duty to take these boots off
boots off the governor's hands. Yeah. Father. Yes. Is it the phone is at long
distance the phone? No sir. Henry I do not wish to be disturbed this afternoon.
Is that clear? But but I'm going out and play. Father couldn't you answer just one
question for me. Yes. May I have 695 for a pair of boots? You may not. Homer maybe
we can earn six ninety five who would pay us that kind of money oh boy father I heard it
I heard it I hear it I hear it I just saw it hello hello
Samuel Oggard this is he go ahead hello Sam oh bird I've been waiting for your
call all morning I've been trying to get through all morning well thank heavens you
did that brief has to be filed by five this afternoon and I can't file without
that information you got it didn't you
yeah
just a minute wait a
time to pay for it
waste
yeah
where's the telephone memo pad
if you stop here
you stop at a time like this
i've got your cargo hanging
wait a minute i'll get you a milk bill
i never had that something
hello bert
you got some paper Sam
there's a newspaper here on the telephone table
i'll jot it down on that
fine
The first is volume three.
- Article 14.
- Article 23.
Got it?
- Yep.
- The second one, let me see.
- Connor, would you consider those tattoo of Liberty bookends on your desk?
White elephant?
- Mary, I'm speaking to Chicago.
- Oh, mother.
- Oh, hello, Bert.
Now, what's the second one?
- Mother, I found it.
- Oh, you found what, dear?
- Got black and purple veins at Bellgate five years ago.
It's a perfect white elephant.
- Peter, do you think we should give that away after all your Aunt Bell paid 25?
$5 for it she told you that of course not just happened to leave the price tag on
Oh, well, it's certainly not doing anybody any good up in the alley. All right, dear
Sammy you still on the phone? Oh, thank you very much, right?
Goodbye
What is it Alice dear? Please come and eat your lunch. Oh first I must copy these figures into my brief
You can do that if you eat you've got to take some nourishment. Oh, but I am sick very well
And Alice isn't there any way to get the boys out of the house this afternoon?
I'll speak to them, dear. You go in and start on your salad.
Oh, certainly a relief to have that Chicago business all over.
Henry, I saw it myself.
Henry? Yes, mother.
Dear, I'd like to speak to you.
Mother, I know what you're going to say, and the only reason I'm excited is because of a ridiculous thing Homer just said.
Mrs. Allrich, do you happen to have last night's paper around?
It's right there on the telephone table, but dear you and Homer will have to get out of the house this afternoon
Yes, mother here. I'll show you Henry even if the ad is in there. They never give a job like that to us
Why not? We're we're too young. No, that's a beautiful part of it. What I find the ad
There it is Henry. Let's see wanted men to work on street cars Saturdays
Good pay experience unnecessary
Call L950. Experience unnecessary. I know. Police we can do is call.
Number three. L950. L950. Hope they pay us higher. Three dollars a day, Henry. For us?
Now tell the truth. Doesn't that sound foolish?
Senator Streetcard Company Employment Office. Hello. I'm calling about the ad in yesterday's paper.
Yes? How inexperienced can you be? You've had a high school education?
In a manner of speaking you might say so.
That's enough.
Would you tell that to my friends?
Here Henry.
Hello?
What is it you want to know?
You mean you'd let us drive street cars without experience?
Of course not.
Do just help collect fares.
On the line that runs down to the football stadium.
Is that all? Just collect fares?
That's right.
If you want that job you better come down today before 5.
Ask me.
This is Lincoln's browser.
Lincoln's browser?
Homer write that down.
Blingenspelzer?
How do you spell it?
Just the way it sounds.
Blingenspelzer.
Prashiller.
I'll write it down next to the ad.
Mr....
How much would that job pay?
Six twenty a day.
Six twenty?
Six twenty.
Oh boy.
What do you take?
Okay.
Drop down.
Goodbye.
I told you, Henry.
I told you.
Henry, could I have part of that paper to wrap this phase in?
Sure, Mary, here.
My goodness, I don't need that much.
Here, I just cleaned this hole.
I'll pick the paper, Seth.
Are you using all of that paper, Henry?
Now, just this section.
It will give me the rest of it.
'Cause the junk man comes today.
I'm going down to the White Elephant shop.
Very well.
And Henry, remember what I told you about getting out of the house.
Henry, you know what? Let's do one.
Let's take a street car down there.
We can get experience as we go.
That's right.
If they pay $6.20 for us the way we are, imagine what they'll pay if we know the business.
You're crazy, Henry.
You're the one who's crazy.
Because you've been earning this trolley for 10 minutes, you're thinking of the whole thing.
He uses that pedal to ring the bell.
Ring the bell, ring the bell.
Homer, what happens when your father presses the pedal in his car?
It stalls.
Come on, let's go up and stand by them motily.
Okay.
Find straight off.
Do you mind letting that lady off, Sonny?
Excuse me.
Watch your step getting off, Miss.
Wallen Street next.
You boys getting off the ball?
Ah, no, sir.
Mr. Do you mind us standing here?
I guess not.
You think you might like to take up transportation when you get older?
Yes, we're thinking of going into it right now.
It's a fine career for a man.
Is that a fine?
Yes, indeed. You get around. See the world. You know what I mean?
Oh, mister, that pedal on the floor there. Is that the gas or the bell?
Neither. It's a brake.
You see, Homer. It's a good thing we ask.
Well, this isn't Walnut Street, mister.
I know. I have to go out and switch the track.
Oh boy, look at all those things he has to work.
Henry, which one is the belt he's supposed?
Now listen Homer, don't touch anything.
There it is, hand that butt.
Homer, look out for the clank.
Why?
Homer, you're out of all!
I'm hoping Homer's not there!
I don't know how you stay!
Oh boy, he hit stop.
Huh, good work, Homer.
May, didn't you stop it?
Who started that car?
Oh, it's futile.
It was an accident, hon.
Sure, and it stopped it, man.
It stopped all right.
It chanced.
Smack into the Swiss.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello?
Hello, sir.
What had cost you--
Yes, pretty much.
I'm sorry, sir.
There'll be three hours a day.
Three hours?
Operator, don't you realize that brief has to be in by five?
I'm sorry, sir.
We'll do that quick, yes.
Thank you.
No, Sam, calm down.
Calm down, Alice.
Do you realize what losing that paper means?
But if you'll just tell me what sort of paper it was--
A newspaper.
Yes, it is times.
I jotted it down on the margin and left it right here
on the telephone table when you made me come to lunch.
Oh, dear.
Sam, I thought it was just an ordinary center bill time.
Alex, what did you do with it?
I told Henry he could have it.
Henry has it?
Yes, that is he has part of it.
Where the rest?
Mary, all except the part I put on the trash pile outside.
On the trash pile?
Maybe the part I want is there.
The only thing is, go to the jumpman, take that out, not more than 15 minutes ago.
Oh, no.
Mother, are you all?
Mary, come in here at once.
My goodness, Father, you should have seen the excitement downtown.
Travel was tied up for bomb.
Never mind, that way.
We were jacking up a streetcar right in the middle of Maine.
Alice.
Mary, what did you do with that part of the newspaper?
You wrapped Aunt Belle's vase in.
I left it in the white elephant shop with a vase.
Go right back there and get it.
His father.
Who are?
I have some very important information written down on part of that paper.
Oh my goodness, I'll run all the way!
Before you do, change your display deal.
- Let him out in the flat heels, just start.
- Yes, Father.
- Did Henry say where he was going out?
- No, dear.
- Well, I'll have to find him somehow.
Meanwhile, you called us and tell him
to bring all our papers right back.
- Yes, dear, and how about a cup of tea?
- Tea, tea.
- To calm you down.
- I'll get it, let your car go.
- I'll put on the wall, hey.
Go ahead, Chicago.
- I should go where?
- Henry, is that you?
- Yes, Father, boy, and do we need a lawyer?
- Where are you?
downtown with Homer and the streetcar company and sits where responsible.
Hey, redoch you will the step. I'm coming right down.
You are?
Homer, we have nothing to worry about. I just got us the best lawyer in town.
Where'd your father go?
And there he is talking to the man from the streetcar company.
company where there in front of the drugstore oh yeah boy is that guy in man see
the way he's pointing his finger right in your father's face you'll notice though
my father's pointing right back
they got the streetcar moving I think this is a fine thing we're the ones who
did the whole thing and with all these people in front of us I can't see a thing
Hey, hey, hey, where are you?
Here, fathers.
Is everything settled?
Just let them sue.
We'll sue right back.
Now, Henry, let me have that paper.
What paper?
You took from the house this morning.
The newspaper? The one with the ad in it?
Yes.
I don't have it.
We toy the ad out and threw the rest of it away.
Throw it away?
Where?
On the trolley?
What trolley?
The one that was stuck in the switch.
There it is going down the street.
Well, that's a fine thing.
Come back.
Father, what have I done?
Come back!
[Music]
Now getting back to the troubles of Henry Aldrich, or rather Mr. Aldrich, for the
newspaper on which he has written important information has disappeared in three
directions. Right now Mary is hurrying back to the white elephant shop to retrieve
her part of the paper. Mrs. Miller. Mrs. Miller.
I'm Mary. Oh, Richard. I was hoping you'd drop in again.
Mrs. Miller, you know that white elephant I brought in this morning?
Yes, Mary. I'm just as thrilled as I can be about that.
Yeah, but when you brought that in Mrs. Hooker said to me she's on a committee to me.
Yes, I know.
Mrs. Hooker said we'll never be able to sell that thing.
That white elephant's going to be a white elephant.
Just kind of cute, I thought.
To that vase, Mrs. Miller. Where is it now?
That's what I'm getting at, Mary.
I sold it.
You did?
Mrs. Smith.
Oh dear.
I had to talk her ear off, but I finally sold it to her for 95 cents.
But the newspaper, you still have that, don't you?
What news page?
That the vase was wrapped in.
My goodness, no, I tore it up and stuffed it in a vase.
What father? I had to keep it from breaking.
What's wrong? Mrs. Miller, do you know where Mrs. Schmidt lives?
Oh, gracious, I could find out.
Could you? My father's entire career may depend on getting that paper back.
Father, are you sure that what your after was on the part of the paper we had?
No, Henry, but it's liable to be, and I can't overlook a single possibility.
There's a street car, Mr. Orlner.
Where? Just ahead.
Oh, yes.
Is that the trolley you went on, Henry?
I don't know.
They all look alike.
It's stopping at that traffic light.
I'll pull over in park.
Father, that's it.
Are you sure?
I'm positive.
I remember that sign on the side of it.
Ride the trolleys and smile.
Well, let's hail him before the light changes.
Homer, get out.
Hey there.
Hey.
You're calling me?
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry I'm not taking any passengers.
Oh, well, we don't wish to ride.
You see, there's a newspaper on your truly...
You? It's you again.
Yes, sir.
And him?
Me?
You cut your nerve.
Henry, I'm going home.
Now, look here, my good man.
If you just let us look through the car, we won't bother you again.
I'll say you won't, because none of you are sitting foot in this car.
Now, see, here I'll see here yourself.
Would you mind getting off that step?
I'd be delighted after I've looked for my paper.
You can get it down at the lost and found.
You can't keep me off if I pay my pay.
I can too. I'm not taking passengers.
I'm headed for the car barn.
Now see here. I'm a lawyer.
And I'm a madam.
Are you letting me on this car?
Are you getting off that step?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Mother, are you still there?
Yes, dear.
Did I hear you say you were in jail?
No.
at the car barn its father who was in jail
oh no but he's out now and mother he said that if Mary or Gus show up with part
of that paper to send them down to the courthouse he'll be waiting there
whether I've got to hang up now goodbye
goodbye
maybe you can explain what we're after to this man as I understand it it's some
kind of newspaper yes or it's very important I get it back you could try
I lost and found this is the employment office employment is your name fallen
fleser Lengen fell sir how did you know gee whiz your
habits whole thing started mr. We're is lost and found they're close for the day
they are you wouldn't have much chance of finding it anyway the conductors usually
collect the papers and take them home all of them usually our conductors are the
best men read in town.
Would they even take a yesterday's time?
No, they read that yesterday.
Well then, can we maybe store in the car?
Which trolley was it?
The one that got stuck downtown.
Oh, that's poor Higgins's.
Old 99.
That trolley is down at the graveyard.
Where?
The graveyard.
They decided to retire her.
After all that happened today, they figured she'd jinxed.
You mean trolleys have graveyards?
You'll find her down at the other end of the car bond.
Thanks Homer, come on.
You know what I think.
What?
Let's forget about that job.
If you're seeing what streetcar people go through,
they don't get paid half enough.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello.
Is this long distance?
Hi, Captain.
Have you gotten through on my call to Chicago?
Oh, what's your name, sir?
All rich.
I'm sorry, sir.
They're still a slight delay.
Slight delay?
I've been calling for four hours.
I'm sorry, sir.
Well, if you get through, I'm at L998.
It's a payphone at the courthouse.
Oh, yes, sir.
And keep trying, please.
Goodbye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[SINGING]
Yes?
Hey, it's me, gosh, the junkie.
Oh, yes.
If you've got my papers, gosh.
I sure have.
Out my wagon.
Well, come on.
Let's get it.
I hope to have on what I'm after is on it.
It's almost 4.30.
Well, I never thought I'd get here,
but it's killer made the trip fine.
Gila?
My horse.
She, there she is.
Double park.
Where's our papers?
On the wagon.
But this wagon's full of papers.
Where's ours?
I don't know.
That's everything that's collected today.
Your paper's in there somewhere.
But I can't go through a whole wagon load of papers
right in front of the courthouse.
And then I'll find it then.
Well, back, Sheila up to the curb.
I suppose I'll have to try.
Yes, sir.
Back up there, Sheila.
Back up.
Hey, the wagon seems stuck somehow.
Hurry up, Gus.
Here comes a policeman.
Well, I'll be hanged.
No wonder she won't move.
The winds are stuck in the street, gertrags.
What?
Well, I'm not getting mixed up with the streetcar company again.
Hey, hey, you can't leave me now.
There comes Henry.
There, but what will I tell the law?
Hey, Henry, how are you?
I'm a boy, Father.
We ran all the way.
Have you got the paper?
That's a long story.
We went down to the graveyard, see?
What graveyard?
But they'd already cleaned old 99 out.
So we had to go to the incinerator.
But it was already incinerated.
Father?
Father, I thought it.
What's that?
No, Mary.
Where did you find it?
Where I've been all afternoon.
And Mrs. Smith.
What floor?
Facing this newspaper together.
Never mind that.
Read off what's there.
It's 10 minutes to five.
Yes, Father.
Oh, wait till I get this brief, Oban.
Go ahead.
From the top?
Yes.
What's the first?
Five pounds of potatoes.
What?
Then comes a pound of coffee.
Mary.
That's a grocery list.
I know, but I thought it might be part of your case.
Mary, what kind of a case would I have
with five pounds of potatoes?
Well, I didn't know it.
I mean, I thought--
I was just trying to help.
Oh, well, of course you were.
I'm sorry, Mary.
I'm sorry, too.
So am I, Mr. Aldrich.
Homer, keep out of it.
Well, thank you, Homer.
Henry, I appreciate what you did, too.
Well, we might as well go home.
You mean you're giving up, Father?
It's just a few minutes to five.
There isn't much hope left.
Does this mean you're ruined, Mr. Aldrich?
Well, not completely, Homer.
Come on, Mary, we'll walk on ahead.
Boy, if we hadn't wanted those pilots boots,
that's what started the whole thing.
How, Henry?
If it hadn't been for them, we would never
have called Hellsinfessor for that job.
Hellsinfessor?
Henry, that man's name was Hockendouper.
Homer, you're crazy.
You are the one who's crazy.
Man?
Sure I'll prove it.
How?
Here's that clipping with his name or--
What's wrong?
Was his name Voll III, Art 14?
What?
Oh, she was.
I was looking at the wrong side.
Voll III, Art.
Homer, let me see that.
Oh boy.
Father!
Henry, what's wrong?
Come back!
[music playing]
(music)
Would you like a pillow for your feet, Sam?
No thanks. This is fine.
Henry? No mother.
Boy, is this a comfortable couch?
My goodness, what a day.
What time was the brief file?
Four fifty-nine.
and three quarters. Boy, if it wasn't for the streetcar company selling us, everything would be fine.
Henry, would you do me a favor? Sure, fine. In the future, would you please stay away from streetcars?
You mean for the rest of my life? If necessary. Maybe you're right.
And Alice, I don't mean to criticize, but this whole thing would never have happened if we had a pad by the telephone.
Yes, dear. As a matter of fact, one came in the mail this morning.
Here it is on this table. Who's it from? I haven't looked yet.
Oh, my goodness. What's so funny?
Is this bad? There are jokes on it? Sam, do you know what it says?
What? For smoother writing, use this pad by Golly.
For smoother writing, use the center of the control.
What? The trowel?
We're coming each other so far.
[LAUGHTER]
Well, what do you know?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[APPLAUSE]
Listen again next week, same time, same station, for another sparkling half hour with your favorite youngster, his family and his pals.
The Eldridge family, starring Ezra Stone, is written by Clifford Goldsmith.
The Eldridge family is distributed internationally by Master of Broadcasting Corporation.
[applause]
(buzzing)