[Music]
To a teenage boy each new day is a new world.
Filled with all sorts of discoveries and excitement and even mishaps, which drop a
Always empty.
Or it is with every opening.
The scene opens at the telephone and calls it front hall.
It is Saturday morning.
Hello?
Oh, how are you, Gladys?
Fine, can you hear us?
Fine.
Do you, well, hear your voice?
Thank you.
You're a student.
It is?
I can see you.
Oh, it's a little bit more.
Oh, Henry.
Henry.
Henry, all of you?
Yeah.
Oh, oh.
Henry.
Oh, just a minute, Gladys.
Yes, Mother.
Me, tell me to birth the...
Sure, Mother.
Just as soon as I find out one thing from Gladys.
One thing, Henry.
Oh, I...
Do you remember last Thursday, Gladys?
I think I do.
You mean you don't remember making a date with me?
Of course I do.
How could I forget that?
When we get bored?
Oh, tonight.
And the reason I call, Gladys,
about what time do you want me to come over?
What time?
Yeah.
I wasn't sure whether you wanted me to come in time for
for what?
I mean I certainly wouldn't want to barge in right in the middle of your
your
how does five thirty sound?
Five thirty?
Isn't that a little bit of a challenge?
It is?
It isn't?
Well how about six?
Is that two early?
One or maybe six thirty?
Six thirty?
Not a dash.
You're at 630 is a nice round number.
Is that before?
Well, that is, was that the answer?
No.
Henry!
Well, 630 is fine, Gladys.
I'll be there.
You can go by.
I'm coming, Mother.
Your breakfast is getting cold.
Now, can you reach the cream, please?
There you are, dear.
Thank you.
Father.
Yes, Henry.
Father, you've had quite a bit of experience eating.
I beg your pardon?
Fantastic.
Great.
So, down to Henry.
People sometimes invite you over to their house for dinner, don't they?
That happened occasionally.
Why do you ask?
Well, Father, when someone invites you over to their house at 6.30, does that mean it's
for dinner or just social?
What's that?
Henry, please eat your grapefruit.
When I've got something on my mind?
The other best way to get something off your mind is to put something in your stomach.
Now start on your grapefruit.
Yes, Mother.
Oh, Henry.
Did I get you, Father?
You did.
Do you see how upset I am, mother?
Alice, let him ask me whatever he's going to.
The sand must simply stay up until he does.
Now, who's invited you to dinner?
That's it, I don't know.
What?
I mean, I know who it is. Sure, but I'm not sure they are.
Oh, what? Sure.
Alice.
Yes, ma'am.
Alice is your son. Translation, please.
Don't you understand, Father?
No.
It's perfectly simple. I've got a date tonight with Gladys Krennis,
and I'm not sure whether eating goes with it or not.
Oh, that seems simple to me. Did she invite you?
Well, she told me to be sure and be there no later than 630.
630? Yes, mother. I got the idea. That was the absolute deadline.
Well, it certainly sounds like dinner.
Oh, this is sounds like nothing of the sort. It might easily be after dinner.
Now, Sam Mabel Prentice was a cabinol before she was married, wasn't she?
Well, that got to deal with it.
Well, her father was a railroad engineer.
And, Ray, she's your mother. Transplacement, please.
They live right across the street from us and I know.
Mr. Kavanaugh's train got in at 6.50 and they never ate before 6.50.
Oh boy, you mean I'm really invited?
No, Henry, let's not see Hasty.
What you heard with Mother said, they always eat at 6.30. It's in their blood.
It's a very simple way to find out if you're invited to dinner.
There is how?
Phone Gladys and Asker.
Asker? Right out?
Why not?
I couldn't see if he wasn't expecting me to think I wanted an invitation.
Well, don't you?
Sam.
No, look, suppose I do this.
Toby Smith lives next door to Gladys.
Maybe he could tell me whether they eat before or after 630.
Finish a great suit first.
But Mother, don't you think I should find out?
I'm going to do it, your mother said.
But, Father, I'm right.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry, Dee.
What's in there, Dee Whizmother?
Did I get you in the eye too?
Now see here.
The fans are heaven's sake, letting go make his phone call.
But, Mark, you want to tell me what you saw?
I think you're not quite in those dishes very well, good.
Oh, Mark, it was time to...
And if you're lending our best sign of the ass-mable for her engagement party tonight, we certainly want to send them over, please.
But doesn't it sound like you're so happy, Mark, when I say to you, Mark?
- Hey, Mom.
- Well, thank you.
I think you may be doubting the conclusion.
But why would you want to come over so early
if you didn't take me out to dinner?
- I'm glad it's a wise thing for you to do
with falling in red,
trying to out definitely just funny as you might.
- Oh, my God, I just couldn't.
- Why not?
- Because if you haven't had taken me to dinner,
my goodness, I just died in the dark, no.
- How's it going?
- I'm good.
- But I went out there and I said,
well, what if you sit,
(scoffs)
my goodness.
- You couldn't break the place, did you?
- Yeah.
I could warn I saw somebody up in that big M3.
That's all I got, y'all.
You did.
Another, you know, it looked like me.
Oh, but it couldn't be.
What would Henry all be to doing up in all M3?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Son?
I just found the brown.
They'll join us?
Yes, dear.
And Elizabeth had the same reaction I did, imagine going out
to dinner for no reason whatsoever.
Why not?
Henry's having dinner at the furnaces.
You deserve a day off.
Why not?
Yes, the same thing.
I can't help being thrilled.
What time do you tell the ground to me, to--
Seven.
And do you think you should call the mansion house
for a reservation?
No, well, we necessary.
But suppose it's crowded.
How if I'm positive it won't be?
Besides, the head waiter knows me very well.
I can always get a table.
Boy, mother, look at my blue skirt suit.
Mary, hunger, and gourish sweater right next to it.
I'm sure we can clean it up clean it up. Well, could you do it now, mother?
It's only five more hours until six thirty and I can't go looking like a bowl weevil
Henry I don't like to seem over cautious, but I just like to have one more
Are you absolutely searching you're invited to dinner at the fantasy?
And he said he was positive. He's been positive before
I told you what I saw with my own eyes when I just happened to be up in their own tree this morning
She was with they be getting out their best kind of just things with each other
I'll be right there Homer
Lucky dog and they're lucky. Do you are why?
It's that right here
My folks are going out with your folks for dinner and they gave me a dollar and a half to blow in an any turn of dinner
I was now kidding a whole dollar and a hand together with the corner. I guess they now be able to
myself six. Oh, I am running a lucky joy. Well, mama, what do I tell you about me?
And why don't you get some money from your parents and little stuff ourselves together?
I'm just in home. I'm sort of invited out to dinner tonight. You're where?
The Gladys Prennis is. No kidding. Sure. That's funny. I just delivered something here from the
We're glad I see the link a little for the boxy little room.
Homer, you think this blue-haired suit?
Yeah, I'm even cleaning Mary's Angora off it. That's how sure I am.
Yeah, you are a rucking dog.
I don't think you better wear your blue-haired suit.
Why not?
Because the fur had your limit with all your hair.
Evening, yeah?
Sure.
They told the truth, they had to have it for today.
Tonight?
Oh, boy.
Hey, what's the matter?
Homer, you don't suppose that dinner is formal, do you?
Little Pacito.
Sure.
And boy, my father didn't even think
I was important not for good China.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Dennis, would you let me up the back, please?
Yes, mother.
And look, why don't I do this?
Why don't I call all the restaurants in town
and see us heading with me to reservation?
Here, that's very foolish.
and I get all the way.
Well, could we hold this a little bit more, Mother?
You know, I think that cleanness grunks this gown.
Mother, why don't we admire you down over that labor?
I'm much too boned here.
Oh, which reminds me?
Your daughter and I've been discussing that evening,
down Gladys, and, well, we think it might be wise
to sew on a little lace around the shoulders.
Mother, I'm not calling you.
We realize that.
(audience laughing)
That's why we thought some lace would add a great deal.
- But in my family, you know how easily you can't go.
In a year or two, when you build up your resistance,
we can take the light off and answer the phone.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Hello?
- Oh, hi, glad I'm hearing you.
- Hello, honey.
- Lucky.
- I have to say that sign here,
not asking about sign up.
- Bye, bye.
- Hello?
- How are you?
- Fine, how are you?
- Fine.
I'll see what's exciting, hold on.
- You're asking you a 632, wanna?
Oh, I'm glad it's yes, I just wanted to know I never look forward to a new move. I can't I could you hold on?
Are you sure?
Oh
You know.
And I am better.
Of course you did.
I mean, I'm so glad you called.
You are?
Well, the...
The rule of glad is I'm sorry.
Well, what you might call a problem about dinner tonight.
Problem?
I mean, nothing's going wrong with you, am I?
No, things you're fine and I am.
That's fine.
How are they at yours?
Fine.
I mean, would you mind very much if I wore a maroon tie?
I'm a maroon tie?
in my tuxedo. She was somehow my black when things who have disappeared come point like
tuxedo? You were a tuxedo tonight?
Then you want me to?
Well, yes, that's a good idea.
Well...
I'm gonna have to hurry and hang up, Mom. I think it's just say goodbye.
Come on.
Mother! Mother, you have to go on that late on my evening down right away!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Let's cross over.
Glad it's lived on this block.
Homer, in a formal dinner, which sport do you use first?
They have a more than one.
Of course.
Well, I start at the end and work hard my place.
And that makes sense.
And hey, Lisa, if you were moving,
Did you get the business name special at the main sector in order to table the holder,
hamburger paradise?
Well, where would you want?
Well, I was concerned that it would be about like a good, solid bowl of soup.
But, in this, the rest would be heard.
I don't know.
Oh, and here I am with a dollar 7.05 and I'd only have to eat it up.
Can you make this out?
What is it?
A menu I picked up from the purple goo.
Does this at the bottom say all new foods are salad and potatoes or salad or potatoes?
Why aren't they?
Oh, we haven't got time to fool around here.
Gladys is half along.
Yeah, so is that our moonlit going over in South Abby's?
Our moonlit?
And then we'll come with a few.
So are we.
Oh, gee.
Hi, guys.
I was just about to knock.
I saw you coming up to walk.
Now, good for you, the person who wants to feed her.
I do.
You look pretty handsome yourself.
Thank you.
Boy, that's some gown.
Wait a minute, here I go after I build up my resistance.
I'm certainly looking forward to this evening.
So am I. Well, here's my hat.
You're closing it off?
You don't think I should?
I'm just going to go.
I'll put a visor on the hall table to the time being.
You're... Boy, I sure am hungry.
- It's so mild. - Yes, sir.
- Yeah. - Mmm, what's that I smell?
- Smells so good. - Smells so good.
Mmm, sure smells good.
- Oh, that's taboo. - It is, I've never eaten any of you.
(crowd laughing)
- That's my tooth, you, Kelly. - First, huh?
Oh, oh, you're...
(crowd laughing)
- Yeah, honey.
Would you like a glass of cinead with you?
- Cinead with you? - My mother thought you might
I've been before before before what?
Oh, excuse me, honey.
I'm phone.
Hello?
And this is Linda Dolders.
Can I see the head briefly?
Yes, Linda Dolders.
Let me see.
Oh, it is.
Thanks, Linda.
I've been in a living room.
Hello, mother.
Dear, your father and I are just about to leave some
imagine houses.
Everything all right?
All right?
About dinner, I mean.
Why, why don't we have a start and eat yet, but they just serve the tomato juice.
Staying in?
Sure.
going into the dining room for the rest of it any minute now.
Well, have a good time and have a good day.
Yes, Mother?
And the dis
That's my aunt, maybe they're going to eat alone.
- We're going to eat alone?
- Oh, yeah.
- Is this the two of us?
- Yeah.
- Oh, boy.
(crowd laughing)
- You mean you're starting?
- Maybe I'm ready any time you are.
- That's good.
You're too hot.
(crowd laughing)
- You mean you want me to put on my hat?
- That's good, you sure?
- Oh, sure.
I just didn't realize it was going to be that formal.
(audience laughing)
I was real, this is the first room I've ever had
a formal dinner with any born in private.
- Me too, I mean you don't.
- I'm practically honest, this is the first time
I've ever been invited out to dinner.
- Is that a thought?
(audience laughing)
Invited out.
- Tell me what's wrong.
- Why you thought you had to dinner, didn't you?
- Why, yeah.
You are.
- Oh, I thought I might have missed anything.
Goodness, this is going to be a night I'll never forget it will. I have a feeling it's gonna be one I'll never forget
I'm getting back to the troubles of Henry Olmer. They carved his date with Gladys Kretz began at 6 30
Henry jumped at the conclusion that he'd been invited to dinner. After a quick tomato juice cocktail however
He learns that planet is expected to be taken out to dinner.
The scene opens in the lobby of the Manchin house restaurant.
It is dinner time.
Now, take here.
Sister Aldridge, you're raising your voice.
I'm not raising it. Besides, I have ever right to.
I've been coming here to the Manchin house regularly for 15 years now,
and it is no time to tell me to have no cable.
Naturally, I'm very sorry, sir, but you should have phoned for reservation.
That's beside the voice. Let me speak to the headwaiter.
I'm the headwaiter. I mean, the headwaiter was of all hands.
He left six months ago. He couldn't have. But he did.
But he did.
Now, you're the one who's raising yours on.
I'm sorry.
You're all that I'm willing to give you a table.
I'm anxious to.
But it'll have to be one on the side of the room.
But I can't sit behind those palms.
I'm allergic to them.
To palm, the last time we sat behind them,
I sneeze from the fruit cup right through the strawberry
shortcake.
You said they have to give us a table in the middle of the room.
Very well, Mr. Olgich.
Very well.
But you'll have to wait at least 40 minutes.
40 minutes?
At least.
Now, just a moment.
The browns will be here any second,
and they're counting on us.
So it may be arranged.
I'm sorry.
Sorry.
After we've been coming here for 50 years, all you can say is you're sorry.
Alex, please.
You're raising your voice.
[MUSIC]
Hey, we're not really going to have dinner here in the morning.
We might.
I mean, that depends on whether you happen to see my mother and father in the dining room.
Good evening, sir.
Just you.
Could I speak to the head waiter?
I'm afraid not he went home about an hour ago with a very severe headache
Well, glad if you mind if I talk to the waiter for one second
No, excuse me look waiter. Do you happen to know my mother and father?
I'm not sure I've had a pleasure well
They're eating here tonight. See I thought under the circumstance as they might like to have a join them and put everything on one
I'll only be a second glatter a young man. What's your parents look like look like?
I've never seen my grandmother.
I'll tell you, my mother looks like life.
Have you ever seen my grandmother?
No, it's not.
That's too bad.
They're the image of each other.
I'm afraid I can't help you, son.
Hey, Gladys, what are you doing at that table?
I was swinging out the car.
I'm going to get a gun, hold it.
Here, I've got to know you fine.
Gladys, my goodness is, look at these places.
I think you're sad.
Oh, sorry.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Waiters, waiters.
Someone calling me.
It's me.
You'll go by the door, Wayne.
Oh, yes, sir.
Have you and the young lady decided on your order?
Why, if she's still having a little trouble making up her mind.
And while she is, I thought I'd ask you.
Do you have an easy credit plan?
[LAUGHTER]
Easy, credit.
Yes.
I'm sorry.
have an easy credit plan.
- The easier the better.
No, I'm afraid not.
- Wrong.
Well, will you be taking on any help for the summer?
- Where it closed for the summer.
- Wrong.
- Yes, we usually did.
- Just look at that.
- You see my parents?
- No, no, but look at that young man
with his nose pressed against the front window.
- Where?
- Right next to the menu.
- Go away young man, go away.
- Oh, oh, you're comer.
- Excuse me.
Please tell him he's touching the entire window.
Homer, boy, am I glad I found you.
- Yes, can we just look at these prices?
- Homer, you haven't eaten all red.
- No, I'm setting up an old year.
Boy, you have to be a lady there.
- I know, and that's why you have to limit your dollar 75.
- Are you crazy, honey?
That's for my dinner.
- Homer, don't you want to save me from a terrible disgrace?
- Yeah, if it's gonna cost me a dollar 75.
(crowd laughs)
I thought you were eating a brandy.
Don't deny, but somehow I'm taking her here instead.
So Homer won't you please let me have that money.
No.
Time is getting humanity.
Not when my son is involved.
(audience laughing)
Okay, Homer, okay.
Well, you're in the spot sometime.
Just come to me for help.
Just come to me.
That's okay, Homer.
Pow.
Oh, okay.
Suppose I do this.
I'll be a part of my money.
Say 75 says.
That's all?
That's all I can afford.
Stand back while I get out of my pocket.
It's all in case.
Here.
$25.
You can make it an even dollar.
No.
Just eat.
But even their Swiss piece sandwiches started $45.
I'm sorry.
52, 3, 4.
Oh, my thing.
I'm going to stop grabbing.
Oh, my.
Oh.
Wow.
Look what you've done.
What do you mean your money went down this grape?
Every last day.
Well, we better go down there again.
In my cup of tea, though.
That young man, the young lady, want us to know it.
and I'm sorry for the all-out.
Well, I'll tell you.
What about my little?
Well, look, Mr. Could you tell me where this grave leads to?
The celeravirus.
Homer, if I go down here and get your money,
could I have a dollar?
Hello, Mrs. Blackman.
I'm afraid you can't go down there, young man.
Why not?
The cellar window's been bricked up for years.
Why?
Oh, boy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
(dramatic music)
- Now let's see.
Wait up, I think I'll have Brussels sprouts with my gaff.
- Yes, my Brussels sprouts so alive.
Now wait a minute, huh?
Let me run over that order again.
Before you do that, waiter,
could I have a little private talk with my friend?
- Again, honey?
- Well, guess the second, come on, Homer.
- I'll take what I lay little with me.
- Honey, I'm starving!
Why don't you have a roll while we're waiting?
Listen Homer, won't you please go home?
No, you lost my dollar seven or five and the least you can do is see.
But I told you I don't have a cent.
So why?
As long as you're not going to be able to pay.
What do you think is the making?
You don't pay for two or something?
[Loud Laughter]
You can technically go easy.
Well, okay.
Suppose I just have a Swiss T-cell.
With whiskey
I mean, but oh look Homer what whiskey just a lot of holes
It's a bread that's really nourishing so they give you all the bread you want for nothing
I want more than red to my dollar seven five sure you do Homer sure you do and you can have all that
Except up and mustard in the morning. I thought this was my lucky day
I'm glad it's home and I are ready to order
I think the waiter was getting down in tension.
I already ordered for you, huh?
That's dinner for three.
Oh, boy.
So, Cian comes now with a first call.
Gladys, before he comes to die, swing one thing until you...
Here you are.
Oh, wait, or stay, ever.
I think...
I think I'd better have another little talk with you.
Privately.
Yes, sir.
But first, here's the check.
And the check?
Before we...
There you are.
That is halfway a couple of rows, quick.
Wait a minute.
This number of five.
I'm going to reach the butter.
What number, sir?
This one with the dollar sign in front of it.
The red queen pass the salary.
Yes, sir.
That's a five.
Oh, boy.
Oh, but you did.
Oh, you put a box in your pocket, sir, again.
Oh, look.
Well, it is something I have to tell you.
There's something I have to tell you.
That Jack says.
Hey.
I can't.
What's going on?
Oh, I'm hiding.
There's a note on the back that explains it.
Turn it over, Henry.
Well, do you win?
But what does it say?
Maybe in the future we'll all be a little less positive and a little more careful.
Who's there?
Nobody.
I'm just like you are.
Well, do you win?
Potter, is that you behind that palm?
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Boy, you're going to need your back.
That's it.
It's going to cost me a pretty penny.
Homer costs you a pretty penny.
When we got it for free from my father,
I'm sure, but I'll have to pay and pay and pay.
Oh, well, what are you talking about?
He was angry so little that the man who was glad he was there.
Now he's so glad he'll ever put the bill for the movie.
He'll have a banana split for us again.
(buzzing)